<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-10-23T18:05:25-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Vancouver</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vancouver" /><published>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/">&lt;p&gt;I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few running themes that I clearly associate with Vancouver. One is nature: Vancouver is a city with a lot of natural beauty. You can go surfing in the morning and skiing at night, just with a car or by transit. There are also a lot of water-related words; the Georgia strait runs alongside Vancouver to become the Burrard Inlet. There are so many different bodies of water nearby that I didn’t think to include any in the word cloud. There are also a lot of outdoor activities, as well as alternate forms of transportation– Vancouver is not a car-centric town, and many city planners worldwide admire it for opting not to have a highway that cuts through downtown. Finally, I’ve included a few different cultures and foods in here; Vancouver is fairly diverse, and the food reflects that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-sketches--refinement&quot;&gt;Initial Sketches &amp;amp; Refinement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off by drawing a number of sketches drawing from the themes of my word cloud. I played with whitespace and shapes, but overall I gravitated towards the idea that Vancouver is a modern city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I favoured my fourth logo concept, but then I decided to look at existing logos for Vancouver to get an idea of the ecosystem my logo would exist in. As it turns out, my logos were often very similar to existing logo concepts– they seeped into my subconscious. Consequentially, I decided on logo concept #2– a literal take on a city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drew a clearer sketch of the idea on my tablet, and then took it into Illustrator for vectorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-concept&quot;&gt;Final Concept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product is slightly different from the refinement. I tilted the buildings to give the logo a bit more depth, and paired with the city’s name in Metro, a geometric typeface that was designed to compete with Futura, yet be a bit more humanist. It was created in 1929– around the same time Vancouver was amalgamated with Point Grey and South Vancouver– and was popular through the 1950s when Vancouver was developing its signature city planning policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logo-in-context&quot;&gt;Logo in Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><category term="logo" /><summary>I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.</summary></entry><entry><title>Appropriation Matrix</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appropriation Matrix" /><published>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/">&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/appropmatrix.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;appropmatrix.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.</summary></entry><entry><title>Serial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serial" /><published>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/">&lt;p&gt;It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lab was a fairly straightforward introduction to serial communication and particularly the notion of character encoding and representation; along with understanding binary vs decimal vs hex, it’s the most review of my CS degree we’ve tackled so far in PComp. It can still be a little tricky for me to remember what a bit is versus a byte versus a nibble; I’m usually a pretty high-level programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second lab connected P5 to the Arduino via serial connections; this was far more expressive than the serial monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waived ICM and haven’t touched P5 before these labs, so I decided to do a creative application to get myself accustomed to it. I had to learn the frustrations of everyone else. Personally, I think P5 is a poor choice for learning to programming; you spend a lot of time thinking about coordinates in a way that you won’t necessarily need to in many programming languages (granted, you do have to do so if you’re doing primarily graphics, but I don’t think most programmers do.) In any case, here’s my little house. It is sunny when you leave the photoresistor uncovered, turns cloudy when it’s partially covered, and becomes night when it’s fully covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/wxlETaoG10S9G&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do a great job of documenting here– my hand is mostly out of frame. I think you can still get the gist of it, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Buffy and Fan Engagement</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buffy and Fan Engagement" /><published>2016-10-16T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy/">&lt;p&gt;Until fairly recently, fan engagement seemed low on the corporate priority list. Case in point: the sale of props and clothing from &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt;, described in the article “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom: When &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt; Goes to eBay”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, was purportedly “for the fans” but was really financial in motivation. From that point of view, the sale was a success: 20th Century Fox made a great deal of money. From a fan engagement point of view, however, it left something to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a common saying that any press is good press, and in fandom, we say the same thing of engagement. Any engagement is good engagement, purportedly. But I would attach an addendum to this: any engagement is good engagement, but positive engagement is better than negative. The Buffy sale exposed longstanding divisions in the fan community, and caused some negative engagement. Because the actors of the show are sexualized by the show, there is no cultural norm of the fan community to refrain from commenting on this. However, the overt fetishization of the clothes for sale in this eBay auction caused some negative reactions from the fans, making one fan comment that they “shudder to think what some people may do with … outfits that are up for sale.” (36) It also exposed other divisions amongst fans, especially the divide amongst rich fans and poor: “I am bitter! It’s not fair! All of us Buffy fans want something but the rich bitches’ll get it all!” (38) Fans were upset by the unequal distribution of goods, and the top two bidders got 10% of the items. Another winner turned out to be a reseller, and fans were extremely upset by his destruction of the fan objects to sell in fractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the sale was poor engagement for going against the spirit of the text of the show. &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt; was built to be egalitarian in nature, with nerds and cheerleader types alike being key members of the Scooby Gang. The eBay sale set the balance of egalitarian fan communities off balance by creating an explicit hierarchy of fans: fans who’ve acquired more items versus fans who failed to buy anything. It transformed the show from a thing that everyone owns to something owned explicitly by a small group of people. Although the show fetishized the characters, it also had a strong feminist streak: the majority of the heroes were female, and it heavily promoted the idea of female empowerment. With the eBay sale, however, it emphasized the sexualization and deemphasized the feminist elements of the show. Actresses were reduced to fetish objects, and not the fully-fleshed female characters as written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Buffy fan community was resilient, and this sale did not have a large effect on the fan community. Fan engagement was already high, with an active message board wherein the show creator and writers would talk to fans directly, engaging in acknowledgement and flattery. The show would even create plots that responded to fan wishes, with episodes that felt very much like fan content (“The Wish”, “Doppelgangland”, and “Once More, with Feeling” are some examples.) Although the fan auction could’ve been better and more positive fan engagement, it’s still fan engagement and better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Stenger, Josh. “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to EBay.” Cinema Journal 45.4 (2006): 26-44. Web. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Until fairly recently, fan engagement seemed low on the corporate priority list. Case in point: the sale of props and clothing from Buffy the Vampire Slayer, described in the article “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom: When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to eBay”1, was purportedly “for the fans” but was really financial in motivation. From that point of view, the sale was a success: 20th Century Fox made a great deal of money. From a fan engagement point of view, however, it left something to be desired.


  
    
      Stenger, Josh. “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to EBay.” Cinema Journal 45.4 (2006): 26-44. Web. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title>Winter Show Poster</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Show Poster" /><published>2016-10-11T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster/">&lt;p&gt;I felt guilty about how I didn’t do my best making my business card double sided, so I also did a visual language assignment our section wasn’t actually assigned– making a postcard for the winter show. &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.itp.nyu.edu/academic-policies/community/show-postcard-design-submission-instructions&quot;&gt;The brief&lt;/a&gt; says that they were looking for “a more humanistic view of ITP” and I ran with that in mind. I was also hoping to submit a very different design from the other submissions: I suspected that most other students would use photography and focus on other students. I decided I’d illustrate my poster, and focus on applications of ITP– our creations and the people who interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/ideas.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/ideas.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched out a number of concepts based around this, ranging from the fantastic to the very practical. Should my poster focus on our dream inventions, our aspirations? Should they abstractly focus on the users? In the end, I decided to focus on a few concrete scenes from actual applications. I sought inspiration from comic books and posters like that for &lt;em&gt;Bill Cunningham, New York&lt;/em&gt;– so much humanity is on display in this poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/bill.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/bill.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brainstormed a list of classes that might make good scenes, and then whittled the list down to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing for Seniors in the Information Age&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hardwired for Stories Out Loud: Why Stories Matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design for the Real World: BeatRockers @ the Lavelle School&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing Assistive Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then drafted out a number of layouts for these scenes. I decided on the checkmarked layout– I figured the poster might be displayed a bit higher, and having the text at the midpoint would put it at eye level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/layouts.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/layouts.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, I moved to digital production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit funny– when I program and have git, I meticulously make commits and backups and always have the older versions on hand. I forget that entirely when I work with graphics: I didn’t save any of my earlier computer drafts. I’ll just describe them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off finding reference images, and creating a draft with stick figures– I just wanted to get the postures right. I then created an initial line drawing and colour testing– colour is so integral to the final image, so I wanted to have a good idea of what it would look like before I spent the time inking the outlines. I decided to stick with a small palette, to save time and since I thought it’d be visual interesting– taking inspiration from the works of Chris Ware and designers on Dribbble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/ware.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/ware.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/2337812-Afterhours-Poster&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/colour.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/colour.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a lot of colours, the image is a bit distracting, and the titling and words do not stand out as much. I also wanted to subtlely evoke NYU and use purple– a hard feat if I were to use realistic colours. I ended up with the colours you can see below in my final version, after inking, colouring, and typesetting. It’s distinctive and futuristic, but still soft. Just like ITP?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/poster.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/poster.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>I felt guilty about how I didn’t do my best making my business card double sided, so I also did a visual language assignment our section wasn’t actually assigned– making a postcard for the winter show. The brief says that they were looking for “a more humanistic view of ITP” and I ran with that in mind. I was also hoping to submit a very different design from the other submissions: I suspected that most other students would use photography and focus on other students. I decided I’d illustrate my poster, and focus on applications of ITP– our creations and the people who interact with them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Design for People</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design for People" /><published>2016-10-09T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people/">&lt;p&gt;It’s funny what experiences carry over when you’re working. When doing physical computing projects, my mind naturally tends towards habits I developed in computer science and development: start small, and test often. Even before Benedetta told us to do so, I had a tendency to test my circuits in pieces and with simpler components; it just seemed logical if I wanted to debug anything. Conversely, though, until this week’s readings, it hadn’t occured to me to bring user experience design into my physical computing projects. Is it because I’ve only been doing simple projects to test my learning, and because they’re not user facing? Or would they just not have occured to me anyways? Either way, &lt;em&gt;Sketching User Experiences: The Workbook&lt;/em&gt; was a great read, and I hope I’ll pick up a physical copy and adopt the habits within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly, I should pick up the habits of: paper prototyping and testing (for physical computing); keeping a sketchbook for design ideas; and the sketching techniques from &lt;em&gt;Drawing from the Right Side of the Brain&lt;/em&gt; (another fine book.) Anh Nguyen’s project, Happy Feedback Machine, has great examples of sketching and a really adorable use case storyboard (though this sort of seems like it’s assuming too much per Tom Igoe’s blog post.) It’s honestly wondrous that I hadn’t thought to apply these techniques to physical computing. Everything covered in &lt;em&gt;Sketching User Experiences&lt;/em&gt; is stuff I’ve encountered before, but I never thought of it as applicable. Hopefully, I’ll be able to bring both CS + Design experience to future Physical Computing Projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It’s funny what experiences carry over when you’re working. When doing physical computing projects, my mind naturally tends towards habits I developed in computer science and development: start small, and test often. Even before Benedetta told us to do so, I had a tendency to test my circuits in pieces and with simpler components; it just seemed logical if I wanted to debug anything. Conversely, though, until this week’s readings, it hadn’t occured to me to bring user experience design into my physical computing projects. Is it because I’ve only been doing simple projects to test my learning, and because they’re not user facing? Or would they just not have occured to me anyways? Either way, Sketching User Experiences: The Workbook was a great read, and I hope I’ll pick up a physical copy and adopt the habits within.</summary></entry><entry><title>Counterculture and Commercial Ventures</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Counterculture and Commercial Ventures" /><published>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/">&lt;p&gt;The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films &lt;em&gt;Escape from Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for the lack of outrage is because both groups remain deeply embedded in their respective fan communities. When you are called a sellout, it’s often for a perceived betrayal of the community: by foregrounding your commercial interests, you are placing your own needs above those of the community. The skaters of “Buying In” largely don’t have this problem because their commercial sales were initially to each other– by keeping within the community, you don’t seem like a sellout. The last example of Tony Hawk is the most likely to be called a sellout, with his tacit approval of people who are not skaters participating in skate culture. However, he can deflect accusations of selling out by claiming that his ventures are evangelization– he is encouraging the expansion of his community– and profit-sharing– by including other skaters in his video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Disneyland social clubs are communities themselves and part of the larger Disney community. They embrace larger Disney values, and accept questions and criticism from regular parkgoers (“feel free to ask any questions” and “always say hi” advises one leader cited in the article.) By following the existing codes of behaviour of the Disney community, they’ve earned themselves tolerance. Additionally, by banding together, they’re also able to protect each other– the films I mentioned in the opening are by solo auteurs, and by being alone they are easier for a corporation to target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;values-and-fan-context&quot;&gt;Values and Fan Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why these groups do not provoke fan outrage is that the fan objects– skateboard culture and Disney– do not have values that disallow or discourage this intersection. Although skateboarding is purportedly rebellious, nothing in its fan context disapproves of commercial interests. The first team even formed as part of a local skate shop, Zephyr, and young fans hope to gain sponsorship deals. Arguably, selling things is a part of the fan context. So long as you’re not printing anti-skate park propaganda, you’re still behaving in line with skateboarding culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social clubs of Disneyland do not look like they represent Disney values, but they prove themselves with their actions. They raise money for charity, and try their best to help people. Disney values are often about children and family, and many social clubs bring their children along, or act as family for each other. Disney wants to look inclusive, so they include the social clubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commodification&quot;&gt;Commodification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one last reason that this intersection is tolerated is commercial: everybody wants to make a living. Skateboarders need to make money somehow, so why would they begrudge the ones who manage to turn their counterculture into a career? If anything, that’s to be admired: doing something they love while making money. Disney profits from the social clubs via their annual memberships, as well as their buying food and merchandise. There’s no reason to turn this money down by shutting these clubs down. Overall, counterculture and commerce can intersect peacefully– so long as it stays in line with core values.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films Escape from Tomorrow, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?</summary></entry><entry><title>Let’s Get Down to Business</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Get Down to Business" /><published>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/">&lt;p&gt;I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important factors in the design of my business cards was the redesign of my portfolio and blog. When I started ITP, I knew I would have to redesign both: I failed to update them in years, and class after class emphasized to me that the blog was a central part of ITP. I also wanted to move my blog to the ceiling.cat domain, a novelty domain that I’d owned for years but had done nothing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were an internet nerd in the mid 2000s, you’d probably remember this meme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I wanted was to have matching but separate identities for both websites. The portfolio was serious, and meant to showcase my best work; the blog was for works in progress and silly thoughts from ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted the blog to have a logo with a cat. It didn’t make much sense to do otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize: I wanted to have a logo template that would work for a serious portfolio as well as a cat. That’s a bit of a tough briefing, but it’s aided by how the original ceiling cat appears: he pops out of a square hole in the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequentially, I can start with a square template for both logos– it’s clean and professional for my portfolio, and appropriate for ceiling cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/template.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/template.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to subtly evoke stamps and Chinese seals– it’d reflect my heritage and help give the logos a unified idea. I rounded the corners and decided that the logos would be single colour, as if they could be stamped on. Then, I could convert them to black and white, any colours, or even add an image to the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is getting a bit long-winded, so I’ll spare you more details about the logos. Suffice to say, I drew a bunch of cats, and tested a bunch of typefaces, and came out with the following two logos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/logos.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/logos.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-original-design&quot;&gt;The Original Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this starting point, I decided to make my business cards on Sunday. Given the ‘chinese seal’ design element, I decided to take scroll paintings as inspiration, and drew a digital watercolour painting of a bird on a cherry blossom tree. (My street in Vancouver was lined with cherry blossoms, as many are.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/flowers.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/flowers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The painting’s focal is from right to left, as most Chinese scrolls are, and I consequentially placed my seal and my information on the left of the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/original.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/original.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished at this point, and then the next day I went to class. I received the assignment, and changed things for the worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-redesign&quot;&gt;The Redesign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most consequential change was that the assignment stipulated that the card had to be double sided. I originally tried making the painting go across the two sides, but the image was too low-resolution to print at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/spread.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/spread.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then decided to stick with the image on one side, and just moved the information to the back. I also flipped the painting, because we discussed in class how the lower left corner was the weakest focal point of an image (which, in retrospect now, is less consequential in a landscape business card with its low height.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/double.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/double.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent this image to the printers, which I terribly regret. In retrospect, landscape business cards are too short for that focus information to matter, and images always look better before they’re flipped (unless they are perfectly symmetrical.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it’s overall a stronger design on only one side. I also regret the serif font I chose on the back– I thought it would provide a nice contrast, but it just looks out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I wish I kept my original card. But you can keep this analysis in the meanwhile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visuallang" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.</summary></entry><entry><title>Westworld</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Westworld" /><published>2016-10-04T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld/">&lt;p&gt;New fandoms are different spaces from older fandoms. Customs have yet to be codified; big name fans have yet to become prominent. In-jokes and norms take time to become established. This week in fandom, Patrick and I took a look at the fandom for Westworld to analyze the techniques to form a group and create group cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westworld is an interesting example, in that it’s both a brand new fandom– the first episode aired only on Sunday (October 2)– and a natural offshoot of older fandoms. It’s a new HBO show that is produced by J.J. Abrams and Jonathan Nolan, who both have sizeable fandoms of their own. J.J. Abrams is known for directing the new Star Wars, the Star Trek reboots, and other films, as well as producing cult TV Shows like Lost and Fringe. Jonathan Nolan– though not as well known as his older brother, director Christopher Nolan– is well known for his collaborations with Christopher on screenplays like Interstellar, and being the showrunner for Person of Interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also based on a movie written and directed by the author of Jurassic Park, Michael Crichton. Plot-wise, it’s very similar to Jurassic Park: Westworld also revolves around a theme park wherein its captive attractions go rogue. This time, though, it’s a science fiction story about a Western theme park filled with robots that become sentient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this extensive pedigree, Westworld had a lot of hype and a lot of high expectations– at a budget of $100 million for its first season, HBO needed it to be a success. So far, it seems to have connected with its audience: the first episode had 3.3 million viewers, the best premiere for HBO in the last three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fans&quot;&gt;The Fans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who tuned into Westworld? Based on just its pedigree, we can make a few assumptions about its fans. It’s an HBO show, so they’ll be accustomed to seeing nudity and on-screen violence (including sexual violence). Because Abrams and Nolan are involved, the fans will be very speculative and will come up with tons of explanations. If you remember Lost, that show caused fans to come up with tons of theories on the nature of the show, the significance of the numbers, and more. For Nolan, even mentioning the spinning top of Inception might make your eyes roll. Additionally, fans of both pride themselves on attention to detail and will point out little things (often in aid of elaborate theories.) It’s easy to extend these qualities to fans of Westworld: speculation and digging for secrets will be a huge part of this fan community, and apparently already is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the fans should have the same qualities as most fans of science fiction and westerns. However, it’s tough to say for sure if this is representative of the whole audience: although the most vocal audience members of Game of Thrones are pre-existing fans of fantasy, the whole viewing audience is surprisingly diverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cohesion-activities&quot;&gt;Cohesion Activities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although some cohesion activities were harder to find– no debates have been ritualized yet, and people were not quite jostling for hierarchy yet (beyond just getting upvotes and reblogs)– others were extremely easy. Exchanging knowledge or gifts was the bulk of fan activity surrounding Westworld, with the predicted theories emerging and details being pointed out to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/wanted.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/wanted.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/milk.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/milk.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/flies.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/flies.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a theory was particularly good, or a rare piece of fan creation appeared, acknowledgement and flattery appeared in spades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/spoileroriginal.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/spoileroriginal.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/spoiler.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/spoiler.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/foreshadowing.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/foreshadowing.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/tldr.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/tldr.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/goodcatch.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/goodcatch.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although for the most part, social norms have not been established, there are some holdover norms from other fandoms that have applied to Westworld. With time, we’ll see if these cultural norms apply to Westworld fans or were just a one-time event. For now though, fans enforce the same cultural norms as other HBO shows– namely Game of Thrones– and other science fiction properties: to criticize those who might analyze the show with a feminist lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/pwned.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/pwned.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/nitpick.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/nitpick.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/brett.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/brett.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, fans do punish infractions, though infractions largely haven’t been established either. One thing is certain though: you don’t post in the Westworld subreddit if you dont like the show. The two following posts have a reasonable tone and don’t make any untrue points, but they were still downvoted and hidden by Westworld fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/featurette.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/featurette.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/cupoftea.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/cupoftea.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this only counts a day or two of activity, we can already see how the Westworld fan group is forming and what its fans might look like in the future. Lots of speculation is key to its cohesion, and encouraging this fan behaviour and discouraging others will define Westworld fans as more episodes air.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>New fandoms are different spaces from older fandoms. Customs have yet to be codified; big name fans have yet to become prominent. In-jokes and norms take time to become established. This week in fandom, Patrick and I took a look at the fandom for Westworld to analyze the techniques to form a group and create group cohesion.</summary></entry><entry><title>Noters and Motors</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Noters and Motors" /><published>2016-10-01T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos/">&lt;p&gt;Since I had already worked with the piezo speaker last week, the labs this week for physical computing were a breeze. What was a little tougher was thinking of another creative application. Should I work with the piezo again? Should I just fix up my previous project? Instead, I decided to play a little more with the servo motor. It’s not as interesting as the Mario music, but a little more interesting than rote labs, which I’ll cover first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rote labs: riveting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up: wiring two photoresistors into an Arduino, and then translating the input into tones for the piezo. This was very annoying to listen to, so I’ll spare you the video for it and instead just play you a pleasant melody:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oUr1l6a2cD8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I don’t have any force sensing resistors, I just made a keyboard with the same photoresistors. Laziness rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QOUL3PrjpCI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I hooked up a servo to a potentiometer. GIF created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/OShZOGqKpU6GI&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught a cold over the weekend, so my mind’s been a little temperature focused. I’ve been meaning to remove my air conditioner from the window, but I should probably wait until I’m feeling less feeble. Unfortunately, that also means that I have to endure the cold air that the air conditioner is letting through. Exactly how cold is my room? How can I know in a temperature system that isn’t backwards? All the thermometers around me are Fahrenheit. (Sorry, Fahrenheit, but it’s true. You only make sense when measuring people.) I decided to make a little temperature gauge with my Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the high and low temperature of the gauge, I looked at the historical highs and lows of New York– it reached 38.6°C in 1966 and was -20°C in 1994. Consequentially, I decided on setting the range at -20 to 40°C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/temperaturecode.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;temperaturecode.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the gauge, I used the Arduino to set the servo to 0, drew a notch, set the servo to 179, drew a notch, and then drew notches in between. It’s super jaggy, so I should probably consider using capacitors to smooth it out. It’s probably not the most accurate temperature gauge either, but it’s enough to confirm for me: my room is too cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/temperaturegauge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;temperaturegauge.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’m less sick, I’ll get that A/C out of the window. For now, jumper wires are as much as I’ll lift.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>Since I had already worked with the piezo speaker last week, the labs this week for physical computing were a breeze. What was a little tougher was thinking of another creative application. Should I work with the piezo again? Should I just fix up my previous project? Instead, I decided to play a little more with the servo motor. It’s not as interesting as the Mario music, but a little more interesting than rote labs, which I’ll cover first.</summary></entry></feed>
