<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-25T08:05:57-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>A Three Minute Pop Quiz</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/09/25/threeminutes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Three Minute Pop Quiz" /><published>2017-09-25T04:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-25T04:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/09/25/threeminutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/09/25/threeminutes/">&lt;p&gt;“If you had 3 minutes to communicate your truth to 100,000 people what would you say, show, and or play?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be cheating a little with my response– the 100,000 people would seem to necessitate a broadcast, and I’m giving everyone a pop quiz. But it’s part of something I’ve been mulling over– how can you change people’s minds on contentious topics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to do so is by testing people’s knowledge. Consequently, I’m using our classroom and the context of the classroom for this assignment, but in practice to 100,000 people it’d be more likely to be a website or targeted facebook ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vQxbJe1P_k3W3vQrOCpQjOSh5Zpu1FtX5HXdyl33z0mOL8e9RZHTjnRno5TUmSLUnuAQ3xbiQET0dpt/pub&quot;&gt;Click here for the quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="canvas for public discourse" /><summary>“If you had 3 minutes to communicate your truth to 100,000 people what would you say, show, and or play?”</summary></entry><entry><title>Final Presentation</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/05/07/presentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final Presentation" /><published>2017-05-07T00:02:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-07T00:02:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/05/07/presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/05/07/presentation/">&lt;p&gt;After many weeks of arguments and meetings, this is our final presentation. Not really anything to do with Finance or Transparency, but it’s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1ubWtVgvgcNjc5Fmpqs-LBRS7cg5exFqQYVV2dzQMKB8/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;569&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here was our draft:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HUlA88g3EIFtetf2T8GTWug-uLD0sXCRPiogxvUEEQE/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;569&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>After many weeks of arguments and meetings, this is our final presentation. Not really anything to do with Finance or Transparency, but it’s good enough.</summary></entry><entry><title>Vending Machine, Finally</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/25/final/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vending Machine, Finally" /><published>2017-04-25T02:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-25T02:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/25/final</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/25/final/">&lt;p&gt;I returned to the creation of my vending machine for my Subtraction, and finished it a week early– I don’t want to compete with anybody for any techno router slots. The machine still needs a lot of work, most notably all the electronics, but as far as the class material, I am done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second version is slightly bigger, meant to accommodate four items instead of just two. It also includes the shelving properly, and a lot more cutouts: more buttons, a hole for wires to come out of, an LCD screen, and finally, two holes to string a bike chain through so we can lock the thing from thieves. I still need to attach the hinges on the side, but it’s otherwise complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process was a lot easier this time, as I just modified my existing Vectorworks templates to be slightly bigger and include all the cutouts. I also included the shelves, which have little dividers for the items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acquired a ton of MDF panels, and intended to cut an initial version to confirm my joints work again. It was also good to start with a material I didn’t care about– I haven’t used the CNC router in a few weeks, and I was a bit out of practice. I quickly got the hang of it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joints were fine, so then I moved on to using the Baltic Birch ply I acquired months ago. It’s so much nicer than the pine I used before. It was quite a lengthy job, requiring so many hours I lost count. It’s hard to measure so many parts that fit together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a big mistake. I forgot that my cad template for the front would be reversed, so I had to redo it. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gluing the thing together also took a great deal of time. Luckily, I learned about the existence of the shop’s single right angle clamp (? I’m not sure what they are called.) I wish we had more than one. I had to use much sketchier setups to clamp the rest of the joints together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making my template, I decided that the item dividers would have to be a 1/4 inch; the 1/2 inch ply I was working with would be too thick when viewed from the outside. I got some 1/4 inch MDF from David, and cut it down with the band saw. I wish they’d match, but this was free. It’s also an inconsequential concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then started fitting the machine with hardware. It’s pretty cute now, if I do say so myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_final/vm7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_final/vm7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s particularly cute with items inside. Look at this! I made it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="routing" /><category term="battery store" /><category term="joinery" /><category term="cnc" /><summary>I returned to the creation of my vending machine for my Subtraction, and finished it a week early– I don’t want to compete with anybody for any techno router slots. The machine still needs a lot of work, most notably all the electronics, but as far as the class material, I am done!</summary></entry><entry><title>Fortune Tinder</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/24/fortune-tinder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fortune Tinder" /><published>2017-04-24T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/24/fortune-tinder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/24/fortune-tinder/">&lt;p&gt;One idea that gets bandied about at ITP is the idea of having a cohesive body of work that you produce at ITP. Interested in LGBT rights? Convinced VR is the future? Focus your works on those concepts. I entered ITP with nothing of this sort in mind; I just wanted to learn new things and be surrounded by people excited by the future of technology (I felt like the tech industry was more cynical and more interested in the monetization of technology.) However, one does have a tendency to gravitate towards certain subjects. And one of my pet subjects is sexism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like a bit of a tangent from the actual subject of this blog post, which is my final for Electronic Rituals: a modified app that tells you your future breakup with the person that you’re​ swiping on in Tinder. It’s pulling on actual Tinder users, but the fortunes are prewritten: your future is determined by a hash of the subject’s name and birthday, and this pulls an entry from an array of fortunes. Sexism doesn’t seem related: you can swipe on both genders that Tinder lets you choose from (there are no other options or ability to opt out) and the fortunes change pronouns appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sexism I refer to is more conceptual than anything else. I did not write the app that logs you into Tinder and lets you swipe on people; that’s pre-existing code from other engineers who reverse engineered Tinder’s API. For the large part, this was done by male engineers who wanted to make dating easier for them. They wanted to automate swiping for them, and some of them even went as far as using machine learning to determine what types of faces they liked to only swipe on “pretty” women. This is the sexism I refer to and comment on. Tinder and this tool were created by men to algorithmically date women. I created a tool to algorithmically find reasons not to date men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder3.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_ft/Fortune_Tinder3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides this, the fortunes are also a comment on my personal dating habits– that is, I don’t really date. I am always finding excuses not to put myself out there; I don’t have time, or maybe I just don’t like the way they dress. This tool automatically does this for me, so it’s a bit of a parody of myself. I’m making fun of myself as well as male engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code for this tool here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/metermaid/fortune-tinder&quot;&gt;https://github.com/metermaid/fortune-tinder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to run the electron app, and sign into Tinder with a Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Apologies for the tardiness of this blog post!)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="tinder" /><category term="fortune telling" /><category term="feminism" /><summary>One idea that gets bandied about at ITP is the idea of having a cohesive body of work that you produce at ITP. Interested in LGBT rights? Convinced VR is the future? Focus your works on those concepts. I entered ITP with nothing of this sort in mind; I just wanted to learn new things and be surrounded by people excited by the future of technology (I felt like the tech industry was more cynical and more interested in the monetization of technology.) However, one does have a tendency to gravitate towards certain subjects. And one of my pet subjects is sexism.</summary></entry><entry><title>Transparency</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/17/transparency/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transparency" /><published>2017-04-17T00:02:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-17T00:02:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/17/transparency</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/17/transparency/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I suspect that Doing Good is Good Business is an elaborate simulation to discourage ITP students from working at NGOs. Endless meetings? Check. Intractable problems? Check. Stakeholders who won’t accept a solution until they add two words to it? Well, that one is very specific, but it happened to me. We had three group meetings this week, perhaps to compensate for the last week, but they were largely arguments over trivial things. Sometimes I would lose focus and my group members’ words would become gibberish to me. “Local community”, they’d say. “Smart contracts.” “NGOs.” “Transparency.” On some level I understood what they meant, but on another, I wondered, “do they know what they mean? Do I understand what they mean and not what they’re saying?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is all a digression. We decided this was the week we would nail down a final topic. Jaycee, Shivanku, and I all wrote proposals, and presented them to Ariana and discussed what topic we should choose. In the end, we may have pleased everybody, at the expense of a little of my understanding. Perhaps my interpretation of what they said differs from what they meant. Here is my understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;problem-statement&quot;&gt;Problem statement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we encourage transparency in non-governmental organizations based in New York?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I think they said “in their local community”, but transparency is transparent– it is for all of the stakeholders. Jaycee also added local “government”, but I have no idea why she’s insistent on it. We need to scope on some level.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;systems-map&quot;&gt;Systems Map&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_map.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_map.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This systems map was made for international organizations, but excepting the foreign government portion would make it applicable to local organizations. The line is a potential point of intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;research-plan&quot;&gt;Research Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would generally like to stick to 1-1 interviews, because the scope of the projects we would like to intervene with is larger than an ethnographic study would be appropriate for (I.e. we would require more than one day’s worth of study.) A group interview would also be inappropriate because the users we would like to look at are so different, and we would like their viewpoints properly represented. Surveys may be appropriate for contacting donors, but we would like more details than those generally provide. We may still do one, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;us-foreign-aid-workers-and-un-accountants&quot;&gt;US Foreign Aid workers and UN accountants&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do countries currently report back after the aid they receive?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;charityaid-organization-report-writers&quot;&gt;Charity/aid organization report writers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how is information generally collected?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you produce the facts and figures for your reports?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-house information or outside sources?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reporting-agencies&quot;&gt;Reporting agencies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how is information generally collected?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you produce the facts and figures for your reports?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-house information or outside sources?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you collect information on how effective aid is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;beneficiaries--supply-chain&quot;&gt;Beneficiaries / Supply Chain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do you receive money or goods?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you spend money or goods?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>Sometimes I suspect that Doing Good is Good Business is an elaborate simulation to discourage ITP students from working at NGOs. Endless meetings? Check. Intractable problems? Check. Stakeholders who won’t accept a solution until they add two words to it? Well, that one is very specific, but it happened to me. We had three group meetings this week, perhaps to compensate for the last week, but they were largely arguments over trivial things. Sometimes I would lose focus and my group members’ words would become gibberish to me. “Local community”, they’d say. “Smart contracts.” “NGOs.” “Transparency.” On some level I understood what they meant, but on another, I wondered, “do they know what they mean? Do I understand what they mean and not what they’re saying?”</summary></entry><entry><title>4-Axis Columns</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/15/4axis2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4-Axis Columns" /><published>2017-04-15T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-15T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/15/4axis2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/15/4axis2/">&lt;p&gt;One skill that I’ve yet to acquire at ITP is 3D modelling. I’ve acquired much of the skills that ITP teaches– programming, physical computing, graphics, and video editing– but 3D continues to be beyond me. Consequently, my attempt at this week’s Subtraction assignment will probably be less impressive than those of my classmates’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off intending to make a panda bear. A simple enough project, and one that worked well enough for me in 2D space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/vw1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/vw1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/vw2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/vw2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I rendered the STL in MakerBot, it was quite clear that I didn’t know what I was doing. I could take down the arms after milling, but that seems to me a waste of using a mill if I had to whittle afterwards. My impression is that Vectorworks is really great if you want precision and generally flat surfaces, but it’s beyond my ability to make rounded shapes. I decided instead to mill a bunch of columns. I liked the idea that a miniature person might find a log and carve a building out of it. Maybe using columns and pillars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/vw3.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/vw3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I wanted to make something without tabs and to retain the material around the milled area. It seemed like a good fit, and easily rendered using Vectorworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/mill1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/mill1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I snuck onto the machine on Saturday, and then setup my job. As mentioned, I didn’t need tabs, but I had to adjust the job to give it margins on the sides. I also used Softwood instead of Hardwood this time– it produced a lot of tearout, but there was a huge time difference between the two settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/mill2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/mill2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then cut and sanded it down, and applied a quick finish. Cute little columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/mill3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/mill3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_mill2/mill4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_mill2/mill4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><summary>One skill that I’ve yet to acquire at ITP is 3D modelling. I’ve acquired much of the skills that ITP teaches– programming, physical computing, graphics, and video editing– but 3D continues to be beyond me. Consequently, my attempt at this week’s Subtraction assignment will probably be less impressive than those of my classmates’.</summary></entry><entry><title>Another Fail Story</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/anotherfailstory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another Fail Story" /><published>2017-04-11T00:02:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-11T00:02:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/anotherfailstory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/anotherfailstory/">&lt;p&gt;I am uncomfortable with the idea of using smart contracts with the underprivileged in the US; one of the virtues of them is that they are not strongly regulated by the government, but that is also problematic when they are not guaranteed to be secure. Ethereum can be forked when the wealthy investors of the DAO are scammed, but would it be forked to protect smaller smart contracts? That seems unlikely. A smart contract protects their rights to be paid when it works, but if it is attacked by a hacker nobody is protected unless they are rich. Consequentially, I wanted to work with smart contracts with people who had disposable incomes– for whom an attack would not mean loss of livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem: a number of fundraising events ask for a donation contingent on reaching some kind of goal. This includes things like marathons and donation matching. These events ask for a commitment, but they may not reach their goals. This can result in wasted resources like investment in running vests for runners who never run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: NYC (or whole of NA)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interview Plan: (one on one interviews)
- Marathon runners (x2)
- Charity run organizers (e.g. the London marathon had many defaultees) (x3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions:
- Why do you like to run marathons?
- Do you regularly donate to charity otherwise?
- What resources do you expect to help you fundraise for your place in a marathon?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>I am uncomfortable with the idea of using smart contracts with the underprivileged in the US; one of the virtues of them is that they are not strongly regulated by the government, but that is also problematic when they are not guaranteed to be secure. Ethereum can be forked when the wealthy investors of the DAO are scammed, but would it be forked to protect smaller smart contracts? That seems unlikely. A smart contract protects their rights to be paid when it works, but if it is attacked by a hacker nobody is protected unless they are rich. Consequentially, I wanted to work with smart contracts with people who had disposable incomes– for whom an attack would not mean loss of livelihood.</summary></entry><entry><title>Female Script Intros</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/generator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Female Script Intros" /><published>2017-04-11T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-11T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/generator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/11/generator/">&lt;p&gt;For my meditation this week, I decided to take a look at sexism in movie scripts. I came to this topic after a long deliberation. When I read that we were to tap into unconscious, subconscious, and the collective, my thoughts turned immediately to the latent biases everyone has. But there are many datasets I could’ve used, and many biases that could be examined– I eventually settled on movies because it’s a topic I know very well, and whose history of sexism has been well documented. It’s also a topic that’s been studied before: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2017/03/film-dialogue/index.html&quot;&gt;this study&lt;/a&gt; looked at how much dialogue different genders have on screen, and Russ Putman maintains a fantastic twitter with female script intros &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/femscriptintros?lang=en&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to see if I could generate the sexist introductions of the kind that Mr. Putman has documented thoroughly, using a dataset culled from famous movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by downloading a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlds.soe.ucsc.edu/fc2&quot;&gt;dataset I found from UC Santa Cruz&lt;/a&gt;, which is culled from the Internet Movie Script Database (imsdb.com). I then wrote a ruby script to find every sentence that surrounded certian keywords. Here, I look for sentences that contain the word ‘sexy’:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;File.open('corpus.txt', 'w') do |writer| 
  Dir.glob('imsdb_scenes_dialogs_nov_2015/scenes/**/*').each do |file|
    next unless File.file?(file)
    content = File.read(file)
    content.scan(/.*sexy .*/) do |match|
      writer.write match
      writer.write &quot;\n&quot;
    end
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could’ve saved all of my keywords in one file, but I wanted to inspect each keyword individually to see if I should use it. Some words were more fruitful than others. For instance, I started looking at ‘pretty’, ‘beautiful’, and other variations on that word:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She looks up. She is beautiful and terrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Points to a gorgeous dead woman with the word GRIFTER on her stomach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But besides examples like those, I also turned up a lot of uses to describe environments and scenery. That wouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then looked at hair colours, noticing a pattern in which women were consistently described by their hair. (For anybody who’s taken a screenwriting class, this is apparently a terrible practice, but it’s been very successful with these produced and famous scripts.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;TAMARA, 28, blonde, wears the shortest mini one can imagine,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We barely notice the redhead kneeling between his legs, face buried in his crotch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that too many instances of ‘blonde’, despite being gendered, were for men; same goes for redheads. The corpus can include false positives, but not nearly as many as there were for these words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then switched to looking at ‘sexy’ and ‘naked’ and ‘nude’. These were generally great– even when they described men, they were typically sexualized. These were part of the corpus that I eventually settled on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She’s naked but for the tiny silver crucifix she wears around her neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MODEL, lying nude in a pool of blue paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Go boards, pachinko machines, sexy little MANGA WAIFS in schoolgirl outfits doling out drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, here are a few of my favourite quotes that my little website has generated. It’s only a Markov chain– it would’ve likely worked out better if I created a ruleset. I like the unpredictability of it, though, and creating a ruleset for sexism would’ve been emotionally exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_generator/2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_generator/2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_generator/3.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_generator/3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_generator/4.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_generator/4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com/metermaid/femalescriptintrogenerator/&quot;&gt;Click here for the github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://metermaid.github.io/femalescriptintrogenerator/&quot;&gt;Click here for the finished product !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="hollywood" /><category term="feminism" /><summary>For my meditation this week, I decided to take a look at sexism in movie scripts. I came to this topic after a long deliberation. When I read that we were to tap into unconscious, subconscious, and the collective, my thoughts turned immediately to the latent biases everyone has. But there are many datasets I could’ve used, and many biases that could be examined– I eventually settled on movies because it’s a topic I know very well, and whose history of sexism has been well documented. It’s also a topic that’s been studied before: this study looked at how much dialogue different genders have on screen, and Russ Putman maintains a fantastic twitter with female script intros here. I wanted to see if I could generate the sexist introductions of the kind that Mr. Putman has documented thoroughly, using a dataset culled from famous movies.</summary></entry><entry><title>4-Axis Mill</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/09/4axis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4-Axis Mill" /><published>2017-04-09T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-09T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/09/4axis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/09/4axis/">&lt;p&gt;The lathe was out of service last week, so I had a week off from blogging about Subtraction. The metal lathe was admittedly a bit intimidating, but I had wanted to try it. Oh well! This week, we tackled the 4-Axis mill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of this week’s exercise was working with Vectorworks– my background in no way involves 3D modelling so I had no idea how to work with this software. Photoshop and Illustrator? Fine. But add another dimension and I’m lost. I had to try hard not to compare myself to other people in the class– they have backgrounds in industrial design, I tell myself, so they knew how to model already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to make myself a simple, geometric necklace. It took a while to figure out Vectorworks’ interpretation of “extruding”, but I eventually settled on the folowing shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/vectorworks.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/vectorworks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I couldn’t quite remember all the steps for setting up the mill, and had to ask Eric for help. He was a great help, but admittedly all I didn’t remember was that I needed an allen key to move the tail stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/setup.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/setup.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cut out job took a bit under an hour. Eric had advised me to use a lot of tabs (because he hadn’t, and his project snapped) so it’s a bit bulky and needs to be sanded down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/cutout.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/cutout.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my immense regret, though, I cut the thing out without first drilling the hole– so I had to clamp it to drill the hole. After I did so, though, the bottom part snapped off– which isn’t too regrettable, since it still looks more or less like I did so intentionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/sanding.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/sanding.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/hole.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/hole.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished sanding it down, I took some yarn from the soft lab and threaded it through. It’s alright for a first try at the mill!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_4axis/necklace.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_4axis/necklace.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><summary>The lathe was out of service last week, so I had a week off from blogging about Subtraction. The metal lathe was admittedly a bit intimidating, but I had wanted to try it. Oh well! This week, we tackled the 4-Axis mill.</summary></entry><entry><title>Money Transfers</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Money Transfers" /><published>2017-04-04T00:02:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:02:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;problem-statement&quot;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of being unbanked affects 2 billion people in the world, the impact of which is that they have no access to credit, insurance, savings, and payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compelling-stories&quot;&gt;Compelling Stories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the following links about un/underbanked American families– I hope that my teammates find sources on non-American sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdic.gov/householdsurvey/&quot;&gt;7% of American families are unbanked and 20% are underbanked, according to the FDIC. 57.4% of unbanked respondants say that one reason for being unbanked is that they do not have enough money to keep in an account. Other reasons given include privacy, not trusting the banks, and account fees being too high or unpredictable.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/b/?node=14583169011&amp;amp;sa-no-redirect=1&quot;&gt;Amazon, recognizing that being unable to access credit/debit cards to use their service is a problem, is starting a new service to convert Cash to Amazon currency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/01/business/as-pay-cards-replace-paychecks-bank-fees-hurt-workers.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;Many American companies are now using payroll cards to pay their employees, and if they do not have a bank account, they must pay fees to withdraw their money.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fletcher.tufts.edu/InclusionInc/Programming/Research/Cost-of-Cash&quot;&gt;It costs American households $40B a year total for using cash, mostly because of the time to go get cash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-diagrams&quot;&gt;System Diagrams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/stakeholders.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/stakeholders.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/whiteboard.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/whiteboard.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>Problem Statement</summary></entry></feed>
