<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-09T23:32:46-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Final</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final" /><published>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/">&lt;p&gt;It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is a loving recreation of a magical object in the world of the Harry Potter series. In the books, the hat reads your mind to determine which of four school houses you have the most affinity for. In real life, we are unable to read minds, so the Sorting Hat asks you a series of questions and determines your house based on your responses. Physically, it is an anthropomorphic hat that beckons you to put it on. Once on your head, it will guide you through a series of yes or no questions to which you will respond with nods or words. The hat will then decide your house, which it will announce loudly, and you can enjoy a sense of belonging and delight at this talking hat’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/finaltimeline1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;finaltimeline1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.</summary></entry><entry><title>Real or Not Real?</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real or Not Real?" /><published>2016-11-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real/">&lt;p&gt;At first, I wasn’t sure what the connection between the two readings we were assigned for Fandom this week was. “Buying In: The Pretty Good Problem” and “From Smart Fan to Backyard Wrestler: Performance, Context, and Aesthetic Violence (WWF)” seemed like very different subjects. Looking at the subject of next week’s class made it come together– we’ll be looking at Authenticity of Fandom. With Professional Wrestling, the fandom revolves around its inauthenticity, and authenticity differentiates companies with the Pretty Good Problem. In this way, the two readings complement each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be said that the wrestling fandom revolves around the authenticity of its inauthenticity. It’s comparable to reality TV in that it is widely perceived as fake and trashy with stupid fans, but that’s a facile line of thinking. All fans of reality TV and professional wrestling knows that it is fake and manipulated, with crafted storylines and personas. Playing along is part of the fun, and the most devoted fans regard themselves as smart and are cognizant of the ways the performances are manipulated. Smart fans may even seek out leaked results and still enjoy the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary focus of the article is about backyard and indie wrestling leagues, which authentically replicate the inauthenticity of professional wrestling. Like professional wrestling, they have storylines and characters, and tapes are recorded and sold. As leagues get bigger they may even pay for rings and promotion, and copy the inauthentic techniques of professionals, such as ‘blading’, intentionally cutting yourself to appear as if you’ve lost a lot of blood. These leagues, as well as professionals, focus on making a good show with as little pain as possible; they shy away from the extreme moves that might actually put them in danger. The priority is to put on a good show, but well within established standards of behaviour. It’s authentically inauthentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to this, the “Pretty Good Problem” reading concerns the inauthentically authentic. A good chunk of the reading is about Ecko, a brand embraced by the hip-hop world, but founded by a suburban white man whose closest ties to the street were viewing old graffitied subway cars in Trenton. Ecko grew into its hip-hop stature because its founder was able to recognize the potential market– he sold ads in black magazines and hired black tastemakers to promote the brand. It wasn’t authentic to begin with, but as people on the street started to buy it, it became authentic in some sense. Similarly, Ralph Lauren wasn’t born into the monied class, but selling to them made his brand an icon of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one part of the reading I wasn’t sure about in the end was the Hello Kitty portion. Hello Kitty is meaningless, so what does it have to do with authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><category term="star trek" /><summary>At first, I wasn’t sure what the connection between the two readings we were assigned for Fandom this week was. “Buying In: The Pretty Good Problem” and “From Smart Fan to Backyard Wrestler: Performance, Context, and Aesthetic Violence (WWF)” seemed like very different subjects. Looking at the subject of next week’s class made it come together– we’ll be looking at Authenticity of Fandom. With Professional Wrestling, the fandom revolves around its inauthenticity, and authenticity differentiates companies with the Pretty Good Problem. In this way, the two readings complement each other.</summary></entry><entry><title>Catching Up on Readings</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Catching Up on Readings" /><published>2016-11-06T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-06T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup/">&lt;p&gt;I blog about every reading for Fandom, but over the last two weeks I’ve been too busy to blog about the previous readings. I’ll do so right now– we covered fan fiction with a reading, “Star Trek Reruns - Reread, Rewritten: Fan Writing as Textual Poaching” by Henry Jenkins, and then watched the TED Talk, “The Art of Asking” by Amanda Palmer. I was significantly more enthused for the former reading than the latter– I have pre-existing negative feelings about Palmer and this talk, and I’ve read other essays by Jenkins that I’ve enjoyed. Funnily, we read an essay by him for Big Games, but it had nothing to do with fandom– he’s just extremely prolific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Star Trek Reruns”, overall, reminded me of what Zoe dubbed the third-wave of fandom theory: that fandom is an extension of self, instead of the theories that fandom was utopia or recreated society. Overall, the essay was much more sympathetic to fandom than the first- or second-wave; it came as little surprise when Zoe later described Jenkins as one of the big names of third-wave fandom theory. I’m not sure about the “textual poaching” metaphor Jenkins uses however; it places fandom and its fan objects in too much opposition. Many fan objects encourage fan creation and “poaching”, but nobody would encourage people to poach from them non-metaphorically. Nowadays, though, “appropriation” also has baggage of its own, so there’s no perfect metaphor for what fandom does with its fan creations. Despite my objections, though, large swathes of the essay are still applicable today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, Jenkins rejects the idea that fans are “kooks” or “out-of-control”, stereotypes that are still employed by the mass media today. Think of any piece about bronies or female-oriented fandoms like Twilight. He also emphasizes that fans do things purely for fun– a refreshing change from overly analytical essays about fandom. Other things I appreciate about his essay are the ideas that fandom particularly appeals to the marginalized, as they can carve spaces for them to represent themselves; as I’ve written previously, fan fiction, for instance, is primarily written by women. The essay focuses on Star Trek, which is a fan object that is viewed by the media as the domain of male basement dwellers, but funnily, was kept going in part by the female fandom– TNG was started because of the fanbase’s longevity, which the female fanzines played a part in promoting. I’m not sure about Jenkins’ gendered analysis of media engagement, but overall the essay provides valuable insight into fan thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next week, we watched Amanda Palmer’s TED Talk, and I was already predisposed to dislike her so it was hard for me to watch. I primarily knew Palmer from her controversies: her ableist appropriation as Evelyn Evelyn (she pretends to be half of a pair of Siamese twins, essentially fetishizing the condition as weird and freak show-y); her poetry about the Boston Marathon Bomber, her use of unpaid musicians, and her blog posts decrying celebrity culture while simultaneously taking advantage of it. I really didn’t want to watch this TED Talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did watch it, it did not change my mind about Palmer. I still think of her as essentially unable to recognize her own privileges and acknowledge the criticisms of her; she makes a reference to the unpaid musician controversy in a way that seems unrepentant about it. It just strikes me all as extremely self-serving; we should allow fans to pay however they can for her music, including performing music for her. But this is an unequal trade that devalues their contribution; it equates them listening to her album with performance fees. I don’t terribly mind the idea of fans getting to perform with Palmer; it’s like paying to swim with dolphins. But when it’s labour performed for her, and she does’t understand why people would be upset by the idea, she just comes off as another rich lady pretending to be poor. The Simple Life for alternative folks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><category term="star trek" /><summary>I blog about every reading for Fandom, but over the last two weeks I’ve been too busy to blog about the previous readings. I’ll do so right now– we covered fan fiction with a reading, “Star Trek Reruns - Reread, Rewritten: Fan Writing as Textual Poaching” by Henry Jenkins, and then watched the TED Talk, “The Art of Asking” by Amanda Palmer. I was significantly more enthused for the former reading than the latter– I have pre-existing negative feelings about Palmer and this talk, and I’ve read other essays by Jenkins that I’ve enjoyed. Funnily, we read an essay by him for Big Games, but it had nothing to do with fandom– he’s just extremely prolific.</summary></entry><entry><title>Brainstorm</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brainstorm" /><published>2016-11-02T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm/">&lt;p&gt;If you could invent anything, what would you invent? It’s an easy question when you’re a kid, but as you get older, it gets increasingly hard. You become less imaginative, and you add more constraints on yourself. It should follow the laws of physics. It should be possible given my skill sets. It should be reasonably cost effective. The list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I originally had trouble thinking of ideas for my final physical computing project. I decided to brainstorm through a number of different lenses– constraints can occasionally help sharpen and inspire ideas. I first thought of “what projects might come up if I am inspired by my other classes?” Visual language and applications did not inspire very much– a real life colour eyedropper would be neat– but big games and fandom were a little more fruitful. I thought of projects that might help women in particular, and looked at dream inventions of women online: most tech entrepreneurs are men, so I suspected this would be an underserved market. Finally, I considered projects that might be of use in my personal life, which is surprisingly in need of little. I’ll list my rejected ideas below, as well as my top three choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rejected-ideas&quot;&gt;Rejected Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;school-inspired&quot;&gt;School-Inspired&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a number of ideas inspired by Harry Potter, a fandom I was obsessed with in high school– magic lends itself well to physical computing projects. I considered making real life versions of a number of things: a pensieve, a memory collector that would work out similarly to Rebecca Liebermann’s memory project; living portraits, an apparently common idea according to Tom Igoe’s blog posts; an invisibility cloak, a camera-heavy project that would likely be extremely costly and not terribly original; or a Marauder’s map, which is essentially in all our pockets with our GPS-enabled phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other ideas inspired by fandom were to create holographic-like communication devices akin to Star Wars or to create the outfit selection tool used by Cher in Clueless. These seemed camera intense and not terribly feasible, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried to think of projects inspired by gaming and my class big games, which was not entirely fruitful. Big games inherently involve a lot of people, and it’s often easier to use low tech solutions or leverage existing technologies everyone has. I did consider making a storytelling game– tag a few objects, and see how the story changes as you switch the objects in the story. I also considered making a Fitbit like tracker that used rpg paradigms to motivate the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;female-inspired-projects&quot;&gt;Female-Inspired Projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t intentional, but all of the female oriented projects I came up with revolve around the beauty industry. I imagine that it’s easier to get funding for more practical female tech products– there are a lot of period tracking apps, for example. I considered creating a little nail polish printer, for those who are as incompetent at nail art as I am. I considered tools to help you style your hair; holding tools up for he back of your head automatically. I considered mirror and lighting tools, and makeup projection mapping. None of them seemed like a great fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;projects-for-my-life&quot;&gt;Projects for My Life&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I considered a few projects that I might need in my life. Perhaps there could be a sensor for stains, that would tell you exactly how you should clean it to get rid of the stain. There could be a product that read barcodes and sensed vegetables, that suggested recipes based on what ingredients you have. One could develop an all in one gardening kit– a device that detects the perfect water, light, and nutrient levels for your plant, for people who lack green thumbs like I do. One could develop a digital pill box for people like me who are extremely forgetful– it should notify you if you forget, and instruct you on what to do if you accidentally skip a day of pills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-three-choices&quot;&gt;Top Three Choices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;colour-scanners&quot;&gt;3. Colour scanners&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that Adafruit had colour sensors in their store, and the possibilities of this are intriguing. On a very basic level, one could create a real life eyedropper for Photoshop and similar tools– scan a colour, and use it in your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, one could use the colour for real life applications: one could mix together colours and create a pen to colour with or nail polish to go on your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;comeback-machine&quot;&gt;2. Comeback machine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an idea, honestly, stolen from a women’s message board, but is honestly gender unspecific. I could create a little box or robot that you could insult, and it should do its best to come up with a come back. You would need speech recognition, but I think I can use the one from IBM Watson. It’s incredibly silly, but sounds like a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;real-life-sorting-hat&quot;&gt;1. Real Life Sorting Hat&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an idea inspired by my fandom class– I had been writing a fan fiction for Harry Potter for that class, so the idea was at the top of my mind. With each new school announced, the first thing at the top of fans’ minds is which house they would be sorted in. People love to fit in, and this would be great fun for kids and the young at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we clearly can’t read minds, we could get the hat to ask the users questions to sort them. We can either use microphones or an accelerometer to answer yes or no questions with a nod or a head shake. Then the hat would use speakers to announce the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty simple project, but if the production values are high it can be fairly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>If you could invent anything, what would you invent? It’s an easy question when you’re a kid, but as you get older, it gets increasingly hard. You become less imaginative, and you add more constraints on yourself. It should follow the laws of physics. It should be possible given my skill sets. It should be reasonably cost effective. The list goes on.</summary></entry><entry><title>Lab &amp;amp; Midterm</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/midterm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lab &amp; Midterm" /><published>2016-11-01T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/midterm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/midterm/">&lt;p&gt;Last week was the first week in which I failed to get my pcomp blogs up on time; finishing the midterm took me down to the wire, and even though I had finished the labs earlier in the week, I neglected the blog post for them. As such, here are the blog posts for them combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;labs&quot;&gt;Labs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, doing the labs was actually helpful to my understanding and completion of the midterm. Our project didn’t involve any serial output from p5, but I implemented handshaking by looking at the code for the labs– input from the keyboard and mouse get converted into a value for the LED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/l2JhwxqJ19Tq3iSas&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/252wzgNyrZR9S&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/8plRNFTYUHd3G&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/araBpAl3KU9EI&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most helpful was doing the Bluetooth lab, as the device is very finicky and particular about wiring. Thankfully the ER had some bluetooth ez-links– I wouldn’t have been able to do the lab nor our midterm without this supply!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_midterm/bluetooth.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_midterm/bluetooth.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midterm&quot;&gt;Midterm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the midterm, I worked with Chloe to convert her existing ICM homework into a physical computing project. She had created an application based around the Little Prince– all about how when you grow older, you fail to see the depths of people and the important things in life. You can view the original project here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggested that we carve out a book and use it as a controller, and perhaps add a touchscreen into the pages. After consulting Benedetta, we simplified the project to just using the book as a switch, and not a touchscreen– we didn’t need to overcomplicate. Later, though, our feedback from the class was largely commenting that they’d wished we did use a touchscreen. Everyone is very ambitious! It was hard enough getting what we had to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick jaunt to the Strand for a book to control, we divided the work as follows: Chloe would handle the cutting of the book; I’d handle the wiring; and we’d split the programming work. It worked out, though, that when it came down to the wire, Chloe handled a lot more of the wiring and I did the programming– in a rush, it’s easiest to play to your strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the work we brought into each other the next day. Since a lot of the materials had to be gotten at school, I just produced a Fritzing wiring diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_midterm/1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_midterm/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_midterm/fritzing.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_midterm/fritzing.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then wired up a button to test our project out. We did everything in increments; it makes it easier to debug and understand what we introduced that went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_midterm/2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_midterm/2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/2LLBr04DATybC&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this test was successful, we tried it on bluetooth and battery– this was also a success, thanks in part to doing the labs earlier. The wiring turned out to be very similar to the fritzing diagram I had produced, after a few mishaps with broken parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/SawSRnRIRVY5i&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this completed, we put everything in the book and changed the switch from a button to a photoresistor. We had originally intended to use conductive ribbon and create a concealed switch in the pages, but by the time we reached this point it was rather late and it seemed more prudent to work with the familiar. It worked relatively well– I just needed to be careful of the light values of each room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_midterm/5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_midterm/5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it was late, as I mentioned. The logic of the code was wrong, and the prince flickered when we closed the box. I was too tired, and could not figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/ybQFRiMgrZpo4&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a good night’s rest, I figured out my simple logic peoblem– I needed to remember the previous state and only update the screen when it changed. I took this time to add a few different book illustrations that changed when you opened and closed the book– I don’t think Chloe liked this as much, but it impressed the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/b51bx3x48MWk0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather cute, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>Last week was the first week in which I failed to get my pcomp blogs up on time; finishing the midterm took me down to the wire, and even though I had finished the labs earlier in the week, I neglected the blog post for them. As such, here are the blog posts for them combined.</summary></entry><entry><title>My First Fanfiction</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Fanfiction" /><published>2016-11-01T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-daily-prophet-special-report-harry-potter-and-the-muggle-biography&quot;&gt;THE DAILY PROPHET SPECIAL REPORT: HARRY POTTER AND THE MUGGLE BIOGRAPHY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Katie Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to imagine now, but there was a time fairly recently when magic was kept secret from Muggles. Wizardry was thought by them to be the domain of liars and charlatans. This attitude rapidly changed, but it was not solely because of the groundbreaking and controversial repeal of the International Statute of Wizarding Secrecy in 2002. Rather, it was the publishing of the wildly popular biographical series about Harry Potter by Muggle historian, J.K. Rowling, that changed Muggle attitudes about witchcraft and wizardry. As we come up to the 10th anniversary of their first publication in 2007, The Daily Prophet takes a look back on how both the Wizarding and Muggle worlds have changed since the publication of these influential works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-hogwarts&quot;&gt;AT HOGWARTS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Honestly, I think those books gave me the wrong impression,” admits Muggleborn Hufflepuff Jacinda Maysle, “I was prepared to give up using pencils.” Luckily for Ms. Maysle, Hogwarts has adopted a more lax attitude to Muggle technologies since the school days of Harry Potter. Although Ms. Rowling did thorough research and described Hogwarts life fairly accurately for the timeframe, the repealing and the appointment of Minerva McGonagall, a half-blood herself, has allowed for small but significant changes. Although quills are still mandatory for all official examinations, enchanted pens and pencils are now allowed for note-taking and small assignments. “Bless the Muggles who invented these pen sills [sic],” says Arithmancy Professor, Naomi Okino. “They’ve become critical to my numerological work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Half-bloods and Muggleborns of all houses grumble about the lack of internet connectivity, and beg the administration to be allowed laptops and mobile devices. On this point, the Headmistress has not budged. As the modern pencil was invented in the 16th century, perhaps in another 500 years Hogwarts will be connected to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-magical-britain&quot;&gt;IN MAGICAL BRITAIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the country, however, Internet connectivity is a novelty and being adopted widely. “Have you heard of this thing they call ‘Googol Translate’?” asks former Minister of Magic, Cornelius Fudge, when asked for comment. “It’s simply marvelous! You simply have to type in your message– I hate typing, but magic doesn’t work with these things– and it translates English into any language you give it.” He is more reticent when I ask him about a translation incident during the 1994 Quidditch World Cup, recounted in the fourth book of J.K. Rowling’s series. “Oh no, that didn’t happen,” he blusters. “That entire book series is just rubbish. I’ll have you know that I employed every resource to support of Harry Potter that entire time!” Fudge is insistent, but witness reports do not corroborate his claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other prominent figures do not share Fudge’s enthusiasm for the Internet however. Although the Malfoy family historically had good relationships with Muggle highborns– a fact accepted by historians but disputed by the family– Draco Malfoy has a contentious relationship with Muggles and the Internet. “Everything written in that thing is completely false,” he says, rolling his eyes at me, “it’s worse than the rag you work for.” (Ed: the Daily Prophet would like to note it now employs an extensive fact checking team.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Malfoy is no doubt referring to the rumours linking him and Mr. Potter in a romantic relationship, which did not die down when Mr. Malfoy wed Astoria Greenglass. The Wizarding internet is full of such rumours, partially flamed by gossip columnist like the Daily Prophet’s Rita Skeeter, who supplements her columns with online gossip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-muggle-britain&quot;&gt;IN MUGGLE BRITAIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite how the Harry Potter biographies were widely read, nonwizarding Britain has not substantially been changed by the influence of magic. Although magic is no longer a secret from them, the Wizarding world is still separate; Muggles are not allowed at Hogwarts or Diagon Alley without explicit permission from the Ministry of Magic. Consequentially, most Muggles do not see or experience magic in their day to day lives, nor are wizards generally employed by Muggles or vice versa, with a few exceptions. Muggles working in IT and telecommunications, for instance, are routinely welcomed in wizarding homes to install ADSL and cable connections; however, as soon as the job is done and a payment of gold and conjured food is secured, they are usually not welcome for much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizards are occasionally employed in the visual effects and movie making industry for special effects too difficult to convincingly create using computer technologies. Few wizards would admit to the fact, though, as such work is typically seen as beneath their abilities and humiliating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;worldwide&quot;&gt;WORLDWIDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizarding communities around the globe have not changed as much as magical Britain since the publication of these books. “Magical America has long adopted many of the conveniences created by non-magical Americans,” asserts a spokesperson for the US’s Department of Magic, Christopher Delaney. “We pride ourselves in being on top of the latest technologies.” He frowns, though, at the lack of representation of other cultures and inaccuracies laid out in J.K. Rowling’s books. “These books were also wildly popular here, but the Department denounces their inaccuracies.” In particular, he objects to the portrayal of the worldwide wizarding community’s reaction to the Second Wizarding War. “It reads as if we all stood by as the UK went up in flames. We didn’t do that. Our help was largely rejected.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan’s Minister of Magic, Makoto Ueda, has similar objections. “Japan sent many healers and peacekeepers over to the UK during the Second Wizarding War. We are proud of our heritage of protecting people from the Dark Arts.” He does not bring it up, but Ueda seems miffed when I ask him about Rowling’s recent blog posts about worldwide wizardry. “Although Ms. Rowling is a capable researcher of Magical Britain, she does not do thorough work on the rest of the Wizarding world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, she asserts that there are only eleven major wizarding schools, with the remaining witches and wizards studying at home or at less prestigious schools. Many countries would dispute this, with China alone accounting for 15 major schools of its own. “Frankly, Ms. Rowling should leave the subject to local researchers,” says Hinata Okomoto, a Japanese historian. “I believe she was mislead by mischievous exchange students to Hogwarts, who told her falsehoods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assertion is corroborated by her writings on Mahoutokoro, the supposed wizarding school of Japan. In reality, Japan is home to two competing schools, neither of which are located on the island of Iwojima nor have Karate-belt-like colour-changing robes. This has led to many headaches for Ms. Okamoto. “Magical Japan has a rich and deep history of its own,” she says, “and in the past, I would get inquiries about that. Now, all I am ever asked are what houses ‘Mahoutokoro’ has, and what houses I would sort a person into. It’s very dispiriting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J.K. Rowling’s biographical series on Harry Potter has had many effects, such as making Muggles significantly more willing to work with the Wizarding World. However, it’s also flattened Muggle’s conception of magic, to the detriment of other magical communities. We will see in the years to come the full impact of her works, particularly as she has announced her biographies on famed adventurer, Newt Scamander. The Daily Prophet hopes she does her research and makes a positive impact on the Wizarding World.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><category term="harry potter" /><summary>THE DAILY PROPHET SPECIAL REPORT: HARRY POTTER AND THE MUGGLE BIOGRAPHY</summary></entry><entry><title>Making Money off Fandom</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Money off Fandom" /><published>2016-10-31T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-31T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I worked with Sunnie, Richard, and Patrick on an unusual task: make money with fandom. We thought of many different ideas: I suggested 3D printing things using ITP’s printers and selling them to people; we brainstormed workshops and other things to which we could charge admission; I tried to convince Richard to make use of his artistic skills and sell people commissioned drawings. There were many events that weekend that we thought we could take advantage of: Tompkins Square had a Halloween Costumed Dog Parade, and there would be a pantsuit rally for Hillary Clinton. We also brainstormed internet exchanges for funds, such as selling on Etsy or Redbubble. We soon found ourselves short on time, though, and fell back on an easy plan: make something in person. Sell this thing in person. ??? Profit. (Hopefully?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a plan that was more financially sound than that of the Underpants Gnomes. At least there was a financial exchange embedded in our plan. We considered selling the stickers on coffee cups and selling the coffee– I found graphics for Star Fox coffee and made one for Super Smash Bros coffee, knowing that people regularly played Smash Brothers in the Tisch basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/coffee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/coffee.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that this was potentially illegal and dangerous. Why not sell the stickers directly, and skip the coffee? Can’t poison anybody with a sticker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I compiled a few graphics with the suggestion of the others on fandoms that might sell. Sunnie was particularly in favour of the political stickers, so I made “bad hombre” and “nasty women” stickers for the Hillary Clinton fandom. In November, a new Gilmore Girls series would come out, and a trailer had just been released for it, so we included Luke’s diner stickers. Finally, I decided to include Nintendo Switch stickers and Overwatch stickers. The Nintendo Switch trailer had only come out that week, and Overwatch was still a fairly new fandom. All of these stickers would have limited availability outside of our little sticker printing enterprise; it was unlikely that anybody had these stickers already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard bought the sticker paper and Sunnie and I headed to Bobst library for colour printing. To my great relief, we could load our own paper into the laser printers, and they came out perfectly. Richard cut them out, and it was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/stickers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/stickers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four of us each received a subset of the stickers to sell, and we had different strategies. The first dollar we ever made– the minimum amount we had to make for this assignment– was actually made by selling to my friends. The assignment had stipulated that we shouldn’t sell to people we already knew, but they wanted the stickers and who am I to deny them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/sales.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/sales.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining $12 that we had made was sold to actual strangers though. We largely did so at the Tisch building, so outside of a fandom context. The four of us didn’t quite agree on a pricing strategy, and I believe Richard was most successful with his pay what you can policy. I had settled on a dollar for the big stickers and 50 cents for the smaller ones; Sunnie gave them away for 50 cents for as many as you liked. Patrick haggled with people to sell them in bulk, since we ended up with many left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling was a fun experience, with some unusual experiences. For me, some notable events included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surprising two game center librarians by offering them Overwatch stickers for sale, as they were playing Overwatch at the time. “Oh my god!” they reacted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard sold political stickers to a girl, who explained the joke to another girl, who promptly bought them as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having good conversations about Gilmore Girls (Rory should end up with none of the love interests, imo) with various customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned that fandom is enough to sell people on things they should normally be much cheaper (each sticker cost a few cents for their material), and it was interesting to see fandom play out in real life, outside of the context of fandom-specific events. The most prominent takeaway, though, was that many people do not carry cash or change with them any longer (or claim not to, such that they don’t have to buy a sticker.) We offered to Venmo people, but people were less willing to do so for small (less than a dollar) amounts. Next time: consider selling more expensive things for fandom. Then they might have the cash on hand for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Last week, I worked with Sunnie, Richard, and Patrick on an unusual task: make money with fandom. We thought of many different ideas: I suggested 3D printing things using ITP’s printers and selling them to people; we brainstormed workshops and other things to which we could charge admission; I tried to convince Richard to make use of his artistic skills and sell people commissioned drawings. There were many events that weekend that we thought we could take advantage of: Tompkins Square had a Halloween Costumed Dog Parade, and there would be a pantsuit rally for Hillary Clinton. We also brainstormed internet exchanges for funds, such as selling on Etsy or Redbubble. We soon found ourselves short on time, though, and fell back on an easy plan: make something in person. Sell this thing in person. ??? Profit. (Hopefully?)</summary></entry><entry><title>Vancouver</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vancouver" /><published>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/">&lt;p&gt;I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few running themes that I clearly associate with Vancouver. One is nature: Vancouver is a city with a lot of natural beauty. You can go surfing in the morning and skiing at night, just with a car or by transit. There are also a lot of water-related words; the Georgia strait runs alongside Vancouver to become the Burrard Inlet. There are so many different bodies of water nearby that I didn’t think to include any in the word cloud. There are also a lot of outdoor activities, as well as alternate forms of transportation– Vancouver is not a car-centric town, and many city planners worldwide admire it for opting not to have a highway that cuts through downtown. Finally, I’ve included a few different cultures and foods in here; Vancouver is fairly diverse, and the food reflects that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-sketches--refinement&quot;&gt;Initial Sketches &amp;amp; Refinement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off by drawing a number of sketches drawing from the themes of my word cloud. I played with whitespace and shapes, but overall I gravitated towards the idea that Vancouver is a modern city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I favoured my fourth logo concept, but then I decided to look at existing logos for Vancouver to get an idea of the ecosystem my logo would exist in. As it turns out, my logos were often very similar to existing logo concepts– they seeped into my subconscious. Consequentially, I decided on logo concept #2– a literal take on a city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drew a clearer sketch of the idea on my tablet, and then took it into Illustrator for vectorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-concept&quot;&gt;Final Concept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product is slightly different from the refinement. I tilted the buildings to give the logo a bit more depth, and paired with the city’s name in Metro, a geometric typeface that was designed to compete with Futura, yet be a bit more humanist. It was created in 1929– around the same time Vancouver was amalgamated with Point Grey and South Vancouver– and was popular through the 1950s when Vancouver was developing its signature city planning policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logo-in-context&quot;&gt;Logo in Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><category term="logo" /><summary>I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.</summary></entry><entry><title>Appropriation Matrix</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appropriation Matrix" /><published>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/">&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/appropmatrix.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;appropmatrix.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.</summary></entry><entry><title>Serial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serial" /><published>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/">&lt;p&gt;It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lab was a fairly straightforward introduction to serial communication and particularly the notion of character encoding and representation; along with understanding binary vs decimal vs hex, it’s the most review of my CS degree we’ve tackled so far in PComp. It can still be a little tricky for me to remember what a bit is versus a byte versus a nibble; I’m usually a pretty high-level programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second lab connected P5 to the Arduino via serial connections; this was far more expressive than the serial monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waived ICM and haven’t touched P5 before these labs, so I decided to do a creative application to get myself accustomed to it. I had to learn the frustrations of everyone else. Personally, I think P5 is a poor choice for learning to programming; you spend a lot of time thinking about coordinates in a way that you won’t necessarily need to in many programming languages (granted, you do have to do so if you’re doing primarily graphics, but I don’t think most programmers do.) In any case, here’s my little house. It is sunny when you leave the photoresistor uncovered, turns cloudy when it’s partially covered, and becomes night when it’s fully covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/wxlETaoG10S9G&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do a great job of documenting here– my hand is mostly out of frame. I think you can still get the gist of it, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.</summary></entry></feed>
