<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-10-09T14:21:54-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Counterculture and Commercial Ventures</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Counterculture and Commercial Ventures" /><published>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/">&lt;p&gt;The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films &lt;em&gt;Escape from Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for the lack of outrage is because both groups remain deeply embedded in their respective fan communities. When you are callrd a sellout, it’s often for a perceived betrayal of the community: by foregrounding your commercial interests, you are placing your own needs above those of the community. The skaters of x largely don’t have this problem because their commercial sales were initially to each other– by keeping within the community, you don’t seem like a sellout. The last example of Tony Hawk is the most likely to be called a sellout, with his tacit approval of people who are not skaters participating in skate culture. However, he can deflect accusations of selling out by claiming that his ventures are evangelization– he is encouraging the expansion of his community– and profit-sharing– by including other skaters in his video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Disneyland social clubs are communities themselves and part of the larger Disney community. They embrace larger Disney values, and accept questions and criticism from regular parkgoers (“feel free to ask any questions” and “always say hi” advises one leader cited in the article.) By following the existing codes of behaviour of the Disney community, they’ve earned themselves tolerance. Additionally, by banding together, they’re also able to protect each other– the films I mentioned in the opening are by solo auteurs, and by being alone they are easier for a corporation to target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;values-and-fan-context&quot;&gt;Values and Fan Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why these groups do not provoke fan outrage is that the fan objects– skateboard culture and Disney– do not have values that disallow or discourage this intersection. Although skateboarding is purportedly rebellious, nothing in its fan context disapproves of commercial interests. The first team even formed as part of a local skate shop, Zephyr, and young fans hope to gain sponsorship deals. Arguably, selling things is a part of the fan context. So long as you’re not printing anti-skate park propaganda, you’re still behaving in line with skateboarding culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social clubs of Disneyland do not look like they represent Disney values, but they prove themselves with their actions. They raise money for charity, and try their best to help people. Disney values are often about children and family, and many social clubs bring their children along, or act as family for each other. Disney wants to look inclusive, so they include the social clubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commodification&quot;&gt;Commodification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one last reason that this intersection is tolerated is commercial: everybody wants to make a living. Skateboarders need to make money somehow, so why would they begrudge the ones who manage to turn their counterculture into a career? If anything, that’s to be admired: doing something they love while making money. Disney profits from the social clubs via their annual memberships, as well as their buying food and merchandise. There’s no reason to turn this money down by shutting these clubs down. Overall, counterculture and commerce can intersect peacefully– so long as it stays in line with core values.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films Escape from Tomorrow, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?</summary></entry><entry><title>Let’s Get Down to Business</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Get Down to Business" /><published>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/">&lt;p&gt;I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important factors in the design of my business cards was the redesign of my portfolio and blog. When I started ITP, I knew I would have to redesign both: I failed to update them in years, and class after class emphasized to me that the blog was a central part of ITP. I also wanted to move my blog to the ceiling.cat domain, a novelty domain that I’d owned for years but had done nothing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were an internet nerd in the mid 2000s, you’d probably remember this meme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I wanted was to have matching but separate identities for both websites. The portfolio was serious, and meant to showcase my best work; the blog was for works in progress and silly thoughts from ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted the blog to have a logo with a cat. It didn’t make much sense to do otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize: I wanted to have a logo template that would work for a serious portfolio as well as a cat. That’s a bit of a tough briefing, but it’s aided by how the original ceiling cat appears: he pops out of a square hole in the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequentially, I can start with a square template for both logos– it’s clean and professional for my portfolio, and appropriate for ceiling cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/template.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/template.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to subtly evoke stamps and Chinese seals– it’d reflect my heritage and help give the logos a unified idea. I rounded the corners and decided that the logos would be single colour, as if they could be stamped on. Then, I could convert them to black and white, any colours, or even add an image to the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is getting a bit long-winded, so I’ll spare you more details about the logos. Suffice to say, I drew a bunch of cats, and tested a bunch of typefaces, and came out with the following two logos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/logos.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/logos.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-original-design&quot;&gt;The Original Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this starting point, I decided to make my business cards on Sunday. Given the ‘chinese seal’ design element, I decided to take scroll paintings as inspiration, and drew a digital watercolour painting of a bird on a cherry blossom tree. (My street in Vancouver was lined with cherry blossoms, as many are.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/flowers.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/flowers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The painting’s focal is from right to left, as most Chinese scrolls are, and I consequentially placed my seal and my information on the left of the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/original.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/original.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished at this point, and then the next day I went to class. I received the assignment, and changed things for the worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-redesign&quot;&gt;The Redesign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most consequential change was that the assignment stipulated that the card had to be double sided. I originally tried making the painting go across the two sides, but the image was too low-resolution to print at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/spread.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/spread.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then decided to stick with the image on one side, and just moved the information to the back. I also flipped the painting, because we discussed in class how the lower left corner was the weakest focal point of an image (which, in retrospect now, is less consequential in a landscape business card with its low height.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/double.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/double.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent this image to the printers, which I terribly regret. In retrospect, landscape business cards are too short for that focus information to matter, and images always look better before they’re flipped (unless they are perfectly symmetrical.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it’s overall a stronger design on only one side. I also regret the serif font I chose on the back– I thought it would provide a nice contrast, but it just looks out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I wish I kept my original card. But you can keep this analysis in the meanwhile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visuallang" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.</summary></entry><entry><title>Westworld</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Westworld" /><published>2016-10-04T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/04/westworld/">&lt;p&gt;New fandoms are different spaces from older fandoms. Customs have yet to be codified; big name fans have yet to become prominent. In-jokes and norms take time to become established. This week in fandom, Patrick and I took a look at the fandom for Westworld to analyze the techniques to form a group and create group cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westworld is an interesting example, in that it’s both a brand new fandom– the first episode aired only on Sunday (October 2)– and a natural offshoot of older fandoms. It’s a new HBO show that is produced by J.J. Abrams and Jonathan Nolan, who both have sizeable fandoms of their own. J.J. Abrams is known for directing the new Star Wars, the Star Trek reboots, and other films, as well as producing cult TV Shows like Lost and Fringe. Jonathan Nolan– though not as well known as his older brother, director Christopher Nolan– is well known for his collaborations with Christopher on screenplays like Interstellar, and being the showrunner for Person of Interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also based on a movie written and directed by the author of Jurassic Park, Michael Crichton. Plot-wise, it’s very similar to Jurassic Park: Westworld also revolves around a theme park wherein its captive attractions go rogue. This time, though, it’s a science fiction story about a Western theme park filled with robots that become sentient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this extensive pedigree, Westworld had a lot of hype and a lot of high expectations– at a budget of $100 million for its first season, HBO needed it to be a success. So far, it seems to have connected with its audience: the first episode had 3.3 million viewers, the best premiere for HBO in the last three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fans&quot;&gt;The Fans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who tuned into Westworld? Based on just its pedigree, we can make a few assumptions about its fans. It’s an HBO show, so they’ll be accustomed to seeing nudity and on-screen violence (including sexual violence). Because Abrams and Nolan are involved, the fans will be very speculative and will come up with tons of explanations. If you remember Lost, that show caused fans to come up with tons of theories on the nature of the show, the significance of the numbers, and more. For Nolan, even mentioning the spinning top of Inception might make your eyes roll. Additionally, fans of both pride themselves on attention to detail and will point out little things (often in aid of elaborate theories.) It’s easy to extend these qualities to fans of Westworld: speculation and digging for secrets will be a huge part of this fan community, and apparently already is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the fans should have the same qualities as most fans of science fiction and westerns. However, it’s tough to say for sure if this is representative of the whole audience: although the most vocal audience members of Game of Thrones are pre-existing fans of fantasy, the whole viewing audience is surprisingly diverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cohesion-activities&quot;&gt;Cohesion Activities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although some cohesion activities were harder to find– no debates have been ritualized yet, and people were not quite jostling for hierarchy yet (beyond just getting upvotes and reblogs)– others were extremely easy. Exchanging knowledge or gifts was the bulk of fan activity surrounding Westworld, with the predicted theories emerging and details being pointed out to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/wanted.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/wanted.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/milk.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/milk.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/flies.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/flies.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a theory was particularly good, or a rare piece of fan creation appeared, acknowledgement and flattery appeared in spades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/spoileroriginal.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/spoileroriginal.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/spoiler.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/spoiler.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/foreshadowing.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/foreshadowing.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/tldr.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/tldr.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/goodcatch.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/goodcatch.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although for the most part, social norms have not been established, there are some holdover norms from other fandoms that have applied to Westworld. With time, we’ll see if these cultural norms apply to Westworld fans or were just a one-time event. For now though, fans enforce the same cultural norms as other HBO shows– namely Game of Thrones– and other science fiction properties: to criticize those who might analyze the show with a feminist lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/pwned.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/pwned.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/nitpick.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/nitpick.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/brett.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/brett.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, fans do punish infractions, though infractions largely haven’t been established either. One thing is certain though: you don’t post in the Westworld subreddit if you dont like the show. The two following posts have a reasonable tone and don’t make any untrue points, but they were still downvoted and hidden by Westworld fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/featurette.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/featurette.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/westworld/cupoftea.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;westworld/cupoftea.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this only counts a day or two of activity, we can already see how the Westworld fan group is forming and what its fans might look like in the future. Lots of speculation is key to its cohesion, and encouraging this fan behaviour and discouraging others will define Westworld fans as more episodes air.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>New fandoms are different spaces from older fandoms. Customs have yet to be codified; big name fans have yet to become prominent. In-jokes and norms take time to become established. This week in fandom, Patrick and I took a look at the fandom for Westworld to analyze the techniques to form a group and create group cohesion.</summary></entry><entry><title>Noters and Motors</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Noters and Motors" /><published>2016-10-01T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/01/servos/">&lt;p&gt;Since I had already worked with the piezo speaker last week, the labs this week for physical computing were a breeze. What was a little tougher was thinking of another creative application. Should I work with the piezo again? Should I just fix up my previous project? Instead, I decided to play a little more with the servo motor. It’s not as interesting as the Mario music, but a little more interesting than rote labs, which I’ll cover first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rote labs: riveting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up: wiring two photoresistors into an Arduino, and then translating the input into tones for the piezo. This was very annoying to listen to, so I’ll spare you the video for it and instead just play you a pleasant melody:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oUr1l6a2cD8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I don’t have any force sensing resistors, I just made a keyboard with the same photoresistors. Laziness rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QOUL3PrjpCI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I hooked up a servo to a potentiometer. GIF created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/OShZOGqKpU6GI&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught a cold over the weekend, so my mind’s been a little temperature focused. I’ve been meaning to remove my air conditioner from the window, but I should probably wait until I’m feeling less feeble. Unfortunately, that also means that I have to endure the cold air that the air conditioner is letting through. Exactly how cold is my room? How can I know in a temperature system that isn’t backwards? All the thermometers around me are Fahrenheit. (Sorry, Fahrenheit, but it’s true. You only make sense when measuring people.) I decided to make a little temperature gauge with my Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the high and low temperature of the gauge, I looked at the historical highs and lows of New York– it reached 38.6°C in 1966 and was -20°C in 1994. Consequentially, I decided on setting the range at -20 to 40°C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/temperaturecode.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;temperaturecode.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the gauge, I used the Arduino to set the servo to 0, drew a notch, set the servo to 179, drew a notch, and then drew notches in between. It’s super jaggy, so I should probably consider using capacitors to smooth it out. It’s probably not the most accurate temperature gauge either, but it’s enough to confirm for me: my room is too cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/temperaturegauge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;temperaturegauge.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’m less sick, I’ll get that A/C out of the window. For now, jumper wires are as much as I’ll lift.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>Since I had already worked with the piezo speaker last week, the labs this week for physical computing were a breeze. What was a little tougher was thinking of another creative application. Should I work with the piezo again? Should I just fix up my previous project? Instead, I decided to play a little more with the servo motor. It’s not as interesting as the Mario music, but a little more interesting than rote labs, which I’ll cover first.</summary></entry><entry><title>Colouring Book</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/28/colouring-book/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Colouring Book" /><published>2016-09-28T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-28T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/28/colouring-book</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/28/colouring-book/">&lt;p&gt;What colours are predominant in our lives? If I close my eyes and imagine a scene from my life, the colours that are prominent are very different from the ones that I see on a day to day basis. But I haven’t lived in New York for very long; once my memories of Vancouver start to fade, the colours of that city will fade to the concrete and brick that surrounds me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of what we see is constructed, and the construction materials of these cities are often different. New York is a much older city than my hometown, and the buildings reflect the styles of the time. Apartments are also more common here; wooden houses are seen less often. Vancouver is noted, and immortalized by the author Douglas Coupland, as a city of glass; New York, despite its skyscraper reputation, has less glass in its construction. It’s not just because I live in Brooklyn and go to school in the village– even in the Financial District and Midtown, the city is less dominated by glass and steel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently: when I close my eyes, I imagine wooden houses painted in many colours or barely stained, cherry blossom trees lining every street, the greenest grass and flowering bushes, and blue green skyscrapers. This does not reflect my current reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some pictures over a day to capture the background colours of my current reality. I thankfully have wooden floors at home and ITP, so I do have a break from the greys and pale blues of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_colour/contact.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_colour/contact.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also then applied a mosaic filter to this thumbnail sheet, to get a better sense of the average colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_colour/contact-m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_colour/contact-m.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue, black, white, grey, beige. It’s a very common palette here, and, honestly, they’re the colours that dominate my wardrobe. Maybe I belong here more than Vancouver; I’ve never been in touch with nature and I have been always fond of muted colour schemes. They’re calm, as I would like to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few outlier colours here, but some are more notable than others. The purple lighting in one of these photos scream, but that’s just for that plant and not usually on. I don’t think it really reflects my life, particular since it’s not my plant. I also wear a lot of burgundy and that is not included here. It’s rich, but not too loud. I think this does reflect my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cap this off, I’ve created an image to capture the colours of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_colour/voxel.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_colour/voxel.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.s. I also took the colour hue test, and here are my results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_colour/hue_test.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_colour/hue_test.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visuallang" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>What colours are predominant in our lives? If I close my eyes and imagine a scene from my life, the colours that are prominent are very different from the ones that I see on a day to day basis. But I haven’t lived in New York for very long; once my memories of Vancouver start to fade, the colours of that city will fade to the concrete and brick that surrounds me.</summary></entry><entry><title>Digital In, Heartbreak Out</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/27/digital-heartbreak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital In, Heartbreak Out" /><published>2016-09-27T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/27/digital-heartbreak</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/27/digital-heartbreak/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned some valuable lessons today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;always-save-your-work&quot;&gt;Always save your work.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a lesson I had always known, but today I will amend it with some secondary lessons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sketch in Arduino is a temporary file and is not saved, no matter how many times you hit CMD+S.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you close the Arduino app, say, to load a new library, this temporary file will be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save your sketch in a new file lest it be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are things I wish I had known this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. In case I forget to ask: my question for next week is whether there is an OSX oscilloscope app? If we’re connecting our Arduino for the computer anyways, using a separate device seems a bit redundant unless you need high precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;labs&quot;&gt;Labs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get to the story implied in the above lessons, I’ll cover the labs that I did to prepare for my heartbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was connect a button as a digital input, and then I printed to serial to see if it was pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/digitalin_lab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;digitalin_lab.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then connected some LEDs to the same circuit as digital outputs, essentially making the same circuits we did last week, but with the Arduino as middleware in between this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/obDJLEKVogZ6U&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I connected an actuator to serve as an analog input to turn on an LED, which makes for a bit of a dull video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/3CBoHiPOfavuw&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heartbreak&quot;&gt;Heartbreak&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then started working on my project for the week, where I learned some valuable lessons about saving your work. I had the bright idea of a Mario simulator. I hooked up a piezo speaker and a photo resister to my Arduino, with the following idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the photo resister is uncovered or it’s light out, play the regular Mario theme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if the photo resister is covered or it’s dark out, play the underground Mario theme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you transition between either of these states, play the Mario pipe noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a bit of time, but I more or less got this working. I put in some delays for debugging, and then had the bright idea to use the TimedAction library. A problem I was having was that each song had to finish playing before I switched states, so I thought TimedAction would help with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I closed the Arduino app to install TimedAction. I reopened it to see that my program was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, i hadn’t reset the Arduino itself, so the app sort of still worked on the board itself– though it is marred with delays for debugging. So I do have video evidence of my handiwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, without the source code, I would need to rewrite it completely to refine the code, or to at least remove the delays. I assume the board only stores a compiled version, so to try and retrieve it from there would require decompilation and a bit of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, you can enjoy this video. And until I reset the board, one could also enjoy little Mario tunes on it in person as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2djO7CtVWRY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>I’ve learned some valuable lessons today.</summary></entry><entry><title>Fan Communities</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/tompetty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fan Communities" /><published>2016-09-25T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-25T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/tompetty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/tompetty/">&lt;p&gt;When I hear the name “Tom Petty”, the first thing I think of is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PQ4o1N4ksyQ&quot;&gt;old standup routine about Google that my old roommates used to repeat&lt;/a&gt;. Only after thinking about the routine do I remember “Free Falling” or “American Girl” or the Travelling Wilburys. Consequentially, both the Tom Petty fans and the Cliff Richard fans described in “Tom Petty: Temperance and religiosity in a non-marginal, non-stigmatized brand community” (Schau, Muniz Jr) and “Imprinting, Incubation and Intensification: Factors Contributing to Fan Club Formation and Continuance” (Henry, Caldwell) were utterly foreign to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PQ4o1N4ksyQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that occurred to me while reading, with this standup piece in mind, was that perhaps the fan activities we learned in class were not wholly sufficient: is it not a unique fan activity to learn as much as you can about an artist? (Or, in the parlance of that standup bit, remember where Tom Petty is from?) The Tom Petty fans make this fan activity explicit with a list of “10 Things Every TPATH fan knows” (Schau, 158) but this is classified by the author under a ‘ritual’. I’m not sure this knowledge gaining is necessarily ritualized in most fandoms, though, but it seems to me to be a form of fan activity. Nowadays, with the Internet in our lives, it’s not necessary to remember anything about your fandom– it’s easy to look any bit of trivia up. I can easily identify a hardcore fan by their memorization of these inconsequential facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I once wondered how wizards in Harry Potter learned foreign languages, and asked two of my fan friends. Within minutes, they reported that this was not addressed in canon, but that no spell for translation existed, citing the Goblet of Fire chapters during the Wizarding World Cup. I don’t think any lesser fan could’ve answered this query so thoroughly.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that struck me about these readings was that I don’t think I’ve been as big of a fan of anything as the fans of Richard and Petty are in these articles. I haven’t really made friends because of a particular fandom; I’ve only deepened pre-existing friendships by bonding over them. This is true despite how I used to work for anime conventions and was the anime club president during high school. During conventions and meetings I would only hang out with friends I’d already known,  and honestly, being a part of them made me a bit sick of anime in general. (I quit watching it abruptly when high school ended.) But Cliff Richard fans, in particular, forged new friendships because of Richard– it was rather cute when a fan answered what life would be like without Cliff with the immediate response, “we would not have met.” (Henry, 171).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve felt like a fan of things for a long time, but I don’t think I’ve really felt a sense of belonging or partook in traditions and obligations. Have I been a fan without being part of a fan group? I suppose the anime club did not count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is because I haven’t experienced a “bolt of lightning” imprinting of fandom as described in class. I’ve mostly fallen into fandoms very casually– my friends would’ve read or experienced something, and I’d join in. I’d watch a TV show because it was on when I got home from school, and then become a fan as I watched more regularly. For any given fandom I identify myself as a part of, I don’t think I can recall the moment when I became a fan. Perhaps I’m permanently stuck in the ‘incubation’ stage of most of my fandoms, but I do know that fangroups exist for them– I just have little interest in devoting the time in finding them and maintaining those relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things I didn’t identify with in these articles are the parasocial relationships and admiring a celebrity for having characteristics I desire for myself. I’m areligious and don’t admire any celebrities in particular. I suppose they offer me nothing in terms of personality traits I admire. For fandoms that are media properties, it makes more sense to me– I gravitate towards coming of age stories and stories that involve “special” outcasts (see: X-Men and Harry Potter fandoms.) It’s a common fixation, almost the entirety of the young adult fiction genre, as well as the collective works of Ayn Rand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don’t participate in fan communities myself, I do have a good number of friends who do participate in fandom– two of my friends, as I mentioned, are hardcore Harry Potter fans and run a Harry Potter roleplaying blog. It’s been interesting to observe, and I do think the patterns mentioned in these pieces have largely been followed by them. Their ability to quote J.K. Rowling seems pseudo-religious, and they’ve been on legitimate Harry Potter pilgrimages: they’ve been to fan conventions to meet the actors of the films; they’ve seen Rowling at readings; they’ve been to Universal Studios for the Harry Potter ride. One of them even flew to Florida just to go to LeakyCon, a Harry Potter fan convention, and attributes Potter for getting her through high school bullying (even though the stigma may have contributed to the bullying? It’s tough to say.) That sounds like a pseudo-religious tale of the miraculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I don’t think I’ve been a part of a fan community, it’s been interesting being adjacent to fans who inarguably are. Also: I at least know where Tom Petty is from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>When I hear the name “Tom Petty”, the first thing I think of is an old standup routine about Google that my old roommates used to repeat. Only after thinking about the routine do I remember “Free Falling” or “American Girl” or the Travelling Wilburys. Consequentially, both the Tom Petty fans and the Cliff Richard fans described in “Tom Petty: Temperance and religiosity in a non-marginal, non-stigmatized brand community” (Schau, Muniz Jr) and “Imprinting, Incubation and Intensification: Factors Contributing to Fan Club Formation and Continuance” (Henry, Caldwell) were utterly foreign to me.</summary></entry><entry><title>Observation</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/observation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Observation" /><published>2016-09-25T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-25T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/observation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/25/observation/">&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of trouble deciding on what piece of interactive technology to observe for this blog post. We had to pick one used by the public, but try not to be seen observing them. Pick one that you can wait around near without being conspicuous. Pick one that you could hopefully take pictures of without seeming like you’re casing the store or establishment. This last criterion was the hardest. It ruled out most stores’ checkout machines, Amazon lockers, and other kiosks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t want to choose any interactive art piece, since there isn’t necessarily a “correct” or expected way to use one of those. After realizing that most NYPL branches are closed on Sundays– my first choice were self-checkout machines for books– I pretended to wait for a friend at the Regal Cinemas Union Square. You could wait a while around the lobby in theatres for a while– waiting for a friend who will never arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been to a movie theatre in the US, but I’ve been to a great deal of them in Canada. I assumed that movie habits were largely the same between our two countries. In Canada, most people pick a movie they want to see, arrive around 30-10 minutes before the film, and then buy tickets at a self-serve kiosk. People weren’t entirely behaving as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caveats: I was at a Regal theatre, which isn’t the dominant theatre chain in New York as far as I can tell. This was a Sunday afternoon, so there were fewer people than on a Friday evening and had different demographics than the popular nights. There were fewer young people at the theatre, and more middle-aged couples.  There were also two guys sitting at a table near the self-checkout machines trying to survey people about Con Edison– a deterrent to using the machines if I’ve ever seen one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/observation/movie1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;These dudes were persistent.&quot; alt=&quot;observation/movie1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, despite these factors, I still believe that theatre goers in Canada would behave differently. First of all, although both American and Canadian chains let you buy tickets in advance, many more Canadians use the feature to print the ticket at the theatre– so much so that Canadian theatres have standalone pickup-only kiosks. Nobody here, as far as I could tell, printed tickets to pickup. If they bought in advance, I assume they printed it out or had them on their phones, as they went straight up the escalators. Additionally, Canadians are much more likely to use the self-service machines entirely– many people (perhaps around 50-60%) from my observations forgo the machines to use the box office. Canadians would use self-service sometimes even if there was no line. Finally, a few of the people I observed engaged in behaviour i rarely saw in Canada– they went to the theatre without having a movie in mind. Before approaching the machine, they stared at the ticker of screenings overhead, and discussed what movie they might want to see. This behaviour seems to be less and less common over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who used the machines seemed experienced with using them. There was no particular demographic that indicated whether one would use the machine or not– young and old, female and male, and couples and singles both used the box office and ticketing machines in equal quantities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines in its usage were entirely similar to Canadian ticketing kiosks, on the other hand. The starting screen gives you four options: purchase a ticket for today, purchase one for the future, access your rewards account, and pickup tickets that were purchased in advance. Everyone who I observed over 20 minutes picked the first option, which then took them to a screen to select a movie, and then a time, and then the number of tickets. You would then optionally select concessions to purchase (which nobody opted for, similar to Canadians. Nobody wants to buy food without seeing it in front of them, particularly since it’s not discounted for buying here.) and finally, pay for their tickets. Overall, each of these transactions took 30 seconds to one minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/observation/movie2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;observation/movie2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, besides the aforementioned differences from Canada (box office vs ticketing machine, picking a movie in advance vs picking it at the theatre, picking up tickets vs printing them out at home) most people did not deviate from the process detailed above. During this process, payment seemed to take the longest– this makes sense, as the machines only take credit and debit cards and therefore require a connection to outside banking services. Beyond this, from the user standpoint, what took the longest was sometimes finding the button in the initial screen– users would be aided if the option to buy tickets today was more prominent, as it is unlikely that a user would pick a different option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest parts seem to be locating their movie and skipping concession movies. The former is easy because it’s visual and sorted– you’re likely to recognize the movie poster, and you can figure out where it fits in alphabetical order. The latter is easy because the skip purchase button is located in the same place as the button to confirm your number of tickets in the previous screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of these machines seem to be easy, though, only because the process is simple and the users seem to have used them before. They don’t do particularly well when judged by Crawford’s definition of interactivity, as they don’t give very much feedback for your actions and don’t seem to “think” about your choices. If you select something incorrectly, you don’t get confirmation until the end. The self-serve kiosks were also set apart from the box office line (most of the time in Canada, the kiosks are in the same space as the box office line) so they don’t do well by Norman’s principles of signifiers–people would go into the box office line because cultural signifiers indicate that the line is the way to purchase a ticket, and not the isolated area adjacent to it (with the kiosks.) The icons of the main screen are also fairly nonsensical, and I wouldn’t be able to distinguish purchasing a ticket and picking one up without the labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;addendum-1&quot;&gt;Addendum 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was at the movie theatre, a dude taught me how to sneak into the movie theatre by bypassing some technology. You get someone who paid for a ticket to call the elevator from upstairs, and sneak into the elevator as it’s going up. He was also hitting on me– and everyone knows that a man who refuses to pay for a movie ticket is very alluring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;addendum-2&quot;&gt;Addendum 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also read the introduction and first chapter of &lt;em&gt;Disability and Design&lt;/em&gt;. This was fascinating, and gave me a lot to think about. It reminded me of a few pieces of design for disability that I’ve seen recently: for instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/metal-gear-solid-prosthetics-arm-amputee-james-young-hi-tech-synthetic-limb-a6887071.html&quot;&gt;Metal Gear Solid prosthetic that a UK man received earlier in the year&lt;/a&gt;. It’s always seemed absurd to me how much design for disability is meant to conceal and blend in, especially when contrasted with the futures we imagine in science fiction in which robots and cyborgs are celebrated and artistic. I imagine a future with 3D printing more readily available to the public in which people could print bespoke versions of the prosthetics they want. Everybody is different, and we shouldn’t assume they all want to hide their disability– but if you do, you should be able to have that option as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp" /><summary>I had a bit of trouble deciding on what piece of interactive technology to observe for this blog post. We had to pick one used by the public, but try not to be seen observing them. Pick one that you can wait around near without being conspicuous. Pick one that you could hopefully take pictures of without seeming like you’re casing the store or establishment. This last criterion was the hardest. It ruled out most stores’ checkout machines, Amazon lockers, and other kiosks.</summary></entry><entry><title>Typefaces</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Typefaces" /><published>2016-09-24T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces/">&lt;p&gt;For visual language, I had to pick six typefaces to represent me. Here are my picks, along with a short explanation of why I chose them.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces01.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces01.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces02.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces02.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces03.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces03.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces04.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces04.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces05.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces05.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces06.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces06.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are all the picks together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces07.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces07.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had to make some “expressive” words. I decided that I wanted my set of three to be visual consistent and part of the same theme. I briefly considered continuing this set of tech with scanners and routers, but I’m pretty lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/wordart.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/wordart.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>For visual language, I had to pick six typefaces to represent me. Here are my picks, along with a short explanation of why I chose them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Switches</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switches" /><published>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches/">&lt;p&gt;I think most people in PComp this week was confused as to what we were supposed to document. There are a few labs assigned, but some of those are just looking at your electronic components. Do we respond to the readings? Tom Igoe’s class, apparently, has to do this. I chose to document the switch lab, since that one was fun.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Here’s a video of that first one. It’s very short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cm7eB3OsBgI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are shots of two other parts of the switch lab.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I have a video of the last part, because it was the most complicated part of the lab. I am clearly excellent at elucidating my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0X5cKt8o8dg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did a creative switch, or an attempt at it– I wired my book to turn the LED on when it was opened or closed. I had grand designs for using graphite to do a switch drawing, but I forgot my graphite sticks at home and had to steal lead from Koji. I’m sorry Koji. The drawing wasn’t enough drawn to conduct electricity. On Wednesday, I tried with the graphite sticks, but the payoff of graphite on the page still didn’t conduct electricity. The lead stick in itself conducted pretty well.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-a_-eWLjP-4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The readings were very lengthy this week, and honestly kind of confusing. I had to google “affect don norman” to figure out exactly what Don Norman meant when he referred to “affect”, because he never defined it in his piece about it. In my understanding, he contrasts cognition with affect: cognition is conscious thought and interpretation of the world, whereas affect is unconscious judgement of the world. I’m not sure if this is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I felt a bit of shame with his precise definition of affordance, since I used that word in my last pcomp blog post in the sense used by graphic designers that he derides. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>I think most people in PComp this week was confused as to what we were supposed to document. There are a few labs assigned, but some of those are just looking at your electronic components. Do we respond to the readings? Tom Igoe’s class, apparently, has to do this. I chose to document the switch lab, since that one was fun.

Here’s a video of that first one. It’s very short.

And here are shots of two other parts of the switch lab.


I have a video of the last part, because it was the most complicated part of the lab. I am clearly excellent at elucidating my thoughts.

I also did a creative switch, or an attempt at it– I wired my book to turn the LED on when it was opened or closed. I had grand designs for using graphite to do a switch drawing, but I forgot my graphite sticks at home and had to steal lead from Koji. I’m sorry Koji. The drawing wasn’t enough drawn to conduct electricity. On Wednesday, I tried with the graphite sticks, but the payoff of graphite on the page still didn’t conduct electricity. The lead stick in itself conducted pretty well.



The readings were very lengthy this week, and honestly kind of confusing. I had to google “affect don norman” to figure out exactly what Don Norman meant when he referred to “affect”, because he never defined it in his piece about it. In my understanding, he contrasts cognition with affect: cognition is conscious thought and interpretation of the world, whereas affect is unconscious judgement of the world. I’m not sure if this is correct.</summary></entry></feed>
