<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-04T15:28:12-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Money Transfers</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Money Transfers" /><published>2017-04-04T00:02:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:02:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/moneytransfers/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;problem-statement&quot;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of being unbanked affects 2 billion people in the world, the impact of which is that they have no access to credit, insurance, savings, and payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compelling-stories&quot;&gt;Compelling Stories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the following links about un/underbanked American families– I hope that my teammates find sources on non-American sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdic.gov/householdsurvey/&quot;&gt;7% of American families are unbanked and 20% are underbanked, according to the FDIC. 57.4% of unbanked respondants say that one reason for being unbanked is that they do not have enough money to keep in an account. Other reasons given include privacy, not trusting the banks, and account fees being too high or unpredictable.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/b/?node=14583169011&amp;amp;sa-no-redirect=1&quot;&gt;Amazon, recognizing that being unable to access credit/debit cards to use their service is a problem, is starting a new service to convert Cash to Amazon currency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/01/business/as-pay-cards-replace-paychecks-bank-fees-hurt-workers.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;Many American companies are now using payroll cards to pay their employees, and if they do not have a bank account, they must pay fees to withdraw their money.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fletcher.tufts.edu/InclusionInc/Programming/Research/Cost-of-Cash&quot;&gt;It costs American households $40B a year total for using cash, mostly because of the time to go get cash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-diagrams&quot;&gt;System Diagrams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/stakeholders.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/stakeholders.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/whiteboard.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/whiteboard.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_transfers/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_transfers/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>Problem Statement</summary></entry><entry><title>Personality Finders</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/mbtifinder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Personality Finders" /><published>2017-04-04T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/mbtifinder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/04/04/mbtifinder/">&lt;p&gt;It’s always weird using other people’s computers, especially when they look so similar to your own. Whenever I have to help anybody with programming, or look up something on their Macbook, it’s always bewildering: will they scroll in the same direction as I do? Did they set up hot corners? Are their desktops and docks messes, with programs littered throughout them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s made me think that the way people keep their computers may be reflective of their personalities in some way. I anal-retentatively keep my desktop and folders emptied and organized. My dock only has three items on it at any given time. So for this week’s EROFT assignment, to divine based on some ‘natural’ digital event, I decided to read a person’s personality based on how they’ve kept their Downloads folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/futurefinder1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;futurefinder1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I wanted to divine a person’s future, MASH-style. It’s one of my favourite childhood interpretations of -omancy, but after I implemented it, it didn’t feel quite right. I decided that the key element of MASH was actually the interpersonal connection, making the lists of homes with your friends, listing out people you know to marry. Consequentially, I backed off of MASH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/futurefinder2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;futurefinder2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then iterated around various facets of personality, but settled on determining a person’s MBTI type from a folder you can give it. I’m not a big fan of MBTI– I think that it’s largely been discounted by personality psychologists, and that the Big 5 types are more intuitive and less changeable. Additionally, most people don’t take the official MBTI test, so the results that they get are quite suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequentially, my extremely inaccurate type test is probably as accurate as the typical MBTI test that someone would take online. It’s entirely based on the number of files in the given folder: if someone has many folders, maybe they’re more extroverted. If they have more images, they’re more sensing than intuitive. If they have a lot of files, perhaps they’re more thinking than feeling. If their oldest file is quite old, maybe they’re more judging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sorted.forEach( function(v) {
  var fileType = v.name.split('.').pop();
  if (fileType == 'png' || fileType == 'jpg' || fileType == 'jpeg' || fileType == 'gif' || fileType == 'bmp' || fileType == 'tiff')
    numImages++;
  if (v.name.split('.').length == 1)
    numFolders++;
  numFiles++;
});

var intro = (numFolders / numFiles) &amp;lt; 0.2;
var sensing = (numImages / numFiles) &amp;gt; 0.4;
var thinking = numFiles &amp;gt; 200;
var judging = Math.abs(new Date() - new Date(sorted[0].lastModified)) &amp;gt; 7 * 24 * 60 * 60 * 1000;
var type = intro ? &quot;I&quot; : &quot;E&quot;;
type += sensing ? &quot;S&quot; : &quot;N&quot;;
type += thinking ? &quot;T&quot; : &quot;F&quot;;
type += judging ? &quot;J&quot; : &quot;P&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, quite clearly, all nonsense. But isn’t it all nonsense anyways?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mbtifinder/&quot;&gt;Click here for the finished product !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="personality tests" /><category term="mbti" /><summary>It’s always weird using other people’s computers, especially when they look so similar to your own. Whenever I have to help anybody with programming, or look up something on their Macbook, it’s always bewildering: will they scroll in the same direction as I do? Did they set up hot corners? Are their desktops and docks messes, with programs littered throughout them?</summary></entry><entry><title>Finance Research</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/29/finance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finance Research" /><published>2017-03-29T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-29T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/29/finance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/29/finance/">&lt;p&gt;Scratch the previous post– for my Doing Good final, I was put into a group to research a project on finance. Having long been a Bitcoin skeptic (the price going up does little to convince me) and unsure of what innovations one should try ahead of more data from GiveDirectly, I still gave researching the topic a great deal of effort. Still, though, listening to hours of podcasts and reading many articles did little to inspire me on the subject. When we convened our meeting on Monday, my group had very little direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many suggestions were made. I suggested encouraging the death of the dowry, but that was turned down as it’s more a cultural issue than financial. Shivanku wanted refugees to be able to access their money from their home countries, but I rejected this– from all my readings on refugees from Syria and Yemen and other similar crises, these refugees either already have means of cash transfer or don’t have any money to transfer. Ariana wondered how to integrate banking more into a person’s usual routine, or perhaps how to educate westerners on poverty in the third world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jaycee arrived later, we coalesced into two factions: Shivanku and Ariana wanted to research cash transfers, whereas Jaycee and I would look at financial education. This would be a closer topic to my menstruation. RIP. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the big problem? Two billion people in the world are unbanked.
2) What’s a focus of that? We can look at the specific issue of financial education– people who are unbanked may not know why that is a problem.
3) What’s some fanciful future tech that could be applied? We can use gamification and SMS to teach bite sized lessons on financial literacy.
4) 3-5 research links:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncfeindia.org/financial-education/loan-borrowing&quot;&gt;http://www.ncfeindia.org/financial-education/loan-borrowing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.centerforfinancialinclusion.org/fi2020/roadmap-to-inclusion/innovations-in-financial-capability&quot;&gt;http://www.centerforfinancialinclusion.org/fi2020/roadmap-to-inclusion/innovations-in-financial-capability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://indiatoday.intoday.in/money/story/survey-finds-76percent-of-indian-adults-lack-basic-financial-literacy/1/547634.html&quot;&gt;http://indiatoday.intoday.in/money/story/survey-finds-76percent-of-indian-adults-lack-basic-financial-literacy/1/547634.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdic.gov/consumers/consumer/moneysmart/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.fdic.gov/consumers/consumer/moneysmart/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/Financial-Literacy-on-the-web.pdf&quot;&gt;http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/Financial-Literacy-on-the-web.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="finance" /><summary>Scratch the previous post– for my Doing Good final, I was put into a group to research a project on finance. Having long been a Bitcoin skeptic (the price going up does little to convince me) and unsure of what innovations one should try ahead of more data from GiveDirectly, I still gave researching the topic a great deal of effort. Still, though, listening to hours of podcasts and reading many articles did little to inspire me on the subject. When we convened our meeting on Monday, my group had very little direction.</summary></entry><entry><title>Marvelous Fortunes</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/28/marvelous/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marvelous Fortunes" /><published>2017-03-28T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-28T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/28/marvelous</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/28/marvelous/">&lt;p&gt;In our last class for Electronic Rituals, I read Tarot for the very first time– and discovered that it’s an activity that I very much enjoy. Interpreting the cards and figuring out how it might be relevant to a friend’s life was challenging and interesting. My only problem with the reading was that I was so new to the practice: discerning the meaning of a card took a long time, as I had to crosscheck each card online to figure out the symbolism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus my primary motivation with the assignment was to create a set of fortunetelling cards that I could intuitively read– a set of cards whose mythology I already knew. I’m also not religious and didn’t grow up with religion, so I didn’t seem to have very many options on that front. After giving it some more thought, though, I realized that there was a modern mythology that I knew very well: that of Marvel Comics. I’m a huge comic book geek, so if I picked up a “Deadpool” card to intuit the past, I’d instantly know what that meant. It’s also something fairly well known: most people have seen the Avengers, so it’s an easy way to collectively tell a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_cards/tarot.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_cards/tarot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a set of cards primarily using the watercolour art of Kevin Wada, a watercolour covers artist who mostly works for Marvel and Image. I emailed him asking for permission, which is something he’d likely have replied to before he became a big-name cover artist. Consequentially, I don’t have his express permission, so I won’t include the PDF or high resolution versions of the cards– if you’d like a set, you’ll have to create your own. Or you can get a reading from me in person!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then determined a spread for the cards, the concept of which is that each card will be placed according to which villain they will fight, and each villain corresponds to a reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Skull&lt;/em&gt; : your past&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ultron&lt;/em&gt; : your challenge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Goblin&lt;/em&gt; : what is hidden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Galactus&lt;/em&gt; : your environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Doom&lt;/em&gt; : your advice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; : a possible outcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did readings for five people– two of those readings are included below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_cards/reading1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_cards/reading1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan’s reading was my first, and a bit rougher than the others– he had to help me out quite a bit. Bucky represents a fractured identity, two paths one can go on. Phoenix is rebirth, obviously. Psylocke represents spirituality and a challenge of cultural identity: she was born in a British body, but was put into a Japanese woman’s body. Nick Fury represents working against a bureaucratic environment. Namor advises that you lead with confidence, and that you should not be afraid to seem arrogant. Rogue means you will learn from your peers, absorbing knowledge from many different sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/eroft_cards/reading2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;eroft_cards/reading2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marco’s reading was very different. His past is seen in the Punisher, which seems to mean there may have been a traumatic event– he should be careful that this doesn’t preoccupy him. His challenge is Falcon: he might be anxious that he is untalented, but he should be reassured that everyone else is as lost as him. His inner strength is what makes him special. Hidden forces is Ms. Marvel, who gains her strength not just from her powers, but also her family and friends. Thor is his environment: he should be wary of traditions, and not feel pressured to live up to others’ expectations. Nightcrawler is advice: do not be afraid to leave a situation you’re uncomfortable with, or say no to them. And finally, an outcome: with Captain America, justice can be attained.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="marvel" /><category term="kevin wada" /><summary>In our last class for Electronic Rituals, I read Tarot for the very first time– and discovered that it’s an activity that I very much enjoy. Interpreting the cards and figuring out how it might be relevant to a friend’s life was challenging and interesting. My only problem with the reading was that I was so new to the practice: discerning the meaning of a card took a long time, as I had to crosscheck each card online to figure out the symbolism.</summary></entry><entry><title>Foosball</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/26/foosball/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foosball" /><published>2017-03-26T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-26T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/26/foosball</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/26/foosball/">&lt;p&gt;This week in Subtraction, we’re making foosball players on the wood lathe. Supposedly, we’re going to play an actual game with our players, but hopefully I will not play. I’m terrible and don’t particularly like the game– in terms of tabletop fictional sports, I prefer air hockey. (So Canadian of me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/positions.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/positions.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be position 12 on these fictional teams. Go fighting Blues!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/firewood.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/firewood.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saved my firewood from last week to use this week, a decision I was glad for when I saw my classmates scramble to glue plywood together. My firewood is very soft, but it seemed a solid decision when a few of their glued pieces fell apart on the lathe. I also had enough material to spare half of my wood for a jig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/jig.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/jig.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, Nate and I worked together to produce this little jig. I took down the wood, but I got distracted and let the scraper go flying when Swapna walked into the shop. She made me take a break and took down more of it– accidentally rounding the part we wanted for the jig. Woops! Thank you, Swapna, though– it was very kind of her to force me off the lathe. I guess I was more shaken than I thought I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned many things in making the jig, including how to use the 4 jaw chuck and how to get the headstock pinned. There was a lot more mental math than I’d like this week– I think everyone had trouble trying to figure out how to get 90/180 degrees when they’re divided by 5!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/jigresult.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/jigresult.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the jig, along with the taken down firewood for my actual piece. Since the jig was narrower than expected, we put the other hole 90 degrees from the one visible here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/signuplist.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/signuplist.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the day I thought I’d finish off the assignment, but so did everyone else! Since you can’t book timeslots for the lathe, I made a little signup sheet– to the consternation of everyone on the list after #6… Sorry guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/ideas.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/ideas.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I waited for my turn, I came up with ideas of how to make my foosball player unique. Since I didn’t want my team to lose, I stayed away from the ideas that seemed unstable, and settled on the chess piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/finished.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/finished.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I actually turned, I thought I might do a knight instead of the Queen that I drew. To make a Queen’s crown seemed like a lot of whittling that I didn’t want to do. Here’s the piece after sanding on the lathe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/foosball.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/foosball.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as I added details on the helmet, I kinda got disatisfied and sanded the whole thing down to a flat top. It’s now a castle! I tested the thing out on the actual foosball table (hanging out with the goalie here) and it looks pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/misaligned.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/misaligned.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I discovered that, though the hole goes straight through, it’s slightly misaligned from the other side. Here you can see where the hole should be through my misaligned hole. Fortunately, this gave me a reason to finally use my deburring tool– if I tried to just drill it, the bits slip to where the hole already exists. The deburring tool let me take off just the bottom left corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_foosball/final.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_foosball/final.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a little more drilling and deburring, it fits! Now I can let Monday come with no worries– my piece will fit into spot #12.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="turning" /><category term="lathe" /><summary>This week in Subtraction, we’re making foosball players on the wood lathe. Supposedly, we’re going to play an actual game with our players, but hopefully I will not play. I’m terrible and don’t particularly like the game– in terms of tabletop fictional sports, I prefer air hockey. (So Canadian of me!)</summary></entry><entry><title>Bleeding Out of Her Wherever</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/22/periods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bleeding Out of Her Wherever" /><published>2017-03-22T04:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-22T04:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/22/periods</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/22/periods/">&lt;p&gt;Periods are a big problem. It’s facile, but that’s the conclusion I drew after a break in which I did a lot of readings on the subject. I knew that I wanted to work on a project that affected both where we live and more developing countries, and I knew that periods caused big problems for girls around the world– some girls will not go to school when it happens, and it’s incredibly hard for many to purchase and access menstruation products. That’s not to mention anyone with PCOS and other debilitating symptoms!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some readings from UNICEF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org/wash/schools/files/WASH_in_Schools_Empowers_Girls_Education_Proceedings_of_Virtual_MHM_conference.pdf&quot;&gt;Proceedings of the Menstrual Hygiene Management in Schools Virtual Conference 2012&lt;/a&gt; (This one is great!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org/wash/schools/files/MHM_study_report_Burkina_Faso_and_Niger_English_Final.pdf&quot;&gt;case study of menstrual hygiene - Unicef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unesdoc.unesco.org/images/0022/002267/226792e.pdf&quot;&gt;Puberty education &amp;amp; menstrual hygiene - Unesco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some articles that might be illuminating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Fears and concerns related to menstruation: a qualitative study from the perspective of gender]&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scielo.br/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;amp;pid=S0104-07072015000100013&quot;&gt;http://www.scielo.br/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;amp;pid=S0104-07072015000100013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Menstruation 101 For Boys: A Comic Book Is Their Guide]&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2017/03/04/516628738/menstruation-101-for-boys-a-comic-book-is-their-guide&quot;&gt;http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2017/03/04/516628738/menstruation-101-for-boys-a-comic-book-is-their-guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/611774/period-pain-can-be-as-bad-as-a-heart-attack-so-why-arent-we-researching-how-to-treat-it/&quot;&gt;Period pain can be “almost as bad as a heart attack.” Why aren’t we researching how to treat it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2015/08/10/london-marathoner-period/&quot;&gt;A woman ran the London Marathon without a tampon to protest period-shaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26260978&quot;&gt;The Indian sanitary pad revolutionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On homeless periods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.com/news/gta/2017/01/23/periods-an-extra-hardship-for-homeless-women.html&quot;&gt;Periods an extra hardship for homeless women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bustle.com/articles/190092-this-is-how-homeless-women-cope-with-their-periods&quot;&gt;This Is How Homeless Women Cope With Their Periods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soapboxie.com/social-issues/Homeless-Periods-Suck&quot;&gt;Homeless Periods: A Problem of Poverty, Dignity, and Feminine Hygiene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took a look at Whisper and Tumblr to see how actual teens and younger women talk about their periods, and it wasn’t actually too different from how people my age talk about it. There was certainly more embarrassment involved, but a lot of it was complaints about cramps, just like any woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy for me to endlessly research, but coming up with a project concept was significantly tougher. There are three main avenues that I can approach this problem from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education. Although puberty and Menstrual Hygiene Management (MHM) is taught in most schools around the world, many women do not get taught about menstruation until after they get their first periods. How do we educate younger girls about this? How do we educate boys to be sensitive about this? And how do we correct misconceptions, or handle any other questions (like PCOS) that might not be addressed in their formal education?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to MHM and hygiene. In many countries, pads are incredibly expensive and are not accessible to many girls and women. Additionally, it may be difficult to wash yourself of any stains and accidents, as well as get new clothes and underwear. Fresh water is not always accessible, and many places do not have bathrooms. Even in the US, it is difficult for poorer women and the homeless to get pads and tampons– you might have to choose between eating and MHM. How can we help the most vulnerable get access and feel clean and safe?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to the above in emergency situations. If what I described wasn’t bad enough, imagine dealing with these things during a civil war or a natural disaster. How can you learn about periods if you live in a refugee camp? How can we keep hygiene a priority when you do not have clean water to access?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s​ difficult, but after giving it a lot of thought, I think it all cycles back to education. If we don’t educate people on the importance of MHM, then we will never create the circumstances in which access for all will be created, and in which MHM is given thought during emergency situations. It’s particularly important that we both keep in mind cultural sensitivities, and also educate all genders about the subject: many girls don’t go to school during their periods because they face ridicule from the boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will take a three pronged approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advertising and educating the general public. It’s very taboo in most cultures to discuss periods, so it’s important that the discussion is brought to the open and the more general public. Periods are not a dirty word, and it shouldn’t be a secret that men don’t understand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Private chat to answer particular questions about periods that might not be addressed in the usual education system. It’s an extremely popular misconception around the world that using tampons would mean you are no longer a virgin. Asking a male teacher about this, or even a female one, would be incredibly awkward. Mothers and friends might tell you the wrong information. We need a trusted resource that is accessible and respectful of girls’ questions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RapidSMS/UReport to identify information impoverished areas to correct MSM misconceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/unicef_final/bom.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;unicef_final/bom.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/unicef_final/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;unicef_final/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a revolutionary approach, and may not be a “provocation” per se, but I think a devoted resource to the topic worldwide would be incredibly powerful. It’s also within the scope of accomplishment– no fantasy pad making devices or laws are needed. It can be done in partnership with governments and corporations. It’s within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(System diagram is forthcoming! Apologies.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="menstruation" /><category term="periods" /><summary>Periods are a big problem. It’s facile, but that’s the conclusion I drew after a break in which I did a lot of readings on the subject. I knew that I wanted to work on a project that affected both where we live and more developing countries, and I knew that periods caused big problems for girls around the world– some girls will not go to school when it happens, and it’s incredibly hard for many to purchase and access menstruation products. That’s not to mention anyone with PCOS and other debilitating symptoms!</summary></entry><entry><title>Airport Rebellion</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Airport Rebellion" /><published>2017-03-21T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-21T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel/">&lt;p&gt;Although many forms of rebellion are the antithesis of ritual, others are directly codified by it. The idea, by Max Gluckman, a South African anthropologist, is that ritualized rebellion serves as a release for impulses that threaten institutions, by which they ultimately reinforce them. For instance, during Carnival, you can drink and revel to a point that would normally be frowned upon, and you could return to the normal Catholic social order afterwards. In a much more fantastical way, the film series, “The Purge” is built around the same idea: you take one day to commit as many crimes as you want, but only that day; in this way, crime the rest of the year is abated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself performing a small ritual of technological rebellion over Spring Break. I’m not sure if this act serves to maintain social order in any way, but it does make me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many security experts, including Bruce Schneider who coined the term, view the airport and airline security apparatus as “security theatre”: a show of supposedly improved security that does not actually achieve it. It makes people feel safer without actually preventing much terrorism, and also wastes a lot of time. All the time I spend putting my toiletries in small containers are a waste. Taking my shoes off is uncomfortable, and the shoe bomb only happened the one time, unsuccessfully. The long lineups and scans and invasions of privacy do little except to annoy me and other passengers. They make me want to rebel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I do, in a very small, inconsequential way. On every airplane, you are told that electronic signals from your phone can interfere with the airplane’s control systems. I am not sure if they actually do. Consequentially, here is my small ritual:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mobile phone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;airplane (you are sitting in)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cabin crew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/airplaneritual.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;airplaneritual.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cabin crew will tell you to switch your phone to airplane mode for takeoffs and landings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to use your phone during takeoffs and landings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are spotted by a crew member, pretend to switch to airplane mode and put your phone away. Do not switch to airplane mode.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take your phone back out. You may continue to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I really need to use my phone during takeoffs and landings? Absolutely not, and the data signal becomes so weak that it’s pointless to keep it on– it honestly just serves to drain my phone’s battery faster. But do I continue to do this as a form of small rebellion against the air travel apparatus? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not believe that this affects anybody else, and especially not the airplane’s control systems. It mostly pacifies me in a system that leaves me feeling powerless, in line after goddamn line. I took four flights over the break, since I had two layovers. I endured scans several times and patdowns. It feels nice to say “no” in a small way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky enough to be a cisgendered woman of the “model” minority, so I’m hardly ever selected for a random search. Whenever my belongings set something off in airport security, I only experience minor panic and am let through with little trouble. Perhaps if I was of a different race or have other circumstances, I’d be less inclined to perform this small ritual. But as it is, it’s a little rebellion to help me endure an arduous process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="security theatre" /><category term="rebellion" /><summary>Although many forms of rebellion are the antithesis of ritual, others are directly codified by it. The idea, by Max Gluckman, a South African anthropologist, is that ritualized rebellion serves as a release for impulses that threaten institutions, by which they ultimately reinforce them. For instance, during Carnival, you can drink and revel to a point that would normally be frowned upon, and you could return to the normal Catholic social order afterwards. In a much more fantastical way, the film series, “The Purge” is built around the same idea: you take one day to commit as many crimes as you want, but only that day; in this way, crime the rest of the year is abated.</summary></entry><entry><title>Turning</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turning" /><published>2017-03-10T04:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T04:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning/">&lt;p&gt;Spring Break has arrived, along with a snowstorm in New York. Knowing that I’ll be leaving for London tomorrow, I wanted to finish my lathe exercise before my trip– lest I be stuck competing with everyone else to finish in the last weekend before class begins again. I had no idea what to make with it, though, and thought hard before concluding that I’d just turn until I felt content with my work. I didn’t see much point in making a handle if I had nothing to which I’d attach it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to turn a simple wooden dowel, and save my piece of firewood for when I felt more confident with the lathe. In all honesty, I hadn’t realized we’d be given material, and hoarded this earlier in the week. After we got material, I decided to use it anyways. Putting it on the lathe was exceedingly simple, and almost suspiciously so. I kept feeling like I was missing a step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started turning the piece, I discovered that I had accidentally put it on at an angle. Woops. I had to take the piece a bit down so it’d be a consistent cylinder, and then just lathed as I saw fit. It was surprisingly soothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanding on the lathe is a bit of a pleasure, but it can be hard to sand down little grooves perfectly. I sanded down my randomly turned dowel, and then rubbed boiled linseed oil on it. My brother advocated it, as it is cheaper than tung oil and dries faster. (I didn’t apply enough for a professional finish, though, since this is just an exercise.) I thought I should listen to a man who literally did his Masters’ thesis on wood finishes (albeit on outdoor deck finishes. I imagine he has reasonable expertise about other finishes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick coat of BLO, I sanded it down and tried to get the rough edges out of the grooves again. This could be a stair baluster, theoretically.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="turning" /><category term="lathe" /><summary>Spring Break has arrived, along with a snowstorm in New York. Knowing that I’ll be leaving for London tomorrow, I wanted to finish my lathe exercise before my trip– lest I be stuck competing with everyone else to finish in the last weekend before class begins again. I had no idea what to make with it, though, and thought hard before concluding that I’d just turn until I felt content with my work. I didn’t see much point in making a handle if I had nothing to which I’d attach it.</summary></entry><entry><title>Satellites</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Satellites" /><published>2017-03-04T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking at landsat data for Everything is Spatial, and it’s fascinating. I wish it had more zoomed-in data so I can look at building and cities more closely, but it’s interesting to look at larger bodies and seeing how things change. It’s nice to be able to access direct satellite data with exact times– one thing that frustrates me about Google is its copyright data that notes everything as Copyright 2017 Google. Who knows when this data is from, consequentially?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some map data from BC. Our slogan is Beautiful British Columbia, and it’s lovely covered in snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/bc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tracked the development of Rio de Janeiro since 2013– I thought it’d be interesting to see how it has changed for the Olympics. A lot of development happened, as you might imagine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2013.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2013.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2014.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2014.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2015.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2015.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2016.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2016.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2017.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2017.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, in gif form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/rio.gif&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/rio.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most striking change is likely the construction of the Arco Metropolitano highway, which was done through 2014, and its later integration into the landscape. You can also see how buildings start to develop the places at the edges, though the city itself isn’t all that changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(All these photos weren’t taken at the same time of year– I was prioritizing clearness of cloud cover over preserving the same timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my final, I was originally thinking of doing a political idea (I considered things like tracking and mapping the prices of menstrual products around the world, similar to the Big Mac Index), but occasionally you need a break from activist topics. Consequentially, I considered sillier things: stuff like mapping copycat buildings and landmarks (China famously copies landmarks from around the world) and comparing them to the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the topic I think I’ve settled on is simpler, and inspired by the place where I’m from. Vancouver is the third most common filming location in North America for many films and TV shows, but hardly ever stars as itself. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ojm74VGsZBU&quot;&gt;great video about this topic by Tony Zhou&lt;/a&gt;. It stars as Seattle, New York, and countless other metropolises. This has got me thinking about all the towns that have pretended to be New York in film besides my city. Toronto is a very common New York stand-in, for instance, starring as the city for American Psycho. So for my final, I think I’ll map all the places that’ve been New York, and let the user explore the movies with false New Yorks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neue New Yorks. Or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>I’ve been looking at landsat data for Everything is Spatial, and it’s fascinating. I wish it had more zoomed-in data so I can look at building and cities more closely, but it’s interesting to look at larger bodies and seeing how things change. It’s nice to be able to access direct satellite data with exact times– one thing that frustrates me about Google is its copyright data that notes everything as Copyright 2017 Google. Who knows when this data is from, consequentially?</summary></entry><entry><title>IDNYC &amp;amp; Final Project Ideas</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IDNYC &amp; Final Project Ideas" /><published>2017-03-04T04:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T04:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid/">&lt;p&gt;Our midterm for doing good is good business was a research project on the IDNYC. It all started with the following prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_nycid/prompt.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_nycid/prompt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I developed a list of questions about the program to ask Benedetta and also determine the answers to. At first, it was unclear whether we were supposed to research other ID programs for the last question or not, but it was clarified that the project centered around the IDNYC, and that at least one of us should go apply for the ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played with the document calculator online and decided that Michael would apply for the card– he had already been planning to, and he had the pamphlets to prove it. Our first meeting was rather unfruitful– we had thought we could just walk-in and get an appointment, but apparently you had to book one in advance online or by calling 311.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_nycid/nyc_id.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_nycid/nyc_id.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first appointment after this was also unsuccessful– we didn’t read the document calculator correctly and didn’t realize his residency documents needed to be dated within the last 60 days. The second appointment was successful, but Michael moved recently so it was a mixed success– he wouldn’t receive his ID at his new address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also created a slide deck to introduce the IDNYC and go through a few personas and the troubles they might face in getting the ID. The slide deck is included below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13V7estj1a3sCrULcK4a-uh9htX3gM72g29RJKGVNQFs/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=10000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics that are particularly interesting to me usually focus on women and girls and also apply to populations in richer countries. Things that are of particular interest to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do we ensure homeless and poorer populations have access to menstrual health products? Could we support small business at the same time? How do we educate young girls about menstrual health across cultures where it may be taboo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do we protect homeless and poorer women from the threat of sexual assault, and encourage them to report cases of assault?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;similarly to my first query, how do we ensure that babies have access to clean diapers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how can we help people have privacy and a good night’s sleep in extremely close quarters? Does everyone have access to an effective mosquito net?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the challenge, how can ensure access to identification cards and other documents? How can we ensure these cards are portable and preservable in harsh conditions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think right now my favourite of these questions is the one about menstrual health, and I need to do more research on the topic. I think it’s a prime area for technology to assist in– although girls have access to their peers and teachers, they would want privacy and sensitivity that these groups might lack (many teachers are male, after all.) And homeless women might have difficulty asking for these products. Additionally, how are these products disposed of? Can we get clean underwear and sanitary products for everybody?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do more research. Hopefully, someone else might be interested in the topic– it’s often a topic men shy away from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="nycid" /><summary>Our midterm for doing good is good business was a research project on the IDNYC. It all started with the following prompt:</summary></entry></feed>
