<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-07T23:15:13-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Do No Evil</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do No Evil" /><published>2017-02-07T06:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T06:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop/">&lt;p&gt;Last week for Doing Good is Good Business, we did a design workshop to practice solving problems– we paired up to solve each other’s problems with communicating with distant loved ones. I paired with Dorothy, who had trouble reaching a friend of hers in Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of trouble thinking of creative ideas in that short amount of time– these aren’t very radical ideas at all. Practice makes perfect though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I settled on a design concept of collaboratively drawing from far away, since I got the sense from Dorothy that she and her friend were both artists. It was also inspired by a few different ‘couple apps’ I’ve seen, which let you see where your partner has touched on screen. While doing that, why not make art?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorothy also came up with an amazing prototype to solve my problem of figuring out when is best to call my mom– which reminds me, I should go do that right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>Last week for Doing Good is Good Business, we did a design workshop to practice solving problems– we paired up to solve each other’s problems with communicating with distant loved ones. I paired with Dorothy, who had trouble reaching a friend of hers in Dubai.</summary></entry><entry><title>Do No Evil</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do No Evil" /><published>2017-02-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil/">&lt;p&gt;In UNICEF’s guidelines for innovation, #8 is a particular favourite of mine: “do no harm.” It harkens back to Google’s old motto to “don’t be evil”, but Google has since changed their slogan since, and it feels like the rest of the tech world has as well. UNICEF’s version even goes a step farther than google: whereas evil is ambiguous and up for interpretation, harm can be measured. To do no harm is a difficult goal and requires a lot of forethought and consideration of ethics, which are ideas explored by this week’s speakers and within the required reading for &lt;em&gt;Doing Good is Good Business&lt;/em&gt;. How do we use data to do good and not do harm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fairness, Donald Trump supporters would not characterize Cambridge Analytica as doing any harm, but if “The Data That Turned the World Upside Down” is completely factual, their work is easily described as harmful. Although this, and many other articles I’ve read on the subject, act as though the use of Big 5 and personality psychology was Cambridge Analytica’s chief innovation, from my reading, it’s not too different from what Barack Obama’s team innovated in 2008 and 2012. The true difference is the use of targeted advertising and segmentation for voter suppression: discouraging potential Hillary Clinton supporters from voting. This is certainly harmful, and certainly not what Michal Kosinski intended with his data collection and analysis– let alone what Mark Zuckerburg and other technologists intended with the web applications they created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, personalized newsfeed and recommender systems were created with the best of intentions. You wouldn’t want to waste your time with things you weren’t interested in. But to be fed a diet of only things you’re interested in can be harmful to your soul, and harmful to your understanding of the world. I’m not always very sympathetic to conservatives– I don’t think there are always two sides to every story, and the so-called “other side” should not be part of the conversation sometimes (for instance, I do not believe creationism has a place in science classes.) But keeping Palestinian and Israeli networks completely separated seems to be doing tangible harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a prime example of the blindness of the tech industry, there is no discussion of ethics within “Social Media Fingerprints of Unemployment”. Is it truly ethical to use social media data to determine economic statistics? One might argue that it isn’t too different from data collected in traditional ways– such as censuses or unemployment surveys. But there is no obvious connection in social media to unemployment, and people who use social media do not explicitly consent to their posts being used in this way. If we do use big data for these purposes, would it affect the accuracy of the data once this information collecting is fully disclosed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some questions I might have for our panel discussion next class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can websites and applications do more to inform their users of the information being collected on them and how it’s being used?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How common is the practice of buying and selling data amongst companies? Or amongst companies and non-profits?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is done to compensate for underrepresentation amongst minority in Big Data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>In UNICEF’s guidelines for innovation, #8 is a particular favourite of mine: “do no harm.” It harkens back to Google’s old motto to “don’t be evil”, but Google has since changed their slogan since, and it feels like the rest of the tech world has as well. UNICEF’s version even goes a step farther than google: whereas evil is ambiguous and up for interpretation, harm can be measured. To do no harm is a difficult goal and requires a lot of forethought and consideration of ethics, which are ideas explored by this week’s speakers and within the required reading for Doing Good is Good Business. How do we use data to do good and not do harm?</summary></entry><entry><title>Othermill</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Othermill" /><published>2017-02-06T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-06T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill/">&lt;p&gt;I had a great deal of trouble with this week’s assignment, to the point that the thing isn’t finished. If I can manage the energy, I might finish it later, but for now I think I’ve tried hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/mountains.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/mountains.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I wanted to mill. It’s an abstract representation of the north shore mountains– the mountains that tower over Vancouver. A little piece of home! I had trouble with picking something to mill, as I only had a 1/8” bit, and a lot of my original ideas needed finer milling. This was good enough, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took great care to load the bit and stick my block onto the machine the first time around. Later attempts, which I had to do, I took less care, and the block came off the base a few times. I think this is because I didn’t give it time to cure, but later, when I left the block on the board a little longer, I had no troubles with it coming off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rDGBYxkI3kE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I had trouble with this machine when I started to run the job. Whenever I tried, it seemed to stop and restart itself. I hypothesized it was a power issue, so I switched the power supply with that of another machine, but when I did this, the machine would constantly beep and did not spin the bit. I ended up giving up and trying a different machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to an Othermill Pro, it worked very well, but was a long job (nearly an hour!) and loud as hell. I had by this point already attempted three attempts on the other machine, and then with the Pro, it took me two tries before the glue set properly. Since I had spent so much time already listening to the machine mill extremely loudly, and since I was the only one milling, I rearranged the sound dampeners to suit my needs. I made a fort, in other words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 40 minutes into this job and after a few vacuums, even the Othermill Pro decided it could have no more and restarted in the middle of a cut. I suspect it overheated from the lengthy job. At this point, I had been at this for hours, and it was nearly midnight, so I decided to leave the job as it was and clean up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/03.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the final result, but I might take it back and finally cut the thing out. The engravings are rather fine– I just need to cut the damn thing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/04.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason the right triangle is cut off was because I kept using the same piece of wood and didn’t align it perfectly with each attempt– I could’ve restarted, but I had grown attached to the dumb thing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="othermill" /><category term="milling" /><summary>I had a great deal of trouble with this week’s assignment, to the point that the thing isn’t finished. If I can manage the energy, I might finish it later, but for now I think I’ve tried hard enough.</summary></entry><entry><title>I Hate The Uses of Enchantment</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/linkedin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Hate The Uses of Enchantment" /><published>2017-02-05T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/linkedin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/linkedin/">&lt;p&gt;There’s no mincing words about it: I hated this week’s readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century. I didn’t like Bettelheim very much last week, but my hatred clicked together this week: The Uses of Enchantment revealed itself to be Freudian nonsense, following the worst impulses of the psychiatric industry. Bruno Bettelheim is a midcentury Freudian, the sort that gets psychiatry made fun in popular culture. As Freud himself would say, sometimes a cigar is just a cigar, but midcentury Freudians like Bettelheim would overanalyze that dumb cigar long after Freud left it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I thought I didn’t like Bettelheim because of his Eurocentric worldview and his overgeneralizations (ironically, he has the gall to chide other adults for not listening to children, but he seems to listen to children only as far as to prove a theory.) I didn’t realize how much more there was to dislike about this man! The reading made me so mad that I did extracurricular research on why Bettelheim is horrible. As an aside, I’ll note it here: Bettelheim lied about his credentials, never earning that PhD he claimed to have. He is a hypocrite and abusive, railing against corporal punishment while physically and verbally abusing his patients and his students. Also, significantly for this reading, he did not respect autistic people and believed autism was caused by neglectful mothers.  In Enchantment, he uses the phrase “normal child” with great frequency. Knowing his background, you realize he means non-autistic when he says this, and often for no reason– there isn’t a reason to distinguish autistic children in his analysis, and he is just doing so out of lack of compassion and respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, I’d accept any other psychoanalytical reading about fairy tales: Freud himself? Fine. Lacan? Great. Klein? I’d love it. But Freudians are the goddamn worst. Freud himself has a lot to like, as he’s important from a critical standpoint and many of his ideas are important (such as the development of childhood.) But his followers are awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the crimes that Bettelheim does in the selected reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He makes a point about illustrations hampering understanding and claims many studies prove this, but he admits to not having an actual study to prove his point and only cites studies that claim illustrations hamper language learning. That’s totally different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He frequently refers to the Oedipal desires of having a child with your parents, which is not at all true. Furthermore, many feminist scholars believe that Freud’s theory was based on the sexual abuse of his patients by their fathers, so to believe this uncritically is gross.
Also Freud never referred to wanting to have a child with your mom. That’s just Freudian extrapolation. He did say the sex thing, though, curiously omitted by Bettelheim.
Attachment theory is fine and good, though. Just none of this literal child with your parent stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He tramautizes a class of children by point out that they were making a model, then uses this to prove that children should not be taught science.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He claims adults who are never read fairy tales are stunted, which is absurd.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He discounts the entire possibility that sometimes a story might be enjoyed as a story and nothing more. Freud would not be pleased.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s tons of gender essentialism, but that goes with the territory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Id, ego, and superego are good metaphors but should not be taken as literal fact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He makes ridiculous assertions like 12 year olds believe that rivers are literally alive. That might be true of a few, but not the majority of 12 year olds I know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surely there must be a better resource on psychology and fairy tales than Bettelheim. Perhaps there is a Lacanian take somewhere that wouldn’t drive me crazy? Freud is important, but midcentury Freudians should be lost like the cult it is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><summary>There’s no mincing words about it: I hated this week’s readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century. I didn’t like Bettelheim very much last week, but my hatred clicked together this week: The Uses of Enchantment revealed itself to be Freudian nonsense, following the worst impulses of the psychiatric industry. Bruno Bettelheim is a midcentury Freudian, the sort that gets psychiatry made fun in popular culture. As Freud himself would say, sometimes a cigar is just a cigar, but midcentury Freudians like Bettelheim would overanalyze that dumb cigar long after Freud left it alone.</summary></entry><entry><title>Cassandra on LinkedIn</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/bettelheim/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cassandra on LinkedIn" /><published>2017-02-05T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/bettelheim</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/05/bettelheim/">&lt;p&gt;We had to develop our characters this week, and I didn’t feel like building 3D models felt right for my reinterpretation. Instead, I built these fake LinkedIn profiles: one for Cassandra, one for Apollo, and one for the boss who doesn’t listen to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_linkedin/cassandra.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_linkedin/cassandra.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_linkedin/apollo.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_linkedin/apollo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_linkedin/boss.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_linkedin/boss.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><category term="cassandra" /><category term="greek mythology" /><category term="the fall of troy" /><summary>We had to develop our characters this week, and I didn’t feel like building 3D models felt right for my reinterpretation. Instead, I built these fake LinkedIn profiles: one for Cassandra, one for Apollo, and one for the boss who doesn’t listen to her.</summary></entry><entry><title>Router</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/30/router/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Router" /><published>2017-01-30T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-30T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/30/router</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/30/router/">&lt;p&gt;On the first day of Subtraction class, I was asked if I was afraid of using power tools. I was taken a bit aback; it hadn’t occured to me that I’d be afraid, and I would describe my feelings more like a deep-seated anxiety than fear. I wasn’t afraid I’d cut off my hand or injure myself, but I knew that my projects would likely go wrong– and my exercise did go wrong. Now that I’ve messed up, I do feel fine. It was the anticipation more than anything. Now I just feel that I’ve learned a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step was straightforward– finding materials. I knew I didn’t want to spend any money, so I just salvaged some 0.5” plywood from the garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then measured out where I’ll stick in the pin, with a weird twist. The ruler I used had apparently been imprecise, the product of another itper on the laser cutter. My original measurements became this unhappy face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then loaded the circle jig and the router bit onto the router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, in high school shop class, I had used a drill press before, so using it wasn’t as intimidating as the other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/03.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad, imprecise face is still sad, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, it was time to actually use the router. I had a little trouble securing the plywood, as I didn’t realize I would want flat screws. The trickiest part, unexpectedly, was adjusting the depth of the head. It took a little finesse sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/04.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/05.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the circular cut was done! It was a little imprecise, but I was too content with my work to think to fix it. In future projects I will know better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/06.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/06.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came time to measure out the straight edge of the cut. Because I had been imprecise earlier, I changed my mind about where I needed to cut. It’s less certain whether the piece would come out if I had followed my original plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/07.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/08.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/08.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting this was very straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/09.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/09.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the piece is now done, despite the imperfections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_router/10.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_router/10.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Lindsey Daniels, Chetan, and Shir for their help and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="router" /><summary>On the first day of Subtraction class, I was asked if I was afraid of using power tools. I was taken a bit aback; it hadn’t occured to me that I’d be afraid, and I would describe my feelings more like a deep-seated anxiety than fear. I wasn’t afraid I’d cut off my hand or injure myself, but I knew that my projects would likely go wrong– and my exercise did go wrong. Now that I’ve messed up, I do feel fine. It was the anticipation more than anything. Now I just feel that I’ve learned a lot.</summary></entry><entry><title>The Dissemination of Fairy Tales</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dissemination of Fairy Tales" /><published>2017-01-29T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-29T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular/">&lt;p&gt;Why are fairy tales popular? In the selected readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century this week, Bettelheim and Zipes take three different approaches to answer this question. Bettelheim answers the question from a psychological perspective, and Zipes looks at the history of their dissemination as well as why fairy tales are still relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not a fan of these readings, however. They were extremely Eurocentric and never addressed this. Out of necessity, the history portion could not include the whole world, but when discussing tales like the Native American fable, &lt;em&gt;The Turkey Girl&lt;/em&gt;, this should be noted. Why do non-western variations on Cinderella get published, when they are often a minor and local folktale in the cultures they supposedly represent? Why don’t we learn about the folktales that are actually popular and important to their cultural identity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the readings did not address the modern mass media’s role in spreading fairy tales, or fairy tale-like stories. Because of Disney movies and their associated merchandising, many people interpret Mulan as a fairy tale, but she was a living historical figure and the fantastical elements of the movie were merely tacked on. Is it disrespectful to group such a story with the other Disney princesses, who often lack agency and character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Disney continues to reinterpret and adapt stories from different cultures, these questions will continue to be on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><summary>Why are fairy tales popular? In the selected readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century this week, Bettelheim and Zipes take three different approaches to answer this question. Bettelheim answers the question from a psychological perspective, and Zipes looks at the history of their dissemination as well as why fairy tales are still relevant today.</summary></entry><entry><title>Cassandra, A Modern Myth</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cassandra, A Modern Myth" /><published>2017-01-29T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-29T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra/">&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, there was a woman named Cassandra. She worked for a multinational oil company– you know their name but for legal purposes, it cannot be included in this story– and reached a fairly high position in the company. She had worked very hard to get this job, and was very proud of the fact. She was also very beautiful, and many people whispered that she had gotten her job because of it. She was not very proud of this fact. She disliked her natural beauty, as it distracted people from her intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, her coworker– who we will call Apollo, but for legal purposes, his real name must be omitted– revealed to her some secrets of the company. They were very dangerous secrets, and Cassandra was appalled. Many people would die because of these secrets. Apollo then expected Cassandra to sleep with him in exchange for these secrets. Cassandra was appalled. She refused, and Apollo cursed her and skulked away. Everyone believed she had slept with him though, as she was very beautiful and that is just what beautiful women do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra decided to go to her boss with the secrets, but he laughed at her and came onto her. She refused him, as she usually does, as it was a habit of his to harass her. This time, though, she reported her boss and Apollo to their company’s HR department. They did nothing with her report. She was very beautiful, so what did she expect? Men were going to try to seduce her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra then tried to report the company’s abhorrent secrets to the government, but even they would not believe her. She seemed like such an airhead, and the secrets didn’t seem possible. Besides, the government had a very good relationship with the oil company, and who would want to ruin that to investigate what were likely lies from some bimbo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra tried then to go to the press with the secrets, but even though the newspaper was sympathetic, they did not have the budget to handle the legal case against a big, multinational company. The secrets were probably not true anyways. But they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole process wore Cassandra down, and she eventually gave up on trying to expose her company. She could not stand staying at the company, however, and was fired after snapping at her boss during another bout of sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years later, the company’s secrer deeds were revealed by a man. There was a lot of outrage, and a lot of deaths were caused by the company. A few people were fired, but they received large severance checks and left to join another multinational firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra never worked again in the oil industry. They say that her name was put on a list. Unlike that of Cassandra, however, the stories of the other names on that list will likely never be heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The End&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><category term="cassandra" /><category term="greek mythology" /><category term="the fall of troy" /><summary>Once upon a time, there was a woman named Cassandra. She worked for a multinational oil company– you know their name but for legal purposes, it cannot be included in this story– and reached a fairly high position in the company. She had worked very hard to get this job, and was very proud of the fact. She was also very beautiful, and many people whispered that she had gotten her job because of it. She was not very proud of this fact. She disliked her natural beauty, as it distracted people from her intelligence.</summary></entry><entry><title>Cinderella, Enchanted</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cinderella, Enchanted" /><published>2017-01-28T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-28T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella/">&lt;p&gt;There are a great number of versions of Cinderella. Some are retellings of the story for a modern audience; some are similar stories from different cultures rebranded as a multicultural version of Cinderella. The version I’ll be focusing on is &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt; by Gail Carson Levine, a young adult novel that I had loved in my youth. I read a lot of young adult fiction about princesses, but this was a particular favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt; is recognizably a fairy tale, its status as a variation on Cinderella is relatively obscured. Most of the Cinderella plot– her father’s remarriage, the ball, and the prince’s search for Ella all occur in the back half of the novel. Instead, the inciting action of the novel is a curse placed on Ella at her birth: a fairy gave her the gift of obedience, and she consequentially cannot disobey any order given to her. She attempts to find the fairy to take this curse back, and encounters and gets to know Prince Charming while she is on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes give Ella more character and make it more of a feminist text than the original fairy tale: giving Ella this curse rationalizes why she acts as servant to her stepmother and stepsisters, as she has no choice but to follow their orders. She is no longer meek and docile, no longer leaving her fate to chance– when she does, it’s because she hasn’t a choice. Meeting Prince Charming and falling in love with him throughout the novel erases a problem many feminists have with fairy tales. Prince Charming does not fall in love merely because Ella is beautiful, but because of her funny and headstrong character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other changes do erase some of the hallmarks of the Cinderella story. To explain why a fairy would come to bless Ella– and to explain why she would encounter the prince in her everyday life– Ella’s family is turned to nobility, instead of that of a mere merchant. Because Ella has already gotten to know the prince, the motif of the glass slipper is minimized, but the prince does have to search for Ella as she has gone into hiding after their dance. Much of the remaining motifs do remain in tact, however; for instance, Ella has a fairy godmother who enchants household objects to bring her to the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the novel that does not concern the core Cinderella story develops Ella’s character, bringing her to boarding school and giving her friends and allies. It also has themes not contained within the original fairy tale– free will and choice, obviously, are ruminated on much more than in Cinderella, and class issues are explored beyond how nice it must be to marry a prince. The primary lesson of Cinderella is still preserved in &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt;, however– live your life morally and with grace, and you will be rewarded for it ultimately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><category term="cinderella" /><category term="ella enchanted" /><summary>There are a great number of versions of Cinderella. Some are retellings of the story for a modern audience; some are similar stories from different cultures rebranded as a multicultural version of Cinderella. The version I’ll be focusing on is Ella Enchanted by Gail Carson Levine, a young adult novel that I had loved in my youth. I read a lot of young adult fiction about princesses, but this was a particular favourite.</summary></entry><entry><title>Everything is Spatial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything is Spatial" /><published>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/">&lt;p&gt;It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned two readings: an intro to web maps and a comparison between Apple and Google Maps. As I read the comparison, I was struck by one difference between the two maps: Google prioritized transit, but Apple prioritized landmarks. This was interesting to me because a friend of mine, Jaycee, prefers Apple maps, and she happened to depend less on transit than me. I have an Android phone, so Apple maps is not an option for me, but even if it were, I doubt I would consequentially choose Apple. With IOS, Jaycee can choose from either of the two, but transit is likely less of a priority. It’s fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also assigned a little exercise we did in class, to use leaflet.js to create a quick map and apply different map tiles to it. I chose Stamen’s watercolor style, and also added a bunch of restaurants that I like to eat at near ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;map&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;

var layer = L.tileLayer('http://tile.stamen.com/watercolor/{z}/{x}/{y}.png', &quot;terrain&quot;, {
  attribution: 'Map tiles by &lt;a href=&quot;http://stamen.com&quot;&gt;Stamen Design&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0&quot;&gt;CC BY 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. Data by &lt;a href=&quot;http://openstreetmap.org&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright&quot;&gt;ODbL&lt;/a&gt;.'
}); 


  var map = L.map('map', {
    scrollWheelZoom: false,
    center: [40.7295, -73.9938],
    zoom: 15
  });

  map.addLayer(layer);
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.9938]).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('ITP', { permanent: true });


  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7350, -73.9930], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('La Maison du Croque Monsieur');
  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7309, -73.9903], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Ippudo');
  L.marker([40.7296, -73.9896], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Korilla');
  L.marker([40.7263, -73.9957], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('The Press Shop');
  L.marker([40.7311, -73.9933], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Maoz');
  L.marker([40.7334, -73.9879], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Trader Joe\'s');
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.999026], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Go Go Curry');
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.</summary></entry></feed>
