<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-27T15:30:27-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Everything is Spatial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything is Spatial" /><published>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/">&lt;p&gt;It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned two readings: an intro to web maps and a comparison between Apple and Google Maps. As I read the comparison, I was struck by one difference between the two maps: Google prioritized transit, but Apple prioritized landmarks. This was interesting to me because a friend of mine, Jaycee, prefers Apple maps, and she happened to depend less on transit than me. I have an Android phone, so Apple maps is not an option for me, but even if it were, I doubt I would consequentially choose Apple. With IOS, Jaycee can choose from either of the two, but transit is likely less of a priority. It’s fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also assigned a little exercise we did in class, to use leaflet.js to create a quick map and apply different map tiles to it. I chose Stamen’s watercolor style, and also added a bunch of restaurants that I like to eat at near ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;map&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;

var layer = L.tileLayer('http://tile.stamen.com/watercolor/{z}/{x}/{y}.png', &quot;terrain&quot;, {
  attribution: 'Map tiles by &lt;a href=&quot;http://stamen.com&quot;&gt;Stamen Design&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0&quot;&gt;CC BY 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. Data by &lt;a href=&quot;http://openstreetmap.org&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright&quot;&gt;ODbL&lt;/a&gt;.'
}); 


  var map = L.map('map', {
    scrollWheelZoom: false,
    center: [40.7295, -73.9938],
    zoom: 15
  });

  map.addLayer(layer);
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.9938]).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('ITP', { permanent: true });


  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7350, -73.9930], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('La Maison du Croque Monsieur');
  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7309, -73.9903], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Ippudo');
  L.marker([40.7296, -73.9896], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Korilla');
  L.marker([40.7263, -73.9957], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('The Press Shop');
  L.marker([40.7311, -73.9933], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Maoz');
  L.marker([40.7334, -73.9879], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Trader Joe\'s');
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.999026], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Go Go Curry');
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.</summary></entry><entry><title>Putting Out Fires</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Putting Out Fires" /><published>2016-12-14T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-14T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires/">&lt;p&gt;There are some people at ITP who make beautiful, artistically fulfilling projects, and write deep and introspective blog posts to match. Their blog posts are gossiped about on the floor, “they make me want to cry. She’ll get a job through these.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not one of those people. I prefer candid and ugly posts. This will be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the blocks of words. I failed to take many photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is working, and will be presented today for Physical Computing. It is not nearly in the state I would like it to be, but it is interactive and interesting for people. It fulfills people’s fantasies, even if it doesn’t fulfill my vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many setbacks in the course of its creation. Last week, we did another round of playtesting during class. I didn’t get my hat functional in time for the class– after fabricating the hat per my previous blog post, I wired it closely to the fritzing diagram in my previous blog posts, with the concession that I didn’t buy complex wire connectors and used a small breadboard instead. After doing so, I discovered a number of problems that prevented me from a working prototype. Consequentially, the playtesting was less helpful than it should’ve been– a mishmash of advice I’d heard last time and suggestions I wouldn’t have time to implement (with a few exceptions.) I did enjoy playtesting for other people though, and I hope I gave them helpful feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people react with incredulity at how many problems I’ve encountered in a deliberately simple project– no serial communication is used whatsoever. But I had to put out many fires related to each of my electrical components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;accelerometer&quot;&gt;Accelerometer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the chief problem that prevented me from playtesting, but I’ve gotten it to a good state now. The problem with the MPU6050 I bought was that it only worked reliably when it could read very often, but I only wanted intermittent reads. It consequentially would overflow its FIFO readings or occasionally trap itself in an infinite loop. If an overflow occurred, the stored values of pitch and yaw were never updated, and then no longer valid previous readings would be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I solved this by making my read function return a boolean, and asking for a reading until the boolean was true and the values were updated. Consequentially, the common FIFO overflows would be less debilitating. I also made infinite while loops time out, so the program would never be stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the flow of the system going is very important, and I also added timeouts to responses in general, with a random assignment. Since the system doesn’t tell you the answer it recorded nor what houses it corresponds to, it seemed unlikely that anybody would care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accelerometer, despite consistently overflowing, is now one of the more reliable parts of the hat– to my great surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mp3-shield&quot;&gt;MP3 Shield&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the Adafruit MP3 Shield had a lot of problems, despite initially looking like a solid solution. Some of it was user error– at one point, I snapped off a capacitor on it and had to scramble to find someone to solder it back on for me– I couldn’t trust myself to do so with my shaky hands. But some of that was the product. When trying to get the capacitor back on, I discovered the paucity of serious documentation for Adafruit products. Where is there a data sheet on it? How do I find a replacement capacitor, if necessary, if I can’t find any information on what capacitor it is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bulk of my problems, though, were audio out related. ITP is usually very loud, so my previous estimations on speakers needed were too optimistic. The mp3 shield either outputs to speaker pins or a regular headphone jack. The speaker pins had a woefully low maximum wattage, so they couldn’t announce a house loudly like I had hoped. I thought I could wire up two sets of speakers– one for private questions near the ear and one in the mouth for announcements. The MP3 shield has a function to control volume per ear, but no function to switch between the headphone jack and speaker pins. I tried to use right and left as different sets of speakers, but that turned out staticky and sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think two sets of audio outs is a pipe dream if I want to keep the hat lightweight. Right now, I’ve decided to use the headphone jack and connect to speakers with an external power source. It’s the best solution I have for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;servos&quot;&gt;Servos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the hat’s mouth move was always a stretch goal, and not one I terribly addressed this week. I did have to adjust some expectations, though– running everything with two servos meant a serious power draw. I had to settle for one planned servo motor, if I get around to it. It’s one of the most frequently requested features, so I hope I do get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-forward&quot;&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hat is currently far from finished, and there are a few things I will work on over the weekend. I’d like to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the hat with fabric. Hide the carrboard! A lot of people complained about it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consider privacy and broadcasting questions and answers. Wire speakers accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try to make the mouth move!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print stickers for takeaways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>There are some people at ITP who make beautiful, artistically fulfilling projects, and write deep and introspective blog posts to match. Their blog posts are gossiped about on the floor, “they make me want to cry. She’ll get a job through these.”</summary></entry><entry><title>Printing and Procrastination</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Printing and Procrastination" /><published>2016-12-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination/">&lt;p&gt;One way I like to procrastinate is by doing other work– no matter how trivial or unimportant it is– and pretending that doing this work is productive. This is what I’ve done for my Physical Computing Final. Instead of fabricating the hat or trying out the wiring, I decided to design the sticker takeaways for it and make brochures to help people who aren’t familiar with Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/stickers.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/stickers.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/brochure.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/brochure.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I probably should’ve spent more time wiring or fabricating because I faced a great deal of challenges later on. None of my components seem to work properly, and I’m having headaches figuring it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/size1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/size1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/size.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/size.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, including the libraries bloat my code to a great degree, so I spent time optimizing my code and making it run in less than 100% of the Uno’s memory space. I could use a Mega, but that’s money to consider. I know I can optimize, so why not? You can see the code on the github: https://github.com/metermaid/sortinghat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/speakers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/speakers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then had problems getting the speakers to work with my mp3 shield. I might have to use the headphone jack for the playtest, since that works. I tried speakers from the shop to ensure– it’s not just my speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had a huge headache working with the accelerometer I bought. I first implemented it as is, but the data was noisy. I then implemented a Kalman filter, which didn’t work very well. Finally, I used the Arduino library by Jeff Rowling, which worked, but consistently had FIFO overflow errors. I can adjust the sizes of the buffer in the library, but this seems like a fundamental problem that isn’t my perogative. I am considering going back to the Kalman filter, or trying out an Arduino 101. I just would rather not spend the money…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And gosh, I didn’t even attempt the servos this time around. What state will I be in next week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/hat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/hat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, I fabricated another paper hat. He’s very witchy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>One way I like to procrastinate is by doing other work– no matter how trivial or unimportant it is– and pretending that doing this work is productive. This is what I’ve done for my Physical Computing Final. Instead of fabricating the hat or trying out the wiring, I decided to design the sticker takeaways for it and make brochures to help people who aren’t familiar with Harry Potter.</summary></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Progress</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving Progress" /><published>2016-11-26T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-26T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last ten days or so visiting my brother in Alabama; consequentially, I’ve been both more and less productive than i expected. More so because there isn’t much to do here, particularly if you don’t have a car; less, because the only materials I have are whatever I brought with me. You can’t wire up a component you don’t have, and my accelerometer didn’t arrive at ITP before my flight to Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I left ITP, though, I managed to solder my MP3 shield. It was the first time I’d ever soldered anything– to the best of my knowledge, my brother said we soldered in eighth grade shop class. I made some mistakes, but it’s not so scary to me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/soldering.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/soldering.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote pseudocode and then Arduino code for the sorting hat. I don’t know if any of this will work at all, though, because I hadn’t been able to wire anything up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;void loop
  if button pressed
    start questioning
  end
end
void questioning
  play preamble
  scramble questions
  start variables
  
  for each question
    play question
    while no_response
      if longenoughtime
        play canthearyou
      end
    end
    if response == nod
      variables++
    else response == shake
     variables++
    end
    if endstate
      break
    else
         playnoise(random)
    end
   play houseName(variables)
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/metermaid/sortinghat&quot;&gt;Arduino code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; which is a practice I need to get back into– I weirdly don’t associate pcomp projects with “real” code that warrants version control. This is an attitude I need to mend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lieu of actual wiring, I created a fritzing sketch of my board. I’m not sure if I like fritzing– it’s somewhat helpful to see a visual representation of how to wire, but it’s much easier to represent most things with schematics. From here on out, I may just do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/fritzing.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/fritzing.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I updated my timeline with estimates of what I’ve completed. Earlier I had assumed I was done with recording lines, but now I think I need to record a few more. It’s hard to come up with questions for that hat, though. I’m also likely overestimating how finished I am with the coding, but I’m gonna let myself have my optimism before my flight back to New York and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>I’ve spent the last ten days or so visiting my brother in Alabama; consequentially, I’ve been both more and less productive than i expected. More so because there isn’t much to do here, particularly if you don’t have a car; less, because the only materials I have are whatever I brought with me. You can’t wire up a component you don’t have, and my accelerometer didn’t arrive at ITP before my flight to Birmingham.</summary></entry><entry><title>Playtest and Planning</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playtest and Planning" /><published>2016-11-13T14:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T14:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans/">&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, we did some play tests of prototypes for our Physical Computing final. I didn’t think I would learn that much, but play tests will often surprise you. I constructed a prototype by wetfolding some Trader Joe’s paper bags– it looked rather good in my opinion. I also made myself a hat; as the McGonagall of my demo I should be similarly outfitted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/hats.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/hats.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a script out, and recorded some lines with Nate. There were around 15 questions to ask, and preamble to go with them as well. I then created a JavaScript soundboard for my questions– it’s a hi-tech lo-fi prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/questions.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/questions.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-play-test&quot;&gt;The Play test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some questions in mind going into the play test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this take too long? Was there too many questions?
Do you know to just put it on? Do you find nodding and shaking your head intuitive?
Are you mad if you get a result you don’t agree with?
Did you want to talk about yourself in a freeform manner?
Would you enjoy watching other people get sorted? Would you get bored if they have the same questions?
Do you want your house announced to the world, like the books and movies, or should it be a private experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions and more were answered by my helpful play testers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/jennyhat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/jennyhat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how cute this is! The playtesters are cute and smart as well, providing me with some helpful feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/feedback.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/feedback.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the play test I learned the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contrary to my assumptions, people really enjoyed answering yes or no questions about themselves and didnt find it tedious. In fact, most people felt they could’ve answered more than the seven or so questions I gave them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nodding and head shaking were intuitive, for the most part– one person shook their head in an unexpected way. Since the hat will be supervised the whole time, I can probably just monitor and correct people who do it wrong, but I should be cognizant of this and adjust the accelerator as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speech recognition would be nice, but holy cow– it gets loud when the room is full of people talking. My tiny phone speaker had to be held up to ears just to be heard. Speech recognition for the Arduino is consequentially unfeasible, and, since people liked the nodding, not necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also, my original concept that the hat would accept freeform responses would be scrapped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of people don’t know Harry Potter, or have forgotten the houses (the remaining people remember, and are very opinionated about them!) I should put up flags or posters to remind people of the idea, and perhaps integrate it into the hat. Maybe the hat could the song from the books, but that might take a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People wanted to watch others get sorted, but didn’t want others to hear their questions and responses. They wanted some privacy. This takes care of my concerns about it being boring to watch repeated questions, but it might be boring to watch the silent questioning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They totally wanted the houses to be loudly announced. They also wanted cloaks. If I go all in on theatricality, they may forgive other flaws of the hat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;planning&quot;&gt;Planning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My description from the last blog post hardly needed updating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is a loving recreation of a magical object in the world of the Harry Potter series. In the books, the hat reads your mind to determine which of four school houses you have the most affinity for. In real life, we are unable to read minds, so the Sorting Hat asks you a series of questions and determines your house based on your responses. Physically, it is an anthropomorphic hat that beckons you to put it on. Once on your head, it will guide you through a series of yes or no questions to which you will respond with nods or head shakes. The hat will then decide your house, which it will announce loudly, and you can enjoy a sense of belonging and delight at this talking hat’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my timeline certainly needed some new information and simplification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created a system diagram of sorts– I’m calling it a hat-user story diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/sortingtime.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/sortingtime.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this information in mind, I created an initial bill of materials. It’s all a lot pricier than I had anticipated, and this is without the speaker / voice recognition that I had originally planned on. The servos I’ll probably be able to borrow for free, but maybe I should just have servos on hand. You’ll never know when they’ll come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/bom.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/bom.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>Last Thursday, we did some play tests of prototypes for our Physical Computing final. I didn’t think I would learn that much, but play tests will often surprise you. I constructed a prototype by wetfolding some Trader Joe’s paper bags– it looked rather good in my opinion. I also made myself a hat; as the McGonagall of my demo I should be similarly outfitted!</summary></entry><entry><title>Nicki and Harry</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicki and Harry" /><published>2016-11-13T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki/">&lt;p&gt;I love Nicki Minaj. I’ve been a fan of hers for a long time; longer than even her jaw-dropping feature in Kanye West’s “Monster”, which was mentioned in the Radiolab episode, “Straight Outta Chevy Chase”, which we listened to for Fandom this week. Consequently, I had the same reaction as her to Rosenberg’s comments that were cited in the podcast– who are you to question whether her tracks are hip hop enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a question that pairs nicely with last week’s discussion on Authenticity, and one loaded with implications about class, race and gender as well. Radiolab directed its questions mostly about race, but I felt that gender was insufficiently addressed– Minaj herself questioned that in particular, and Rosenberg’s comments were often gendered unfairly. Pop music is often assumed to be the domain of teenage girls, and in Rosenberg’s complaints about “Starships”, the teenage girl became code for a lack of savviness about hip-hop. His comment, “I know there’s some chicks here waiting to sing ‘Starships’ later, I’m not talking to y’all right now, fuck that bullshit.” is an example of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Minaj and Rosenberg are outsiders in hiphop– Minaj for her gender and Rosenberg for his race and class– and they both get questioned about this. Who are they to present themselves as authorities on the subject? Don’t fans know better than them? This may be an example of Fandom Gone Wrong, our next subject for class. Our other reading this week handles more clear cut examples of this for Harry Potter. “Consumer Tribes: Harry Potter and the Fandom Menace” discusses a great many topics, chiefly the myth making of Harry Potter and how fandom has affected the publications of these books. In truth, I thought it was the worst reading we’ve done all class; it’s poorly written and overly obsessed with puns. It does bring up several good points, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Harry Potter creation myth that it spread through word of mouth is false– there was a concentrated marketing campaign in schools. Secondly, J.K. Rowling encouraged a sort of anti-marketing and fans were able to band together under the banner of being looked down upon by the mass media. Thirdly, fans are fans of the fan object, and not necessarily the fan object owner, and can and have turned on Rowling at any time. They criticize her work– I have myself, with her creations of international magical schools– and encourage poor writing in an effort to get new books as fast as possible. Editors are less willing to edit books that they know will be bestsellers anyways. It’s also tough when, as a writer, you must focus on fan management as well as your core duties of writing. Managing a fan object is a tough job, especially when it opens yourself up to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>I love Nicki Minaj. I’ve been a fan of hers for a long time; longer than even her jaw-dropping feature in Kanye West’s “Monster”, which was mentioned in the Radiolab episode, “Straight Outta Chevy Chase”, which we listened to for Fandom this week. Consequently, I had the same reaction as her to Rosenberg’s comments that were cited in the podcast– who are you to question whether her tracks are hip hop enough?</summary></entry><entry><title>Final</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final" /><published>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/">&lt;p&gt;It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is a loving recreation of a magical object in the world of the Harry Potter series. In the books, the hat reads your mind to determine which of four school houses you have the most affinity for. In real life, we are unable to read minds, so the Sorting Hat asks you a series of questions and determines your house based on your responses. Physically, it is an anthropomorphic hat that beckons you to put it on. Once on your head, it will guide you through a series of yes or no questions to which you will respond with nods or words. The hat will then decide your house, which it will announce loudly, and you can enjoy a sense of belonging and delight at this talking hat’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/finaltimeline1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;finaltimeline1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.</summary></entry><entry><title>Real or Not Real?</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real or Not Real?" /><published>2016-11-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/07/real/">&lt;p&gt;At first, I wasn’t sure what the connection between the two readings we were assigned for Fandom this week was. “Buying In: The Pretty Good Problem” and “From Smart Fan to Backyard Wrestler: Performance, Context, and Aesthetic Violence (WWF)” seemed like very different subjects. Looking at the subject of next week’s class made it come together– we’ll be looking at Authenticity of Fandom. With Professional Wrestling, the fandom revolves around its inauthenticity, and authenticity differentiates companies with the Pretty Good Problem. In this way, the two readings complement each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be said that the wrestling fandom revolves around the authenticity of its inauthenticity. It’s comparable to reality TV in that it is widely perceived as fake and trashy with stupid fans, but that’s a facile line of thinking. All fans of reality TV and professional wrestling knows that it is fake and manipulated, with crafted storylines and personas. Playing along is part of the fun, and the most devoted fans regard themselves as smart and are cognizant of the ways the performances are manipulated. Smart fans may even seek out leaked results and still enjoy the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary focus of the article is about backyard and indie wrestling leagues, which authentically replicate the inauthenticity of professional wrestling. Like professional wrestling, they have storylines and characters, and tapes are recorded and sold. As leagues get bigger they may even pay for rings and promotion, and copy the inauthentic techniques of professionals, such as ‘blading’, intentionally cutting yourself to appear as if you’ve lost a lot of blood. These leagues, as well as professionals, focus on making a good show with as little pain as possible; they shy away from the extreme moves that might actually put them in danger. The priority is to put on a good show, but well within established standards of behaviour. It’s authentically inauthentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to this, the “Pretty Good Problem” reading concerns the inauthentically authentic. A good chunk of the reading is about Ecko, a brand embraced by the hip-hop world, but founded by a suburban white man whose closest ties to the street were viewing old graffitied subway cars in Trenton. Ecko grew into its hip-hop stature because its founder was able to recognize the potential market– he sold ads in black magazines and hired black tastemakers to promote the brand. It wasn’t authentic to begin with, but as people on the street started to buy it, it became authentic in some sense. Similarly, Ralph Lauren wasn’t born into the monied class, but selling to them made his brand an icon of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one part of the reading I wasn’t sure about in the end was the Hello Kitty portion. Hello Kitty is meaningless, so what does it have to do with authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>At first, I wasn’t sure what the connection between the two readings we were assigned for Fandom this week was. “Buying In: The Pretty Good Problem” and “From Smart Fan to Backyard Wrestler: Performance, Context, and Aesthetic Violence (WWF)” seemed like very different subjects. Looking at the subject of next week’s class made it come together– we’ll be looking at Authenticity of Fandom. With Professional Wrestling, the fandom revolves around its inauthenticity, and authenticity differentiates companies with the Pretty Good Problem. In this way, the two readings complement each other.</summary></entry><entry><title>Catching Up on Readings</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Catching Up on Readings" /><published>2016-11-06T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-06T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/06/catchup/">&lt;p&gt;I blog about every reading for Fandom, but over the last two weeks I’ve been too busy to blog about the previous readings. I’ll do so right now– we covered fan fiction with a reading, “Star Trek Reruns - Reread, Rewritten: Fan Writing as Textual Poaching” by Henry Jenkins, and then watched the TED Talk, “The Art of Asking” by Amanda Palmer. I was significantly more enthused for the former reading than the latter– I have pre-existing negative feelings about Palmer and this talk, and I’ve read other essays by Jenkins that I’ve enjoyed. Funnily, we read an essay by him for Big Games, but it had nothing to do with fandom– he’s just extremely prolific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Star Trek Reruns”, overall, reminded me of what Zoe dubbed the third-wave of fandom theory: that fandom is an extension of self, instead of the theories that fandom was utopia or recreated society. Overall, the essay was much more sympathetic to fandom than the first- or second-wave; it came as little surprise when Zoe later described Jenkins as one of the big names of third-wave fandom theory. I’m not sure about the “textual poaching” metaphor Jenkins uses however; it places fandom and its fan objects in too much opposition. Many fan objects encourage fan creation and “poaching”, but nobody would encourage people to poach from them non-metaphorically. Nowadays, though, “appropriation” also has baggage of its own, so there’s no perfect metaphor for what fandom does with its fan creations. Despite my objections, though, large swathes of the essay are still applicable today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, Jenkins rejects the idea that fans are “kooks” or “out-of-control”, stereotypes that are still employed by the mass media today. Think of any piece about bronies or female-oriented fandoms like Twilight. He also emphasizes that fans do things purely for fun– a refreshing change from overly analytical essays about fandom. Other things I appreciate about his essay are the ideas that fandom particularly appeals to the marginalized, as they can carve spaces for them to represent themselves; as I’ve written previously, fan fiction, for instance, is primarily written by women. The essay focuses on Star Trek, which is a fan object that is viewed by the media as the domain of male basement dwellers, but funnily, was kept going in part by the female fandom– TNG was started because of the fanbase’s longevity, which the female fanzines played a part in promoting. I’m not sure about Jenkins’ gendered analysis of media engagement, but overall the essay provides valuable insight into fan thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next week, we watched Amanda Palmer’s TED Talk, and I was already predisposed to dislike her so it was hard for me to watch. I primarily knew Palmer from her controversies: her ableist appropriation as Evelyn Evelyn (she pretends to be half of a pair of Siamese twins, essentially fetishizing the condition as weird and freak show-y); her poetry about the Boston Marathon Bomber, her use of unpaid musicians, and her blog posts decrying celebrity culture while simultaneously taking advantage of it. I really didn’t want to watch this TED Talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did watch it, it did not change my mind about Palmer. I still think of her as essentially unable to recognize her own privileges and acknowledge the criticisms of her; she makes a reference to the unpaid musician controversy in a way that seems unrepentant about it. It just strikes me all as extremely self-serving; we should allow fans to pay however they can for her music, including performing music for her. But this is an unequal trade that devalues their contribution; it equates them listening to her album with performance fees. I don’t terribly mind the idea of fans getting to perform with Palmer; it’s like paying to swim with dolphins. But when it’s labour performed for her, and she does’t understand why people would be upset by the idea, she just comes off as another rich lady pretending to be poor. The Simple Life for alternative folks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><category term="star trek" /><summary>I blog about every reading for Fandom, but over the last two weeks I’ve been too busy to blog about the previous readings. I’ll do so right now– we covered fan fiction with a reading, “Star Trek Reruns - Reread, Rewritten: Fan Writing as Textual Poaching” by Henry Jenkins, and then watched the TED Talk, “The Art of Asking” by Amanda Palmer. I was significantly more enthused for the former reading than the latter– I have pre-existing negative feelings about Palmer and this talk, and I’ve read other essays by Jenkins that I’ve enjoyed. Funnily, we read an essay by him for Big Games, but it had nothing to do with fandom– he’s just extremely prolific.</summary></entry><entry><title>Brainstorm</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brainstorm" /><published>2016-11-02T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/02/brainstorm/">&lt;p&gt;If you could invent anything, what would you invent? It’s an easy question when you’re a kid, but as you get older, it gets increasingly hard. You become less imaginative, and you add more constraints on yourself. It should follow the laws of physics. It should be possible given my skill sets. It should be reasonably cost effective. The list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I originally had trouble thinking of ideas for my final physical computing project. I decided to brainstorm through a number of different lenses– constraints can occasionally help sharpen and inspire ideas. I first thought of “what projects might come up if I am inspired by my other classes?” Visual language and applications did not inspire very much– a real life colour eyedropper would be neat– but big games and fandom were a little more fruitful. I thought of projects that might help women in particular, and looked at dream inventions of women online: most tech entrepreneurs are men, so I suspected this would be an underserved market. Finally, I considered projects that might be of use in my personal life, which is surprisingly in need of little. I’ll list my rejected ideas below, as well as my top three choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rejected-ideas&quot;&gt;Rejected Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;school-inspired&quot;&gt;School-Inspired&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a number of ideas inspired by Harry Potter, a fandom I was obsessed with in high school– magic lends itself well to physical computing projects. I considered making real life versions of a number of things: a pensieve, a memory collector that would work out similarly to Rebecca Liebermann’s memory project; living portraits, an apparently common idea according to Tom Igoe’s blog posts; an invisibility cloak, a camera-heavy project that would likely be extremely costly and not terribly original; or a Marauder’s map, which is essentially in all our pockets with our GPS-enabled phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other ideas inspired by fandom were to create holographic-like communication devices akin to Star Wars or to create the outfit selection tool used by Cher in Clueless. These seemed camera intense and not terribly feasible, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried to think of projects inspired by gaming and my class big games, which was not entirely fruitful. Big games inherently involve a lot of people, and it’s often easier to use low tech solutions or leverage existing technologies everyone has. I did consider making a storytelling game– tag a few objects, and see how the story changes as you switch the objects in the story. I also considered making a Fitbit like tracker that used rpg paradigms to motivate the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;female-inspired-projects&quot;&gt;Female-Inspired Projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t intentional, but all of the female oriented projects I came up with revolve around the beauty industry. I imagine that it’s easier to get funding for more practical female tech products– there are a lot of period tracking apps, for example. I considered creating a little nail polish printer, for those who are as incompetent at nail art as I am. I considered tools to help you style your hair; holding tools up for he back of your head automatically. I considered mirror and lighting tools, and makeup projection mapping. None of them seemed like a great fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;projects-for-my-life&quot;&gt;Projects for My Life&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I considered a few projects that I might need in my life. Perhaps there could be a sensor for stains, that would tell you exactly how you should clean it to get rid of the stain. There could be a product that read barcodes and sensed vegetables, that suggested recipes based on what ingredients you have. One could develop an all in one gardening kit– a device that detects the perfect water, light, and nutrient levels for your plant, for people who lack green thumbs like I do. One could develop a digital pill box for people like me who are extremely forgetful– it should notify you if you forget, and instruct you on what to do if you accidentally skip a day of pills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-three-choices&quot;&gt;Top Three Choices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;colour-scanners&quot;&gt;3. Colour scanners&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that Adafruit had colour sensors in their store, and the possibilities of this are intriguing. On a very basic level, one could create a real life eyedropper for Photoshop and similar tools– scan a colour, and use it in your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, one could use the colour for real life applications: one could mix together colours and create a pen to colour with or nail polish to go on your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;comeback-machine&quot;&gt;2. Comeback machine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an idea, honestly, stolen from a women’s message board, but is honestly gender unspecific. I could create a little box or robot that you could insult, and it should do its best to come up with a come back. You would need speech recognition, but I think I can use the one from IBM Watson. It’s incredibly silly, but sounds like a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;real-life-sorting-hat&quot;&gt;1. Real Life Sorting Hat&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an idea inspired by my fandom class– I had been writing a fan fiction for Harry Potter for that class, so the idea was at the top of my mind. With each new school announced, the first thing at the top of fans’ minds is which house they would be sorted in. People love to fit in, and this would be great fun for kids and the young at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we clearly can’t read minds, we could get the hat to ask the users questions to sort them. We can either use microphones or an accelerometer to answer yes or no questions with a nod or a head shake. Then the hat would use speakers to announce the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty simple project, but if the production values are high it can be fairly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>If you could invent anything, what would you invent? It’s an easy question when you’re a kid, but as you get older, it gets increasingly hard. You become less imaginative, and you add more constraints on yourself. It should follow the laws of physics. It should be possible given my skill sets. It should be reasonably cost effective. The list goes on.</summary></entry></feed>
