<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-01T19:49:06-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>My First Fanfiction</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Fanfiction" /><published>2016-11-01T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/01/fanfiction/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-daily-prophet-special-report-harry-potter-and-the-muggle-biography&quot;&gt;THE DAILY PROPHET SPECIAL REPORT: HARRY POTTER AND THE MUGGLE BIOGRAPHY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Katie Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to imagine now, but there was a time fairly recently when magic was kept secret from Muggles. Wizardry was thought by them to be the domain of liars and charlatans. This attitude rapidly changed, but it was not solely because of the groundbreaking and controversial repeal of the International Statute of Wizarding Secrecy in 2002. Rather, it was the publishing of the wildly popular biographical series about Harry Potter by Muggle historian, J.K. Rowling, that changed Muggle attitudes about witchcraft and wizardry. As we come up to the 10th anniversary of their first publication in 2007, The Daily Prophet takes a look back on how both the Wizarding and Muggle worlds have changed since the publication of these influential works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-hogwarts&quot;&gt;AT HOGWARTS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Honestly, I think those books gave me the wrong impression,” admits Muggleborn Hufflepuff Jacinda Maysle, “I was prepared to give up using pencils.” Luckily for Ms. Maysle, Hogwarts has adopted a more lax attitude to Muggle technologies since the school days of Harry Potter. Although Ms. Rowling did thorough research and described Hogwarts life fairly accurately for the timeframe, the repealing and the appointment of Minerva McGonagall, a half-blood herself, has allowed for small but significant changes. Although quills are still mandatory for all official examinations, enchanted pens and pencils are now allowed for note-taking and small assignments. “Bless the Muggles who invented these pen sills [sic],” says Arithmancy Professor, Naomi Okino. “They’ve become critical to my numerological work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Half-bloods and Muggleborns of all houses grumble about the lack of internet connectivity, and beg the administration to be allowed laptops and mobile devices. On this point, the Headmistress has not budged. As the modern pencil was invented in the 16th century, perhaps in another 500 years Hogwarts will be connected to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-magical-britain&quot;&gt;IN MAGICAL BRITAIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the country, however, Internet connectivity is a novelty and being adopted widely. “Have you heard of this thing they call ‘Googol Translate’?” asks former Minister of Magic, Cornelius Fudge, when asked for comment. “It’s simply marvelous! You simply have to type in your message– I hate typing, but magic doesn’t work with these things– and it translates English into any language you give it.” He is more reticent when I ask him about a translation incident during the 1994 Quidditch World Cup, recounted in the fourth book of J.K. Rowling’s series. “Oh no, that didn’t happen,” he blusters. “That entire book series is just rubbish. I’ll have you know that I employed every resource to support of Harry Potter that entire time!” Fudge is insistent, but witness reports do not corroborate his claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other prominent figures do not share Fudge’s enthusiasm for the Internet however. Although the Malfoy family historically had good relationships with Muggle highborns– a fact accepted by historians but disputed by the family– Draco Malfoy has a contentious relationship with Muggles and the Internet. “Everything written in that thing is completely false,” he says, rolling his eyes at me, “it’s worse than the rag you work for.” (Ed: the Daily Prophet would like to note it now employs an extensive fact checking team.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Malfoy is no doubt referring to the rumours linking him and Mr. Potter in a romantic relationship, which did not die down when Mr. Malfoy wed Astoria Greenglass. The Wizarding internet is full of such rumours, partially flamed by gossip columnist like the Daily Prophet’s Rita Skeeter, who supplements her columns with online gossip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-muggle-britain&quot;&gt;IN MUGGLE BRITAIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite how the Harry Potter biographies were widely read, nonwizarding Britain has not substantially been changed by the influence of magic. Although magic is no longer a secret from them, the Wizarding world is still separate; Muggles are not allowed at Hogwarts or Diagon Alley without explicit permission from the Ministry of Magic. Consequentially, most Muggles do not see or experience magic in their day to day lives, nor are wizards generally employed by Muggles or vice versa, with a few exceptions. Muggles working in IT and telecommunications, for instance, are routinely welcomed in wizarding homes to install ADSL and cable connections; however, as soon as the job is done and a payment of gold and conjured food is secured, they are usually not welcome for much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizards are occasionally employed in the visual effects and movie making industry for special effects too difficult to convincingly create using computer technologies. Few wizards would admit to the fact, though, as such work is typically seen as beneath their abilities and humiliating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;worldwide&quot;&gt;WORLDWIDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizarding communities around the globe have not changed as much as magical Britain since the publication of these books. “Magical America has long adopted many of the conveniences created by non-magical Americans,” asserts a spokesperson for the US’s Department of Magic, Christopher Delaney. “We pride ourselves in being on top of the latest technologies.” He frowns, though, at the lack of representation of other cultures and inaccuracies laid out in J.K. Rowling’s books. “These books were also wildly popular here, but the Department denounces their inaccuracies.” In particular, he objects to the portrayal of the worldwide wizarding community’s reaction to the Second Wizarding War. “It reads as if we all stood by as the UK went up in flames. We didn’t do that. Our help was largely rejected.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan’s Minister of Magic, Makoto Ueda, has similar objections. “Japan sent many healers and peacekeepers over to the UK during the Second Wizarding War. We are proud of our heritage of protecting people from the Dark Arts.” He does not bring it up, but Ueda seems miffed when I ask him about Rowling’s recent blog posts about worldwide wizardry. “Although Ms. Rowling is a capable researcher of Magical Britain, she does not do thorough work on the rest of the Wizarding world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, she asserts that there are only eleven major wizarding schools, with the remaining witches and wizards studying at home or at less prestigious schools. Many countries would dispute this, with China alone accounting for 15 major schools of its own. “Frankly, Ms. Rowling should leave the subject to local researchers,” says Hinata Okomoto, a Japanese historian. “I believe she was mislead by mischievous exchange students to Hogwarts, who told her falsehoods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assertion is corroborated by her writings on Mahoutokoro, the supposed wizarding school of Japan. In reality, Japan is home to two competing schools, neither of which are located on the island of Iwojima nor have Karate-belt-like colour-changing robes. This has led to many headaches for Ms. Okamoto. “Magical Japan has a rich and deep history of its own,” she says, “and in the past, I would get inquiries about that. Now, all I am ever asked are what houses ‘Mahoutokoro’ has, and what houses I would sort a person into. It’s very dispiriting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J.K. Rowling’s biographical series on Harry Potter has had many effects, such as making Muggles significantly more willing to work with the Wizarding World. However, it’s also flattened Muggle’s conception of magic, to the detriment of other magical communities. We will see in the years to come the full impact of her works, particularly as she has announced her biographies on famed adventurer, Newt Scamander. The Daily Prophet hopes she does her research and makes a positive impact on the Wizarding World.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><category term="harry potter" /><summary>THE DAILY PROPHET SPECIAL REPORT: HARRY POTTER AND THE MUGGLE BIOGRAPHY</summary></entry><entry><title>Making Money off Fandom</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Money off Fandom" /><published>2016-10-31T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-31T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/31/money/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I worked with Sunnie, Richard, and Patrick on an unusual task: make money with fandom. We thought of many different ideas: I suggested 3D printing things using ITP’s printers and selling them to people; we brainstormed workshops and other things to which we could charge admission; I tried to convince Richard to make use of his artistic skills and sell people commissioned drawings. There were many events that weekend that we thought we could take advantage of: Tompkins Square had a Halloween Costumed Dog Parade, and there would be a pantsuit rally for Hillary Clinton. We also brainstormed internet exchanges for funds, such as selling on Etsy or Redbubble. We soon found ourselves short on time, though, and fell back on an easy plan: make something in person. Sell this thing in person. ??? Profit. (Hopefully?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a plan that was more financially sound than that of the Underpants Gnomes. At least there was a financial exchange embedded in our plan. We considered selling the stickers on coffee cups and selling the coffee– I found graphics for Star Fox coffee and made one for Super Smash Bros coffee, knowing that people regularly played Smash Brothers in the Tisch basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/coffee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/coffee.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that this was potentially illegal and dangerous. Why not sell the stickers directly, and skip the coffee? Can’t poison anybody with a sticker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I compiled a few graphics with the suggestion of the others on fandoms that might sell. Sunnie was particularly in favour of the political stickers, so I made “bad hombre” and “nasty women” stickers for the Hillary Clinton fandom. In November, a new Gilmore Girls series would come out, and a trailer had just been released for it, so we included Luke’s diner stickers. Finally, I decided to include Nintendo Switch stickers and Overwatch stickers. The Nintendo Switch trailer had only come out that week, and Overwatch was still a fairly new fandom. All of these stickers would have limited availability outside of our little sticker printing enterprise; it was unlikely that anybody had these stickers already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard bought the sticker paper and Sunnie and I headed to Bobst library for colour printing. To my great relief, we could load our own paper into the laser printers, and they came out perfectly. Richard cut them out, and it was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/stickers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/stickers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four of us each received a subset of the stickers to sell, and we had different strategies. The first dollar we ever made– the minimum amount we had to make for this assignment– was actually made by selling to my friends. The assignment had stipulated that we shouldn’t sell to people we already knew, but they wanted the stickers and who am I to deny them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_money/sales.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_money/sales.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining $12 that we had made was sold to actual strangers though. We largely did so at the Tisch building, so outside of a fandom context. The four of us didn’t quite agree on a pricing strategy, and I believe Richard was most successful with his pay what you can policy. I had settled on a dollar for the big stickers and 50 cents for the smaller ones; Sunnie gave them away for 50 cents for as many as you liked. Patrick haggled with people to sell them in bulk, since we ended up with many left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling was a fun experience, with some unusual experiences. For me, some notable events included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surprising two game center librarians by offering them Overwatch stickers for sale, as they were playing Overwatch at the time. “Oh my god!” they reacted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard sold political stickers to a girl, who explained the joke to another girl, who promptly bought them as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having good conversations about Gilmore Girls (Rory should end up with none of the love interests, imo) with various customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned that fandom is enough to sell people on things they should normally be much cheaper (each sticker cost a few cents for their material), and it was interesting to see fandom play out in real life, outside of the context of fandom-specific events. The most prominent takeaway, though, was that many people do not carry cash or change with them any longer (or claim not to, such that they don’t have to buy a sticker.) We offered to Venmo people, but people were less willing to do so for small (less than a dollar) amounts. Next time: consider selling more expensive things for fandom. Then they might have the cash on hand for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Last week, I worked with Sunnie, Richard, and Patrick on an unusual task: make money with fandom. We thought of many different ideas: I suggested 3D printing things using ITP’s printers and selling them to people; we brainstormed workshops and other things to which we could charge admission; I tried to convince Richard to make use of his artistic skills and sell people commissioned drawings. There were many events that weekend that we thought we could take advantage of: Tompkins Square had a Halloween Costumed Dog Parade, and there would be a pantsuit rally for Hillary Clinton. We also brainstormed internet exchanges for funds, such as selling on Etsy or Redbubble. We soon found ourselves short on time, though, and fell back on an easy plan: make something in person. Sell this thing in person. ??? Profit. (Hopefully?)</summary></entry><entry><title>Vancouver</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vancouver" /><published>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-23T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/23/vancouver/">&lt;p&gt;I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/wordcloud.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few running themes that I clearly associate with Vancouver. One is nature: Vancouver is a city with a lot of natural beauty. You can go surfing in the morning and skiing at night, just with a car or by transit. There are also a lot of water-related words; the Georgia strait runs alongside Vancouver to become the Burrard Inlet. There are so many different bodies of water nearby that I didn’t think to include any in the word cloud. There are also a lot of outdoor activities, as well as alternate forms of transportation– Vancouver is not a car-centric town, and many city planners worldwide admire it for opting not to have a highway that cuts through downtown. Finally, I’ve included a few different cultures and foods in here; Vancouver is fairly diverse, and the food reflects that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-sketches--refinement&quot;&gt;Initial Sketches &amp;amp; Refinement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/initialsketches.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off by drawing a number of sketches drawing from the themes of my word cloud. I played with whitespace and shapes, but overall I gravitated towards the idea that Vancouver is a modern city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverlogocollection.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I favoured my fourth logo concept, but then I decided to look at existing logos for Vancouver to get an idea of the ecosystem my logo would exist in. As it turns out, my logos were often very similar to existing logo concepts– they seeped into my subconscious. Consequentially, I decided on logo concept #2– a literal take on a city embedded in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/refinement.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drew a clearer sketch of the idea on my tablet, and then took it into Illustrator for vectorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-concept&quot;&gt;Final Concept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouvercolour.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/vancouverbw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product is slightly different from the refinement. I tilted the buildings to give the logo a bit more depth, and paired with the city’s name in Metro, a geometric typeface that was designed to compete with Futura, yet be a bit more humanist. It was created in 1929– around the same time Vancouver was amalgamated with Point Grey and South Vancouver– and was popular through the 1950s when Vancouver was developing its signature city planning policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logo-in-context&quot;&gt;Logo in Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/tshirt.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/banner.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/dudechilling.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_logo/letterhead.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><category term="logo" /><summary>I had written about my hometown of Vancouver in this blog before; it served as a contrast to New York in my colour study earlier. So when I decided on it for my city logo brief, I already had some ideas in mind: greens and blue, woods and glass, rivers and mountains. I thought I should still elaborate on my associations with the city, so I started by making a word cloud to emphasize the concepts with which I associate Vancouver.</summary></entry><entry><title>Appropriation Matrix</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Appropriation Matrix" /><published>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-19T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/19/appropriation/">&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/appropmatrix.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;appropmatrix.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Taking inspiration from New York Magazine’s Approval Matrix, I trekked to Gamestop, K-Mart, and Quintessence (a West Village vegetarian restaurant) to produce an Appropriation Matrix for your entertainment.</summary></entry><entry><title>Serial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serial" /><published>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-18T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/18/serial-comms/">&lt;p&gt;It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lab was a fairly straightforward introduction to serial communication and particularly the notion of character encoding and representation; along with understanding binary vs decimal vs hex, it’s the most review of my CS degree we’ve tackled so far in PComp. It can still be a little tricky for me to remember what a bit is versus a byte versus a nibble; I’m usually a pretty high-level programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/numbersystems.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second lab connected P5 to the Arduino via serial connections; this was far more expressive than the serial monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/lab2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_serial/p5lab.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waived ICM and haven’t touched P5 before these labs, so I decided to do a creative application to get myself accustomed to it. I had to learn the frustrations of everyone else. Personally, I think P5 is a poor choice for learning to programming; you spend a lot of time thinking about coordinates in a way that you won’t necessarily need to in many programming languages (granted, you do have to do so if you’re doing primarily graphics, but I don’t think most programmers do.) In any case, here’s my little house. It is sunny when you leave the photoresistor uncovered, turns cloudy when it’s partially covered, and becomes night when it’s fully covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/wxlETaoG10S9G&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do a great job of documenting here– my hand is mostly out of frame. I think you can still get the gist of it, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It’s midterm season, and it’s taking a toll on everyone. I took screenshots and photos of my labs, but can’t muster up much to say about them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Buffy and Fan Engagement</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buffy and Fan Engagement" /><published>2016-10-16T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/16/buffy/">&lt;p&gt;Until fairly recently, fan engagement seemed low on the corporate priority list. Case in point: the sale of props and clothing from &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt;, described in the article “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom: When &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt; Goes to eBay”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, was purportedly “for the fans” but was really financial in motivation. From that point of view, the sale was a success: 20th Century Fox made a great deal of money. From a fan engagement point of view, however, it left something to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a common saying that any press is good press, and in fandom, we say the same thing of engagement. Any engagement is good engagement, purportedly. But I would attach an addendum to this: any engagement is good engagement, but positive engagement is better than negative. The Buffy sale exposed longstanding divisions in the fan community, and caused some negative engagement. Because the actors of the show are sexualized by the show, there is no cultural norm of the fan community to refrain from commenting on this. However, the overt fetishization of the clothes for sale in this eBay auction caused some negative reactions from the fans, making one fan comment that they “shudder to think what some people may do with … outfits that are up for sale.” (36) It also exposed other divisions amongst fans, especially the divide amongst rich fans and poor: “I am bitter! It’s not fair! All of us Buffy fans want something but the rich bitches’ll get it all!” (38) Fans were upset by the unequal distribution of goods, and the top two bidders got 10% of the items. Another winner turned out to be a reseller, and fans were extremely upset by his destruction of the fan objects to sell in fractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the sale was poor engagement for going against the spirit of the text of the show. &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt; was built to be egalitarian in nature, with nerds and cheerleader types alike being key members of the Scooby Gang. The eBay sale set the balance of egalitarian fan communities off balance by creating an explicit hierarchy of fans: fans who’ve acquired more items versus fans who failed to buy anything. It transformed the show from a thing that everyone owns to something owned explicitly by a small group of people. Although the show fetishized the characters, it also had a strong feminist streak: the majority of the heroes were female, and it heavily promoted the idea of female empowerment. With the eBay sale, however, it emphasized the sexualization and deemphasized the feminist elements of the show. Actresses were reduced to fetish objects, and not the fully-fleshed female characters as written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Buffy fan community was resilient, and this sale did not have a large effect on the fan community. Fan engagement was already high, with an active message board wherein the show creator and writers would talk to fans directly, engaging in acknowledgement and flattery. The show would even create plots that responded to fan wishes, with episodes that felt very much like fan content (“The Wish”, “Doppelgangland”, and “Once More, with Feeling” are some examples.) Although the fan auction could’ve been better and more positive fan engagement, it’s still fan engagement and better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Stenger, Josh. “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to EBay.” Cinema Journal 45.4 (2006): 26-44. Web. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>Until fairly recently, fan engagement seemed low on the corporate priority list. Case in point: the sale of props and clothing from Buffy the Vampire Slayer, described in the article “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom: When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to eBay”1, was purportedly “for the fans” but was really financial in motivation. From that point of view, the sale was a success: 20th Century Fox made a great deal of money. From a fan engagement point of view, however, it left something to be desired.


  
    
      Stenger, Josh. “The Clothes Make the Fan: Fashion and Online Fandom When Buffy the Vampire Slayer Goes to EBay.” Cinema Journal 45.4 (2006): 26-44. Web. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title>Winter Show Poster</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Show Poster" /><published>2016-10-11T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/11/poster/">&lt;p&gt;I felt guilty about how I didn’t do my best making my business card double sided, so I also did a visual language assignment our section wasn’t actually assigned– making a postcard for the winter show. &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.itp.nyu.edu/academic-policies/community/show-postcard-design-submission-instructions&quot;&gt;The brief&lt;/a&gt; says that they were looking for “a more humanistic view of ITP” and I ran with that in mind. I was also hoping to submit a very different design from the other submissions: I suspected that most other students would use photography and focus on other students. I decided I’d illustrate my poster, and focus on applications of ITP– our creations and the people who interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/ideas.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/ideas.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched out a number of concepts based around this, ranging from the fantastic to the very practical. Should my poster focus on our dream inventions, our aspirations? Should they abstractly focus on the users? In the end, I decided to focus on a few concrete scenes from actual applications. I sought inspiration from comic books and posters like that for &lt;em&gt;Bill Cunningham, New York&lt;/em&gt;– so much humanity is on display in this poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/bill.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/bill.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brainstormed a list of classes that might make good scenes, and then whittled the list down to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing for Seniors in the Information Age&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hardwired for Stories Out Loud: Why Stories Matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design for the Real World: BeatRockers @ the Lavelle School&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing Assistive Technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then drafted out a number of layouts for these scenes. I decided on the checkmarked layout– I figured the poster might be displayed a bit higher, and having the text at the midpoint would put it at eye level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/layouts.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/layouts.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, I moved to digital production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit funny– when I program and have git, I meticulously make commits and backups and always have the older versions on hand. I forget that entirely when I work with graphics: I didn’t save any of my earlier computer drafts. I’ll just describe them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off finding reference images, and creating a draft with stick figures– I just wanted to get the postures right. I then created an initial line drawing and colour testing– colour is so integral to the final image, so I wanted to have a good idea of what it would look like before I spent the time inking the outlines. I decided to stick with a small palette, to save time and since I thought it’d be visual interesting– taking inspiration from the works of Chris Ware and designers on Dribbble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/ware.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/ware.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/2337812-Afterhours-Poster&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/colour.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/colour.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a lot of colours, the image is a bit distracting, and the titling and words do not stand out as much. I also wanted to subtlely evoke NYU and use purple– a hard feat if I were to use realistic colours. I ended up with the colours you can see below in my final version, after inking, colouring, and typesetting. It’s distinctive and futuristic, but still soft. Just like ITP?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_poster/poster.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_poster/poster.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>I felt guilty about how I didn’t do my best making my business card double sided, so I also did a visual language assignment our section wasn’t actually assigned– making a postcard for the winter show. The brief says that they were looking for “a more humanistic view of ITP” and I ran with that in mind. I was also hoping to submit a very different design from the other submissions: I suspected that most other students would use photography and focus on other students. I decided I’d illustrate my poster, and focus on applications of ITP– our creations and the people who interact with them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Design for People</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design for People" /><published>2016-10-09T14:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T14:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/design-for-people/">&lt;p&gt;It’s funny what experiences carry over when you’re working. When doing physical computing projects, my mind naturally tends towards habits I developed in computer science and development: start small, and test often. Even before Benedetta told us to do so, I had a tendency to test my circuits in pieces and with simpler components; it just seemed logical if I wanted to debug anything. Conversely, though, until this week’s readings, it hadn’t occured to me to bring user experience design into my physical computing projects. Is it because I’ve only been doing simple projects to test my learning, and because they’re not user facing? Or would they just not have occured to me anyways? Either way, &lt;em&gt;Sketching User Experiences: The Workbook&lt;/em&gt; was a great read, and I hope I’ll pick up a physical copy and adopt the habits within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly, I should pick up the habits of: paper prototyping and testing (for physical computing); keeping a sketchbook for design ideas; and the sketching techniques from &lt;em&gt;Drawing from the Right Side of the Brain&lt;/em&gt; (another fine book.) Anh Nguyen’s project, Happy Feedback Machine, has great examples of sketching and a really adorable use case storyboard (though this sort of seems like it’s assuming too much per Tom Igoe’s blog post.) It’s honestly wondrous that I hadn’t thought to apply these techniques to physical computing. Everything covered in &lt;em&gt;Sketching User Experiences&lt;/em&gt; is stuff I’ve encountered before, but I never thought of it as applicable. Hopefully, I’ll be able to bring both CS + Design experience to future Physical Computing Projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It’s funny what experiences carry over when you’re working. When doing physical computing projects, my mind naturally tends towards habits I developed in computer science and development: start small, and test often. Even before Benedetta told us to do so, I had a tendency to test my circuits in pieces and with simpler components; it just seemed logical if I wanted to debug anything. Conversely, though, until this week’s readings, it hadn’t occured to me to bring user experience design into my physical computing projects. Is it because I’ve only been doing simple projects to test my learning, and because they’re not user facing? Or would they just not have occured to me anyways? Either way, Sketching User Experiences: The Workbook was a great read, and I hope I’ll pick up a physical copy and adopt the habits within.</summary></entry><entry><title>Counterculture and Commercial Ventures</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Counterculture and Commercial Ventures" /><published>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/09/counterculture/">&lt;p&gt;The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films &lt;em&gt;Escape from Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for the lack of outrage is because both groups remain deeply embedded in their respective fan communities. When you are called a sellout, it’s often for a perceived betrayal of the community: by foregrounding your commercial interests, you are placing your own needs above those of the community. The skaters of “Buying In” largely don’t have this problem because their commercial sales were initially to each other– by keeping within the community, you don’t seem like a sellout. The last example of Tony Hawk is the most likely to be called a sellout, with his tacit approval of people who are not skaters participating in skate culture. However, he can deflect accusations of selling out by claiming that his ventures are evangelization– he is encouraging the expansion of his community– and profit-sharing– by including other skaters in his video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Disneyland social clubs are communities themselves and part of the larger Disney community. They embrace larger Disney values, and accept questions and criticism from regular parkgoers (“feel free to ask any questions” and “always say hi” advises one leader cited in the article.) By following the existing codes of behaviour of the Disney community, they’ve earned themselves tolerance. Additionally, by banding together, they’re also able to protect each other– the films I mentioned in the opening are by solo auteurs, and by being alone they are easier for a corporation to target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;values-and-fan-context&quot;&gt;Values and Fan Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why these groups do not provoke fan outrage is that the fan objects– skateboard culture and Disney– do not have values that disallow or discourage this intersection. Although skateboarding is purportedly rebellious, nothing in its fan context disapproves of commercial interests. The first team even formed as part of a local skate shop, Zephyr, and young fans hope to gain sponsorship deals. Arguably, selling things is a part of the fan context. So long as you’re not printing anti-skate park propaganda, you’re still behaving in line with skateboarding culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social clubs of Disneyland do not look like they represent Disney values, but they prove themselves with their actions. They raise money for charity, and try their best to help people. Disney values are often about children and family, and many social clubs bring their children along, or act as family for each other. Disney wants to look inclusive, so they include the social clubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commodification&quot;&gt;Commodification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one last reason that this intersection is tolerated is commercial: everybody wants to make a living. Skateboarders need to make money somehow, so why would they begrudge the ones who manage to turn their counterculture into a career? If anything, that’s to be admired: doing something they love while making money. Disney profits from the social clubs via their annual memberships, as well as their buying food and merchandise. There’s no reason to turn this money down by shutting these clubs down. Overall, counterculture and commerce can intersect peacefully– so long as it stays in line with core values.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>The intersection of counterculture and commercialism often provokes strong emotions. If you’re a counterculture figure and sign a deal with a corporation, you’ll be angrily branded a sellout. If your art presents a brand in a way the owners don’t like, you’re likely to be sued. (Chief examples of this are the films Escape from Tomorrow, which was illegally filmed at Disneyland, and Superstar, a biopic of Karen Carpenter which presented Richard Carpenter in an unflattering light.) In this week in fandom, however, we had two readings in which counterculture and commercialism are joined without too much controversy. In “Buying In: The Straw Man in the Gray Flannel Suit”, we examine the the commodification of skate culture of southern California. In “The Very Merry Un-Gangs of Disneyland”, we take a look at the social clubs of Disneyland that style themselves after gangs. But why don’t these provoke a stronger reaction?</summary></entry><entry><title>Let’s Get Down to Business</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Get Down to Business" /><published>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/10/06/business/">&lt;p&gt;I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important factors in the design of my business cards was the redesign of my portfolio and blog. When I started ITP, I knew I would have to redesign both: I failed to update them in years, and class after class emphasized to me that the blog was a central part of ITP. I also wanted to move my blog to the ceiling.cat domain, a novelty domain that I’d owned for years but had done nothing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/ceilingcat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were an internet nerd in the mid 2000s, you’d probably remember this meme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I wanted was to have matching but separate identities for both websites. The portfolio was serious, and meant to showcase my best work; the blog was for works in progress and silly thoughts from ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted the blog to have a logo with a cat. It didn’t make much sense to do otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize: I wanted to have a logo template that would work for a serious portfolio as well as a cat. That’s a bit of a tough briefing, but it’s aided by how the original ceiling cat appears: he pops out of a square hole in the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequentially, I can start with a square template for both logos– it’s clean and professional for my portfolio, and appropriate for ceiling cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/template.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/template.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to subtly evoke stamps and Chinese seals– it’d reflect my heritage and help give the logos a unified idea. I rounded the corners and decided that the logos would be single colour, as if they could be stamped on. Then, I could convert them to black and white, any colours, or even add an image to the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/seals.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is getting a bit long-winded, so I’ll spare you more details about the logos. Suffice to say, I drew a bunch of cats, and tested a bunch of typefaces, and came out with the following two logos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/logos.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/logos.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-original-design&quot;&gt;The Original Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this starting point, I decided to make my business cards on Sunday. Given the ‘chinese seal’ design element, I decided to take scroll paintings as inspiration, and drew a digital watercolour painting of a bird on a cherry blossom tree. (My street in Vancouver was lined with cherry blossoms, as many are.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/flowers.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/flowers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The painting’s focal is from right to left, as most Chinese scrolls are, and I consequentially placed my seal and my information on the left of the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/original.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/original.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished at this point, and then the next day I went to class. I received the assignment, and changed things for the worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-redesign&quot;&gt;The Redesign&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most consequential change was that the assignment stipulated that the card had to be double sided. I originally tried making the painting go across the two sides, but the image was too low-resolution to print at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/spread.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/spread.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then decided to stick with the image on one side, and just moved the information to the back. I also flipped the painting, because we discussed in class how the lower left corner was the weakest focal point of an image (which, in retrospect now, is less consequential in a landscape business card with its low height.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vl_business/double.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;vl_business/double.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent this image to the printers, which I terribly regret. In retrospect, landscape business cards are too short for that focus information to matter, and images always look better before they’re flipped (unless they are perfectly symmetrical.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it’s overall a stronger design on only one side. I also regret the serif font I chose on the back– I thought it would provide a nice contrast, but it just looks out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I wish I kept my original card. But you can keep this analysis in the meanwhile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visuallang" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>I have three confessions to make, dear blog readers, about my Visual Language assignment. The first is that the night before it was assigned, I essentially finished it. I wasn’t aware it would be assigned the next day; I just thought that I should make myself business cards. The second is that I just made some quick edits to it to meet the assignment’s criteria for submission. I didn’t redo the assignment; it felt like a waste. The third confession: I don’t like the adjustments I made, and I wish I kept my original design before sending them to the printers.</summary></entry></feed>
