<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-21T17:43:18-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Airport Rebellion</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Airport Rebellion" /><published>2017-03-21T06:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-21T06:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/21/airportrebel/">&lt;p&gt;Although many forms of rebellion are the antithesis of ritual, others are directly codified by it. The idea, by Max Gluckman, a South African anthropologist, is that ritualized rebellion serves as a release for impulses that threaten institutions, by which they ultimately reinforce them. For instance, during Carnival, you can drink and revel to a point that would normally be frowned upon, and you could return to the normal Catholic social order afterwards. In a much more fantastical way, the film series, “The Purge” is built around the same idea: you take one day to commit as many crimes as you want, but only that day; in this way, crime the rest of the year is abated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself performing a small ritual of technological rebellion over Spring Break. I’m not sure if this act serves to maintain social order in any way, but it does make me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many security experts, including Bruce Schneider who coined the term, view the airport and airline security apparatus as “security theatre”: a show of supposedly improved security that does not actually achieve it. It makes people feel safer without actually preventing much terrorism, and also wastes a lot of time. All the time I spend putting my toiletries in small containers are a waste. Taking my shoes off is uncomfortable, and the shoe bomb only happened the one time, unsuccessfully. The long lineups and scans and invasions of privacy do little except to annoy me and other passengers. They make me want to rebel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I do, in a very small, inconsequential way. On every airplane, you are told that electronic signals from your phone can interfere with the airplane’s control systems. I am not sure if they actually do. Consequentially, here is my small ritual:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mobile phone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;airplane (you are sitting in)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cabin crew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/airplaneritual.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;airplaneritual.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cabin crew will tell you to switch your phone to airplane mode for takeoffs and landings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to use your phone during takeoffs and landings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are spotted by a crew member, pretend to switch to airplane mode and put your phone away. Do not switch to airplane mode.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take your phone back out. You may continue to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I really need to use my phone during takeoffs and landings? Absolutely not, and the data signal becomes so weak that it’s pointless to keep it on– it honestly just serves to drain my phone’s battery faster. But do I continue to do this as a form of small rebellion against the air travel apparatus? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not believe that this affects anybody else, and especially not the airplane’s control systems. It mostly pacifies me in a system that leaves me feeling powerless, in line after goddamn line. I took four flights over the break, since I had two layovers. I endured scans several times and patdowns. It feels nice to say “no” in a small way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky enough to be a cisgendered woman of the “model” minority, so I’m hardly ever selected for a random search. Whenever my belongings set something off in airport security, I only experience minor panic and am let through with little trouble. Perhaps if I was of a different race or have other circumstances, I’d be less inclined to perform this small ritual. But as it is, it’s a little rebellion to help me endure an arduous process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="eroft" /><category term="electronic rituals" /><category term="electronic rituals oracles and fortune telling" /><category term="security theatre" /><category term="rebellion" /><summary>Although many forms of rebellion are the antithesis of ritual, others are directly codified by it. The idea, by Max Gluckman, a South African anthropologist, is that ritualized rebellion serves as a release for impulses that threaten institutions, by which they ultimately reinforce them. For instance, during Carnival, you can drink and revel to a point that would normally be frowned upon, and you could return to the normal Catholic social order afterwards. In a much more fantastical way, the film series, “The Purge” is built around the same idea: you take one day to commit as many crimes as you want, but only that day; in this way, crime the rest of the year is abated.</summary></entry><entry><title>Turning</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turning" /><published>2017-03-10T04:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T04:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/10/turning/">&lt;p&gt;Spring Break has arrived, along with a snowstorm in New York. Knowing that I’ll be leaving for London tomorrow, I wanted to finish my lathe exercise before my trip– lest I be stuck competing with everyone else to finish in the last weekend before class begins again. I had no idea what to make with it, though, and thought hard before concluding that I’d just turn until I felt content with my work. I didn’t see much point in making a handle if I had nothing to which I’d attach it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to turn a simple wooden dowel, and save my piece of firewood for when I felt more confident with the lathe. In all honesty, I hadn’t realized we’d be given material, and hoarded this earlier in the week. After we got material, I decided to use it anyways. Putting it on the lathe was exceedingly simple, and almost suspiciously so. I kept feeling like I was missing a step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started turning the piece, I discovered that I had accidentally put it on at an angle. Woops. I had to take the piece a bit down so it’d be a consistent cylinder, and then just lathed as I saw fit. It was surprisingly soothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanding on the lathe is a bit of a pleasure, but it can be hard to sand down little grooves perfectly. I sanded down my randomly turned dowel, and then rubbed boiled linseed oil on it. My brother advocated it, as it is cheaper than tung oil and dries faster. (I didn’t apply enough for a professional finish, though, since this is just an exercise.) I thought I should listen to a man who literally did his Masters’ thesis on wood finishes (albeit on outdoor deck finishes. I imagine he has reasonable expertise about other finishes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_lathe/4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_lathe/4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick coat of BLO, I sanded it down and tried to get the rough edges out of the grooves again. This could be a stair baluster, theoretically.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="turning" /><category term="lathe" /><summary>Spring Break has arrived, along with a snowstorm in New York. Knowing that I’ll be leaving for London tomorrow, I wanted to finish my lathe exercise before my trip– lest I be stuck competing with everyone else to finish in the last weekend before class begins again. I had no idea what to make with it, though, and thought hard before concluding that I’d just turn until I felt content with my work. I didn’t see much point in making a handle if I had nothing to which I’d attach it.</summary></entry><entry><title>Satellites</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Satellites" /><published>2017-03-04T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/satellites/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking at landsat data for Everything is Spatial, and it’s fascinating. I wish it had more zoomed-in data so I can look at building and cities more closely, but it’s interesting to look at larger bodies and seeing how things change. It’s nice to be able to access direct satellite data with exact times– one thing that frustrates me about Google is its copyright data that notes everything as Copyright 2017 Google. Who knows when this data is from, consequentially?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some map data from BC. Our slogan is Beautiful British Columbia, and it’s lovely covered in snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/bc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tracked the development of Rio de Janeiro since 2013– I thought it’d be interesting to see how it has changed for the Olympics. A lot of development happened, as you might imagine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2013.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2013.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2014.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2014.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2015.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2015.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2016.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2016.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/2017.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/2017.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, in gif form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_sat/rio.gif&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_sat/rio.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most striking change is likely the construction of the Arco Metropolitano highway, which was done through 2014, and its later integration into the landscape. You can also see how buildings start to develop the places at the edges, though the city itself isn’t all that changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(All these photos weren’t taken at the same time of year– I was prioritizing clearness of cloud cover over preserving the same timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my final, I was originally thinking of doing a political idea (I considered things like tracking and mapping the prices of menstrual products around the world, similar to the Big Mac Index), but occasionally you need a break from activist topics. Consequentially, I considered sillier things: stuff like mapping copycat buildings and landmarks (China famously copies landmarks from around the world) and comparing them to the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the topic I think I’ve settled on is simpler, and inspired by the place where I’m from. Vancouver is the third most common filming location in North America for many films and TV shows, but hardly ever stars as itself. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ojm74VGsZBU&quot;&gt;great video about this topic by Tony Zhou&lt;/a&gt;. It stars as Seattle, New York, and countless other metropolises. This has got me thinking about all the towns that have pretended to be New York in film besides my city. Toronto is a very common New York stand-in, for instance, starring as the city for American Psycho. So for my final, I think I’ll map all the places that’ve been New York, and let the user explore the movies with false New Yorks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neue New Yorks. Or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>I’ve been looking at landsat data for Everything is Spatial, and it’s fascinating. I wish it had more zoomed-in data so I can look at building and cities more closely, but it’s interesting to look at larger bodies and seeing how things change. It’s nice to be able to access direct satellite data with exact times– one thing that frustrates me about Google is its copyright data that notes everything as Copyright 2017 Google. Who knows when this data is from, consequentially?</summary></entry><entry><title>IDNYC &amp;amp; Final Project Ideas</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IDNYC &amp; Final Project Ideas" /><published>2017-03-04T04:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T04:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/03/04/nycid/">&lt;p&gt;Our midterm for doing good is good business was a research project on the IDNYC. It all started with the following prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_nycid/prompt.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_nycid/prompt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I developed a list of questions about the program to ask Benedetta and also determine the answers to. At first, it was unclear whether we were supposed to research other ID programs for the last question or not, but it was clarified that the project centered around the IDNYC, and that at least one of us should go apply for the ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played with the document calculator online and decided that Michael would apply for the card– he had already been planning to, and he had the pamphlets to prove it. Our first meeting was rather unfruitful– we had thought we could just walk-in and get an appointment, but apparently you had to book one in advance online or by calling 311.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_nycid/nyc_id.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_nycid/nyc_id.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first appointment after this was also unsuccessful– we didn’t read the document calculator correctly and didn’t realize his residency documents needed to be dated within the last 60 days. The second appointment was successful, but Michael moved recently so it was a mixed success– he wouldn’t receive his ID at his new address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also created a slide deck to introduce the IDNYC and go through a few personas and the troubles they might face in getting the ID. The slide deck is included below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13V7estj1a3sCrULcK4a-uh9htX3gM72g29RJKGVNQFs/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=10000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics that are particularly interesting to me usually focus on women and girls and also apply to populations in richer countries. Things that are of particular interest to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do we ensure homeless and poorer populations have access to menstrual health products? Could we support small business at the same time? How do we educate young girls about menstrual health across cultures where it may be taboo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how do we protect homeless and poorer women from the threat of sexual assault, and encourage them to report cases of assault?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;similarly to my first query, how do we ensure that babies have access to clean diapers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how can we help people have privacy and a good night’s sleep in extremely close quarters? Does everyone have access to an effective mosquito net?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the challenge, how can ensure access to identification cards and other documents? How can we ensure these cards are portable and preservable in harsh conditions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think right now my favourite of these questions is the one about menstrual health, and I need to do more research on the topic. I think it’s a prime area for technology to assist in– although girls have access to their peers and teachers, they would want privacy and sensitivity that these groups might lack (many teachers are male, after all.) And homeless women might have difficulty asking for these products. Additionally, how are these products disposed of? Can we get clean underwear and sanitary products for everybody?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do more research. Hopefully, someone else might be interested in the topic– it’s often a topic men shy away from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="nycid" /><summary>Our midterm for doing good is good business was a research project on the IDNYC. It all started with the following prompt:</summary></entry><entry><title>Prototyping a Vending Machine</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/27/vendingmachine1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping a Vending Machine" /><published>2017-02-27T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-27T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/27/vendingmachine1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/27/vendingmachine1/">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my previous post about Subtraction, I wanted to prototype a Vending Machine housing for my midterm project. It’s a project born out of the Battery Store, a small business run by me and Lindsey Daniels (and a few other helpers!) If you’re at ITP and want cheap batteries, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.nyu.edu/batteries/&quot;&gt;check out the details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://entrepreneur.nyu.edu/blog/2017/02/17/prototyping-fund-spring-17-awardees/&quot;&gt;NYU’s prototyping fund&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps in the future, we’ll make a kitso other popel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to a terrible pine plywood from MDF, because I had run out of MDF– I’m slightly regretting it now that I’m seeing everyone else’s projects and how polished they look! But this is meant to be an initial prototype, and I have a nicer ply for the finished version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I wanted to use what I learned from the last exercise, I used those complicated hidden finger joints on the sides again. Since it was a different material, I tested out the joints again before working on a final copy– a good decision because it took a few tries before I got the joints tight again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_midterm/vm1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_midterm/vm1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_midterm/vm2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_midterm/vm2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting this right, I drew out the vending machine in Vectorworks. Since it’s just a prototype, I planned on only a two-item vending machine, with a shelf to hold the items. I didn’t plan on having the shelf for class, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_midterm/vectorworks.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_midterm/vectorworks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, I was on the CNC for around five hours. I feel like I’m an expert on the thing now. Relatively speaking, anyways. Compared to the rest of the first-years, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_midterm/vm5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_midterm/vm5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the completed prototype of the housing. I also tried out the shelf but… I didn’t measure everything quite perfectly. I cut out the shelf before I finished the rest of the housing, which was a mistake. But now that the housing is done, I can work on getting a shelf that fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_midterm/vm4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_midterm/vm4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><category term="cnc" /><category term="battery store" /><category term="joinery" /><summary>As I mentioned in my previous post about Subtraction, I wanted to prototype a Vending Machine housing for my midterm project. It’s a project born out of the Battery Store, a small business run by me and Lindsey Daniels (and a few other helpers!) If you’re at ITP and want cheap batteries, check out the details.</summary></entry><entry><title>Everything is Connected</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/26/connected/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything is Connected" /><published>2017-02-26T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-26T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/26/connected</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/26/connected/">&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I wish I could say that I created an extremely thoughtful data map for Everything is Spatial, but the output ended up being entirely shaped by the datasets that were available from NYC OpenData. A less discussed aspect of making data available for everyone from the government is the cold fact that some of this data isn’t very useful to people outside the agencies. For my work today, this isn’t a matter of what the contents are or why I should care about, but the truth of formatting and complete data. I could hardly find any use in a compilation of farmer’s markets if every latitude and longitude listed was rounded to the nearest whole number. I’m pretty certain most NYC farmer’s markets aren’t in Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up, instead, mapping out LinkNYC and used a custom icon– the idea was that these hotspots are tourist’s destinations and centered around tourists’ areas. Consequentially, a point of interest icon for a LinkNYC was likely to point to an actual point of interest. That’s the idea, anyways. Here’s the map: &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/styles/v1/zelara/ciznkp1yr002t2rqk1goyzyac.html?title=true&amp;amp;access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiemVsYXJhIiwiYSI6ImNpejRqcTM3dTA1NmgycXA4aG9sMThwOWQifQ.IgjTacT5vhTj5Zzitd_rQQ#9.6/40.787107/-73.782926/0&quot;&gt;https://api.mapbox.com/styles/v1/zelara/ciznkp1yr002t2rqk1goyzyac.html?title=true&amp;amp;access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiemVsYXJhIiwiYSI6ImNpejRqcTM3dTA1NmgycXA4aG9sMThwOWQifQ.IgjTacT5vhTj5Zzitd_rQQ#9.6/40.787107/-73.782926/0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my QGIS map, I created an extremely patriotic map of Canada. There are so many rivers abound, and it’s so tied up with the mythos of the fur traders, that I was playing with the idea that rivers are the ‘blood’ of Canada. In the end, though, I reversed the colours of land and rivers, so it’s more of a flag tribute than anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_canada.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_canada.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This projection of Canada really bugs me, in ways I never anticipated. I thought I’d like non-Mercator projections more. Is there a way to change projections easily in QGIS? More research must be done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>Honestly, I wish I could say that I created an extremely thoughtful data map for Everything is Spatial, but the output ended up being entirely shaped by the datasets that were available from NYC OpenData. A less discussed aspect of making data available for everyone from the government is the cold fact that some of this data isn’t very useful to people outside the agencies. For my work today, this isn’t a matter of what the contents are or why I should care about, but the truth of formatting and complete data. I could hardly find any use in a compilation of farmer’s markets if every latitude and longitude listed was rounded to the nearest whole number. I’m pretty certain most NYC farmer’s markets aren’t in Jersey.</summary></entry><entry><title>Building a World</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/25/prototypes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a World" /><published>2017-02-25T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-25T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/25/prototypes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/25/prototypes/">&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t realized that I needed to build a paper prototype last class– I didn’t remember what Marianne had told us in class, and misread the syllabus. As the next assignment was to build out our world, however, and I don’t have a traditional world to build as I’m not doing VR, building a paper prototype of the app was still an appropriate way to ‘build my world’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/prototype1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/prototype1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/prototype2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/prototype2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/prototype3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/prototype3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/prototype4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/prototype4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then built logos for the major players in the universe– the oil company that Cassandra works for, Troy Oil, as i”n the original story, she was a princess of Troy, and the messaging application she uses to communicate. Since the idea is that Troy Oil is testing out a new communication platform for secure messaging– a trend nowadays, with players like Signal and concerns about encryption are more commonplace after the election– the idea was to create a fake encrypted communications platform. I went with the name “Soothsafe”– safe, to imply the encryption and security, and Sooth for the pun on soothsay, the power of Cassandra in the original story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/soothsafe.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/soothsafe.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/troyoil.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/troyoil.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then mocked up digital copies of the prototype– they’re my “world”– and also a file of the document that Cassandra is whistleblowing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/digital1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/digital1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/digital2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/digital2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/digital3.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/digital3.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ft_prototype/memo.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;ft_prototype/memo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The readings this week were more personal than I’m accustomed to for readings for this class, and I’m refreshed by its candor. It is problematic the way we’ve normalized child abuse, and it’s great to see someone directly address it– I feel like Bettleheim would’ve done so, but he was also a practitioner of abuse. It is still disappointing to see a continued eurocentrism, even if it is at least acknowledged. Are there any academics who write about fairy tales and also have actually studied anything in other cultures? So far I’m not certain this exists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><summary>I hadn’t realized that I needed to build a paper prototype last class– I didn’t remember what Marianne had told us in class, and misread the syllabus. As the next assignment was to build out our world, however, and I don’t have a traditional world to build as I’m not doing VR, building a paper prototype of the app was still an appropriate way to ‘build my world’.</summary></entry><entry><title>Glitch, A Fail Story</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glitch, A Fail Story" /><published>2017-02-20T15:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T15:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch/">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1BMAGmJ5jZB0V1vUPhXJMGUXjTc6IQoDoyPblylFSyAI/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=15000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="glitch" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Blockchained Melody</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchained Melody" /><published>2017-02-20T06:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T06:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought much for Bitcoin, and consequentially blockchain technologies. Anecdotally, I knew it as the currency of libertarians and drug dealers; I only knew people who used it because they needed something illegal or used our university’s power and servers to mine it. Consequentially, it was kind of interesting to read positive takes on their potential uses for charity work, though it was quite clear to me that the sources were biased towards the technology (three of the articles came from websites devoted to promoting the blockchain or a product of blockchain; the fourth was Forbes, but was not on a blockchain technology.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, one reading wasn’t too bad for the most part, but ended with the suggestion that the reader should “buy cryptocurrency.” Ridiculous. You don’t advise potential stock buyers to just buy up some stock to learn about trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I do concede that blockchain has its uses when accountability is paramount or when the local currency is unstable or otherwise unreliable, for instance, in states where inflation is out of control. I don’t really see how it can prevent corruption or crime that doesn’t involve double dealing– and even then, that supposes all the broker’s partners will be using the blockchain technology. If even one partner doesn’t, they can double deal with one blockchain partner and one that doesn’t use the technology. They’d also have to all be using the same technology. A lot of the appeal of blockchain is decentralization, but to insist on decentralization and standardization simultaneously doesn’t seem entirely feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another concern I have is how this is essentially predicated on other countries having the resources to freely mine the blockchain, which is fairly resource intensive. Isn’t it problematic to toot your own horn for paying for a South African school’s electricity when your payment required a similar sized farm in China to oversee it? Or perhaps one in Europe or America (though China is the most likely.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, I still see blockchain as largely an attempt by libertarians to sidestep the government. And buy drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article I felt most kindly towards was for M-Pasa, which grew out of Kenya and thusly was well suited to Kenyan needs. Maybe I’d like the blockchain more if it didn’t seem like another case of the Western world prescribing solutions to non-western countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions I have for this week’s panel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the strengths of blockchain is in decentralization, but how can we ensure standardization and adoption without an authority to guide it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a related note, how can we ensure decentralization when so many of the miners are in farms in the same location?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin is largely what people think of when they think of blockchain currencies, but it has numerous problems (reserves are held by a few people, the aforementioned server farms in China, limits and refunds.) If not Bitcoin, what cryptocurrency could you mean? Do you envision a future with one cryptocurrency or with many?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What advantages does blockchain offer local or national charities? In countries with stable currency?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite cryptocurrency is still Dogecoin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>I’ve never thought much for Bitcoin, and consequentially blockchain technologies. Anecdotally, I knew it as the currency of libertarians and drug dealers; I only knew people who used it because they needed something illegal or used our university’s power and servers to mine it. Consequentially, it was kind of interesting to read positive takes on their potential uses for charity work, though it was quite clear to me that the sources were biased towards the technology (three of the articles came from websites devoted to promoting the blockchain or a product of blockchain; the fourth was Forbes, but was not on a blockchain technology.)</summary></entry><entry><title>Joinery</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joinery" /><published>2017-02-19T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery/">&lt;p&gt;For my midterm project for Subtraction, I wanted to construct the case for a desktop vending machine for the battery store that I run with Lindsey Daniels. I’ve seen pictures of this done before, but the creator doesn’t release his plans since he sells the parts on his website. Why not make my own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/venduino.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/venduino.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the joints I needed to study are tenons– I’ll be making use of a lot of right angles for the vending machine. It was a little tricky making the template in vector works, and I got frustrated more than a few times. I never really understood when and why the program would want to snap things, so I often had to manually adjust x and y coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/vectorworks.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/vectorworks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, cutting was a bit of a cinch. I was working off the scraps of my MDF last week, so I was a bit concerned about the spacing, but it worked out fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/cutting.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re very little, but they’re important for testing this joint out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/final.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/final.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version I tried was not quite flush. I had to adjust the spacing of my pocket on the right side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was far more flush, but still had too much of a pocket. Let’s try it again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this attempt worked out fairly well, and I had run out of my scrap of MDF so I had to stop. It’s pretty nice, though, but I’ll have to try out the joints again when I get my materials for my vending machine. I’ll be ordering ply instead of MDF– what if somebody spills things onto my vending machine– so the material change might make things a little different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><category term="cnc" /><category term="joinery" /><summary>For my midterm project for Subtraction, I wanted to construct the case for a desktop vending machine for the battery store that I run with Lindsey Daniels. I’ve seen pictures of this done before, but the creator doesn’t release his plans since he sells the parts on his website. Why not make my own?</summary></entry></feed>
