<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-29T17:02:58-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>The Dissemination of Fairy Tales</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dissemination of Fairy Tales" /><published>2017-01-29T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-29T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/popular/">&lt;p&gt;Why are fairy tales popular? In the selected readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century this week, Bettelheim and Zipes take three different approaches to answer this question. Bettelheim answers the question from a psychological perspective, and Zipes looks at the history of their dissemination as well as why fairy tales are still relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not a fan of these readings, however. They were extremely Eurocentric and never addressed this. Out of necessity, the history portion could not include the whole world, but when discussing tales like the Native American fable, &lt;em&gt;The Turkey Girl&lt;/em&gt;, this should be noted. Why do non-western variations on Cinderella get published, when they are often a minor and local folktale in the cultures they supposedly represent? Why don’t we learn about the folktales that are actually popular and important to their cultural identity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the readings did not address the modern mass media’s role in spreading fairy tales, or fairy tale-like stories. Because of Disney movies and their associated merchandising, many people interpret Mulan as a fairy tale, but she was a living historical figure and the fantastical elements of the movie were merely tacked on. Is it disrespectful to group such a story with the other Disney princesses, who often lack agency and character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Disney continues to reinterpret and adapt stories from different cultures, these questions will continue to be on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><summary>Why are fairy tales popular? In the selected readings for Fairy Tales for the 21st Century this week, Bettelheim and Zipes take three different approaches to answer this question. Bettelheim answers the question from a psychological perspective, and Zipes looks at the history of their dissemination as well as why fairy tales are still relevant today.</summary></entry><entry><title>Cassandra, A Modern Myth</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cassandra, A Modern Myth" /><published>2017-01-29T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-29T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/29/cassandra/">&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, there was a woman named Cassandra. She worked for a multinational oil company– you know their name but for legal purposes, it cannot be included in this story– and reached a fairly high position in the company. She had worked very hard to get this job, and was very proud of the fact. She was also very beautiful, and many people whispered that she had gotten her job because of it. She was not very proud of this fact. She disliked her natural beauty, as it distracted people from her intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, her coworker– who we will call Apollo, but for legal purposes, his real name must be omitted– revealed to her some secrets of the company. They were very dangerous secrets, and Cassandra was appalled. Many people would die because of these secrets. Apollo then expected Cassandra to sleep with him in exchange for these secrets. Cassandra was appalled. She refused, and Apollo cursed her and skulked away. Everyone believed she had slept with him though, as she was very beautiful and that is just what beautiful women do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra decided to go to her boss with the secrets, but he laughed at her and came onto her. She refused him, as she usually does, as it was a habit of his to harass her. This time, though, she reported her boss and Apollo to their company’s HR department. They did nothing with her report. She was very beautiful, so what did she expect? Men were going to try to seduce her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra then tried to report the company’s abhorrent secrets to the government, but even they would not believe her. She seemed like such an airhead, and the secrets didn’t seem possible. Besides, the government had a very good relationship with the oil company, and who would want to ruin that to investigate what were likely lies from some bimbo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cassandra tried then to go to the press with the secrets, but even though the newspaper was sympathetic, they did not have the budget to handle the legal case against a big, multinational company. The secrets were probably not true anyways. But they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole process wore Cassandra down, and she eventually gave up on trying to expose her company. She could not stand staying at the company, however, and was fired after snapping at her boss during another bout of sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years later, the company’s secrer deeds were revealed by a man. There was a lot of outrage, and a lot of deaths were caused by the company. A few people were fired, but they received large severance checks and left to join another multinational firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what happened to Cassandra. I think she became a housewife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The End&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><category term="cassandra" /><category term="greek mythology" /><category term="the fall of troy" /><summary>Once upon a time, there was a woman named Cassandra. She worked for a multinational oil company– you know their name but for legal purposes, it cannot be included in this story– and reached a fairly high position in the company. She had worked very hard to get this job, and was very proud of the fact. She was also very beautiful, and many people whispered that she had gotten her job because of it. She was not very proud of this fact. She disliked her natural beauty, as it distracted people from her intelligence.</summary></entry><entry><title>Cinderella, Enchanted</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cinderella, Enchanted" /><published>2017-01-28T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-28T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/28/cinderella/">&lt;p&gt;There are a great number of versions of Cinderella. Some are retellings of the story for a modern audience; some are similar stories from different cultures rebranded as a multicultural version of Cinderella. The version I’ll be focusing on is &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt; by Gail Carson Levine, a young adult novel that I had loved in my youth. I read a lot of young adult fiction about princesses, but this was a particular favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt; is recognizably a fairy tale, its status as a variation on Cinderella is relatively obscured. Most of the Cinderella plot– her father’s remarriage, the ball, and the prince’s search for Ella all occur in the back half of the novel. Instead, the inciting action of the novel is a curse placed on Ella at her birth: a fairy gave her the gift of obedience, and she consequentially cannot disobey any order given to her. She attempts to find the fairy to take this curse back, and encounters and gets to know Prince Charming while she is on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes give Ella more character and make it more of a feminist text than the original fairy tale: giving Ella this curse rationalizes why she acts as servant to her stepmother and stepsisters, as she has no choice but to follow their orders. She is no longer meek and docile, no longer leaving her fate to chance– when she does, it’s because she hasn’t a choice. Meeting Prince Charming and falling in love with him throughout the novel erases a problem many feminists have with fairy tales. Prince Charming does not fall in love merely because Ella is beautiful, but because of her funny and headstrong character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other changes do erase some of the hallmarks of the Cinderella story. To explain why a fairy would come to bless Ella– and to explain why she would encounter the prince in her everyday life– Ella’s family is turned to nobility, instead of that of a mere merchant. Because Ella has already gotten to know the prince, the motif of the glass slipper is minimized, but the prince does have to search for Ella as she has gone into hiding after their dance. Much of the remaining motifs do remain in tact, however; for instance, Ella has a fairy godmother who enchants household objects to bring her to the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the novel that does not concern the core Cinderella story develops Ella’s character, bringing her to boarding school and giving her friends and allies. It also has themes not contained within the original fairy tale– free will and choice, obviously, are ruminated on much more than in Cinderella, and class issues are explored beyond how nice it must be to marry a prince. The primary lesson of Cinderella is still preserved in &lt;em&gt;Ella Enchanted&lt;/em&gt;, however– live your life morally and with grace, and you will be rewarded for it ultimately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><category term="cinderella" /><category term="ella enchanted" /><summary>There are a great number of versions of Cinderella. Some are retellings of the story for a modern audience; some are similar stories from different cultures rebranded as a multicultural version of Cinderella. The version I’ll be focusing on is Ella Enchanted by Gail Carson Levine, a young adult novel that I had loved in my youth. I read a lot of young adult fiction about princesses, but this was a particular favourite.</summary></entry><entry><title>Everything is Spatial</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything is Spatial" /><published>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-27T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/01/27/maps/">&lt;p&gt;It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned two readings: an intro to web maps and a comparison between Apple and Google Maps. As I read the comparison, I was struck by one difference between the two maps: Google prioritized transit, but Apple prioritized landmarks. This was interesting to me because a friend of mine, Jaycee, prefers Apple maps, and she happened to depend less on transit than me. I have an Android phone, so Apple maps is not an option for me, but even if it were, I doubt I would consequentially choose Apple. With IOS, Jaycee can choose from either of the two, but transit is likely less of a priority. It’s fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also assigned a little exercise we did in class, to use leaflet.js to create a quick map and apply different map tiles to it. I chose Stamen’s watercolor style, and also added a bunch of restaurants that I like to eat at near ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/leaflet/1.0.3/leaflet.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;map&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;

var layer = L.tileLayer('http://tile.stamen.com/watercolor/{z}/{x}/{y}.png', &quot;terrain&quot;, {
  attribution: 'Map tiles by &lt;a href=&quot;http://stamen.com&quot;&gt;Stamen Design&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0&quot;&gt;CC BY 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. Data by &lt;a href=&quot;http://openstreetmap.org&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright&quot;&gt;ODbL&lt;/a&gt;.'
}); 


  var map = L.map('map', {
    scrollWheelZoom: false,
    center: [40.7295, -73.9938],
    zoom: 15
  });

  map.addLayer(layer);
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.9938]).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('ITP', { permanent: true });


  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7350, -73.9930], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('La Maison du Croque Monsieur');
  L.marker([40.7297, -73.9990], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Legend West Village');
  L.marker([40.7309, -73.9903], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Ippudo');
  L.marker([40.7296, -73.9896], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Korilla');
  L.marker([40.7263, -73.9957], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('The Press Shop');
  L.marker([40.7311, -73.9933], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Maoz');
  L.marker([40.7334, -73.9879], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Trader Joe\'s');
  L.marker([40.7295, -73.999026], {opacity: 0.7}).addTo(map)
  .bindTooltip('Go Go Curry');
&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>It’s a new semester at ITP, and I have entirely new classes. My favourite so far is Everything is Spatial; long ago I had planned a web app to create travel guidebooks using web map data, so it’s totally up my alley.</summary></entry><entry><title>Putting Out Fires</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Putting Out Fires" /><published>2016-12-14T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-14T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/14/fires/">&lt;p&gt;There are some people at ITP who make beautiful, artistically fulfilling projects, and write deep and introspective blog posts to match. Their blog posts are gossiped about on the floor, “they make me want to cry. She’ll get a job through these.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not one of those people. I prefer candid and ugly posts. This will be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the blocks of words. I failed to take many photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is working, and will be presented today for Physical Computing. It is not nearly in the state I would like it to be, but it is interactive and interesting for people. It fulfills people’s fantasies, even if it doesn’t fulfill my vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many setbacks in the course of its creation. Last week, we did another round of playtesting during class. I didn’t get my hat functional in time for the class– after fabricating the hat per my previous blog post, I wired it closely to the fritzing diagram in my previous blog posts, with the concession that I didn’t buy complex wire connectors and used a small breadboard instead. After doing so, I discovered a number of problems that prevented me from a working prototype. Consequentially, the playtesting was less helpful than it should’ve been– a mishmash of advice I’d heard last time and suggestions I wouldn’t have time to implement (with a few exceptions.) I did enjoy playtesting for other people though, and I hope I gave them helpful feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people react with incredulity at how many problems I’ve encountered in a deliberately simple project– no serial communication is used whatsoever. But I had to put out many fires related to each of my electrical components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;accelerometer&quot;&gt;Accelerometer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the chief problem that prevented me from playtesting, but I’ve gotten it to a good state now. The problem with the MPU6050 I bought was that it only worked reliably when it could read very often, but I only wanted intermittent reads. It consequentially would overflow its FIFO readings or occasionally trap itself in an infinite loop. If an overflow occurred, the stored values of pitch and yaw were never updated, and then no longer valid previous readings would be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I solved this by making my read function return a boolean, and asking for a reading until the boolean was true and the values were updated. Consequentially, the common FIFO overflows would be less debilitating. I also made infinite while loops time out, so the program would never be stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the flow of the system going is very important, and I also added timeouts to responses in general, with a random assignment. Since the system doesn’t tell you the answer it recorded nor what houses it corresponds to, it seemed unlikely that anybody would care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accelerometer, despite consistently overflowing, is now one of the more reliable parts of the hat– to my great surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mp3-shield&quot;&gt;MP3 Shield&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the Adafruit MP3 Shield had a lot of problems, despite initially looking like a solid solution. Some of it was user error– at one point, I snapped off a capacitor on it and had to scramble to find someone to solder it back on for me– I couldn’t trust myself to do so with my shaky hands. But some of that was the product. When trying to get the capacitor back on, I discovered the paucity of serious documentation for Adafruit products. Where is there a data sheet on it? How do I find a replacement capacitor, if necessary, if I can’t find any information on what capacitor it is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bulk of my problems, though, were audio out related. ITP is usually very loud, so my previous estimations on speakers needed were too optimistic. The mp3 shield either outputs to speaker pins or a regular headphone jack. The speaker pins had a woefully low maximum wattage, so they couldn’t announce a house loudly like I had hoped. I thought I could wire up two sets of speakers– one for private questions near the ear and one in the mouth for announcements. The MP3 shield has a function to control volume per ear, but no function to switch between the headphone jack and speaker pins. I tried to use right and left as different sets of speakers, but that turned out staticky and sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think two sets of audio outs is a pipe dream if I want to keep the hat lightweight. Right now, I’ve decided to use the headphone jack and connect to speakers with an external power source. It’s the best solution I have for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;servos&quot;&gt;Servos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the hat’s mouth move was always a stretch goal, and not one I terribly addressed this week. I did have to adjust some expectations, though– running everything with two servos meant a serious power draw. I had to settle for one planned servo motor, if I get around to it. It’s one of the most frequently requested features, so I hope I do get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-forward&quot;&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hat is currently far from finished, and there are a few things I will work on over the weekend. I’d like to accomplish the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the hat with fabric. Hide the carrboard! A lot of people complained about it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consider privacy and broadcasting questions and answers. Wire speakers accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try to make the mouth move!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print stickers for takeaways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>There are some people at ITP who make beautiful, artistically fulfilling projects, and write deep and introspective blog posts to match. Their blog posts are gossiped about on the floor, “they make me want to cry. She’ll get a job through these.”</summary></entry><entry><title>Printing and Procrastination</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Printing and Procrastination" /><published>2016-12-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/12/07/nextlevelprocrastination/">&lt;p&gt;One way I like to procrastinate is by doing other work– no matter how trivial or unimportant it is– and pretending that doing this work is productive. This is what I’ve done for my Physical Computing Final. Instead of fabricating the hat or trying out the wiring, I decided to design the sticker takeaways for it and make brochures to help people who aren’t familiar with Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/stickers.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/stickers.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/brochure.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/brochure.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I probably should’ve spent more time wiring or fabricating because I faced a great deal of challenges later on. None of my components seem to work properly, and I’m having headaches figuring it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/size1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/size1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/size.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/size.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, including the libraries bloat my code to a great degree, so I spent time optimizing my code and making it run in less than 100% of the Uno’s memory space. I could use a Mega, but that’s money to consider. I know I can optimize, so why not? You can see the code on the github: https://github.com/metermaid/sortinghat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/speakers.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/speakers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then had problems getting the speakers to work with my mp3 shield. I might have to use the headphone jack for the playtest, since that works. I tried speakers from the shop to ensure– it’s not just my speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had a huge headache working with the accelerometer I bought. I first implemented it as is, but the data was noisy. I then implemented a Kalman filter, which didn’t work very well. Finally, I used the Arduino library by Jeff Rowling, which worked, but consistently had FIFO overflow errors. I can adjust the sizes of the buffer in the library, but this seems like a fundamental problem that isn’t my perogative. I am considering going back to the Kalman filter, or trying out an Arduino 101. I just would rather not spend the money…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And gosh, I didn’t even attempt the servos this time around. What state will I be in next week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_procrastination/hat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_procrastination/hat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, I fabricated another paper hat. He’s very witchy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>One way I like to procrastinate is by doing other work– no matter how trivial or unimportant it is– and pretending that doing this work is productive. This is what I’ve done for my Physical Computing Final. Instead of fabricating the hat or trying out the wiring, I decided to design the sticker takeaways for it and make brochures to help people who aren’t familiar with Harry Potter.</summary></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Progress</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving Progress" /><published>2016-11-26T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-26T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/26/progress/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last ten days or so visiting my brother in Alabama; consequentially, I’ve been both more and less productive than i expected. More so because there isn’t much to do here, particularly if you don’t have a car; less, because the only materials I have are whatever I brought with me. You can’t wire up a component you don’t have, and my accelerometer didn’t arrive at ITP before my flight to Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I left ITP, though, I managed to solder my MP3 shield. It was the first time I’d ever soldered anything– to the best of my knowledge, my brother said we soldered in eighth grade shop class. I made some mistakes, but it’s not so scary to me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/soldering.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/soldering.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote pseudocode and then Arduino code for the sorting hat. I don’t know if any of this will work at all, though, because I hadn’t been able to wire anything up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;void loop
  if button pressed
    start questioning
  end
end
void questioning
  play preamble
  scramble questions
  start variables
  
  for each question
    play question
    while no_response
      if longenoughtime
        play canthearyou
      end
    end
    if response == nod
      variables++
    else response == shake
     variables++
    end
    if endstate
      break
    else
         playnoise(random)
    end
   play houseName(variables)
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/metermaid/sortinghat&quot;&gt;Arduino code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; which is a practice I need to get back into– I weirdly don’t associate pcomp projects with “real” code that warrants version control. This is an attitude I need to mend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lieu of actual wiring, I created a fritzing sketch of my board. I’m not sure if I like fritzing– it’s somewhat helpful to see a visual representation of how to wire, but it’s much easier to represent most things with schematics. From here on out, I may just do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/fritzing.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/fritzing.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I updated my timeline with estimates of what I’ve completed. Earlier I had assumed I was done with recording lines, but now I think I need to record a few more. It’s hard to come up with questions for that hat, though. I’m also likely overestimating how finished I am with the coding, but I’m gonna let myself have my optimism before my flight back to New York and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_thanksgiving/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_thanksgiving/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>I’ve spent the last ten days or so visiting my brother in Alabama; consequentially, I’ve been both more and less productive than i expected. More so because there isn’t much to do here, particularly if you don’t have a car; less, because the only materials I have are whatever I brought with me. You can’t wire up a component you don’t have, and my accelerometer didn’t arrive at ITP before my flight to Birmingham.</summary></entry><entry><title>Playtest and Planning</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playtest and Planning" /><published>2016-11-13T14:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T14:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/finalplans/">&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, we did some play tests of prototypes for our Physical Computing final. I didn’t think I would learn that much, but play tests will often surprise you. I constructed a prototype by wetfolding some Trader Joe’s paper bags– it looked rather good in my opinion. I also made myself a hat; as the McGonagall of my demo I should be similarly outfitted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/hats.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/hats.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a script out, and recorded some lines with Nate. There were around 15 questions to ask, and preamble to go with them as well. I then created a JavaScript soundboard for my questions– it’s a hi-tech lo-fi prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/questions.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/questions.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-play-test&quot;&gt;The Play test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some questions in mind going into the play test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this take too long? Was there too many questions?
Do you know to just put it on? Do you find nodding and shaking your head intuitive?
Are you mad if you get a result you don’t agree with?
Did you want to talk about yourself in a freeform manner?
Would you enjoy watching other people get sorted? Would you get bored if they have the same questions?
Do you want your house announced to the world, like the books and movies, or should it be a private experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions and more were answered by my helpful play testers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/jennyhat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/jennyhat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how cute this is! The playtesters are cute and smart as well, providing me with some helpful feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/feedback.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/feedback.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the play test I learned the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contrary to my assumptions, people really enjoyed answering yes or no questions about themselves and didnt find it tedious. In fact, most people felt they could’ve answered more than the seven or so questions I gave them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nodding and head shaking were intuitive, for the most part– one person shook their head in an unexpected way. Since the hat will be supervised the whole time, I can probably just monitor and correct people who do it wrong, but I should be cognizant of this and adjust the accelerator as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speech recognition would be nice, but holy cow– it gets loud when the room is full of people talking. My tiny phone speaker had to be held up to ears just to be heard. Speech recognition for the Arduino is consequentially unfeasible, and, since people liked the nodding, not necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also, my original concept that the hat would accept freeform responses would be scrapped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of people don’t know Harry Potter, or have forgotten the houses (the remaining people remember, and are very opinionated about them!) I should put up flags or posters to remind people of the idea, and perhaps integrate it into the hat. Maybe the hat could the song from the books, but that might take a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People wanted to watch others get sorted, but didn’t want others to hear their questions and responses. They wanted some privacy. This takes care of my concerns about it being boring to watch repeated questions, but it might be boring to watch the silent questioning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They totally wanted the houses to be loudly announced. They also wanted cloaks. If I go all in on theatricality, they may forgive other flaws of the hat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;planning&quot;&gt;Planning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My description from the last blog post hardly needed updating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is a loving recreation of a magical object in the world of the Harry Potter series. In the books, the hat reads your mind to determine which of four school houses you have the most affinity for. In real life, we are unable to read minds, so the Sorting Hat asks you a series of questions and determines your house based on your responses. Physically, it is an anthropomorphic hat that beckons you to put it on. Once on your head, it will guide you through a series of yes or no questions to which you will respond with nods or head shakes. The hat will then decide your house, which it will announce loudly, and you can enjoy a sense of belonging and delight at this talking hat’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my timeline certainly needed some new information and simplification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/timeline.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created a system diagram of sorts– I’m calling it a hat-user story diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/sortingtime.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/sortingtime.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this information in mind, I created an initial bill of materials. It’s all a lot pricier than I had anticipated, and this is without the speaker / voice recognition that I had originally planned on. The servos I’ll probably be able to borrow for free, but maybe I should just have servos on hand. You’ll never know when they’ll come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pc_plan/bom.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;pc_plan/bom.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><summary>Last Thursday, we did some play tests of prototypes for our Physical Computing final. I didn’t think I would learn that much, but play tests will often surprise you. I constructed a prototype by wetfolding some Trader Joe’s paper bags– it looked rather good in my opinion. I also made myself a hat; as the McGonagall of my demo I should be similarly outfitted!</summary></entry><entry><title>Nicki and Harry</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicki and Harry" /><published>2016-11-13T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/13/nicki/">&lt;p&gt;I love Nicki Minaj. I’ve been a fan of hers for a long time; longer than even her jaw-dropping feature in Kanye West’s “Monster”, which was mentioned in the Radiolab episode, “Straight Outta Chevy Chase”, which we listened to for Fandom this week. Consequently, I had the same reaction as her to Rosenberg’s comments that were cited in the podcast– who are you to question whether her tracks are hip hop enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a question that pairs nicely with last week’s discussion on Authenticity, and one loaded with implications about class, race and gender as well. Radiolab directed its questions mostly about race, but I felt that gender was insufficiently addressed– Minaj herself questioned that in particular, and Rosenberg’s comments were often gendered unfairly. Pop music is often assumed to be the domain of teenage girls, and in Rosenberg’s complaints about “Starships”, the teenage girl became code for a lack of savviness about hip-hop. His comment, “I know there’s some chicks here waiting to sing ‘Starships’ later, I’m not talking to y’all right now, fuck that bullshit.” is an example of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Minaj and Rosenberg are outsiders in hiphop– Minaj for her gender and Rosenberg for his race and class– and they both get questioned about this. Who are they to present themselves as authorities on the subject? Don’t fans know better than them? This may be an example of Fandom Gone Wrong, our next subject for class. Our other reading this week handles more clear cut examples of this for Harry Potter. “Consumer Tribes: Harry Potter and the Fandom Menace” discusses a great many topics, chiefly the myth making of Harry Potter and how fandom has affected the publications of these books. In truth, I thought it was the worst reading we’ve done all class; it’s poorly written and overly obsessed with puns. It does bring up several good points, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Harry Potter creation myth that it spread through word of mouth is false– there was a concentrated marketing campaign in schools. Secondly, J.K. Rowling encouraged a sort of anti-marketing and fans were able to band together under the banner of being looked down upon by the mass media. Thirdly, fans are fans of the fan object, and not necessarily the fan object owner, and can and have turned on Rowling at any time. They criticize her work– I have myself, with her creations of international magical schools– and encourage poor writing in an effort to get new books as fast as possible. Editors are less willing to edit books that they know will be bestsellers anyways. It’s also tough when, as a writer, you must focus on fan management as well as your core duties of writing. Managing a fan object is a tough job, especially when it opens yourself up to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>I love Nicki Minaj. I’ve been a fan of hers for a long time; longer than even her jaw-dropping feature in Kanye West’s “Monster”, which was mentioned in the Radiolab episode, “Straight Outta Chevy Chase”, which we listened to for Fandom this week. Consequently, I had the same reaction as her to Rosenberg’s comments that were cited in the podcast– who are you to question whether her tracks are hip hop enough?</summary></entry><entry><title>Final</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final" /><published>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T13:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/11/09/final/">&lt;p&gt;It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sorting Hat is a loving recreation of a magical object in the world of the Harry Potter series. In the books, the hat reads your mind to determine which of four school houses you have the most affinity for. In real life, we are unable to read minds, so the Sorting Hat asks you a series of questions and determines your house based on your responses. Physically, it is an anthropomorphic hat that beckons you to put it on. Once on your head, it will guide you through a series of yes or no questions to which you will respond with nods or words. The hat will then decide your house, which it will announce loudly, and you can enjoy a sense of belonging and delight at this talking hat’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/finaltimeline1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;finaltimeline1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="pcomp final" /><category term="final" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>It was incredibly hard to focus on school today– the election results had come out. Still, I’ll make an attempt at describing my final, an effort that is made easier by having a pre-existing property to work off of. I also mocked up an initial timeline, which you can see below. I had some stretch goals that i optimistically thought I could manage, but now that I see the timeline, realize they aren’t reasonable at all. Still, I include them for hope’s sake.</summary></entry></feed>
