<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-24T16:07:36-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Typefaces</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Typefaces" /><published>2016-09-24T05:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T05:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/24/typefaces/">&lt;p&gt;For visual language, I had to pick six typefaces to represent me. Here are my picks, along with a short explanation of why I chose them.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces01.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces01.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces02.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces02.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces03.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces03.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces04.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces04.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces05.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces05.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces06.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces06.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are all the picks together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/typefaces07.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/typefaces07.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had to make some “expressive” words. I decided that I wanted my set of three to be visual consistent and part of the same theme. I briefly considered continuing this set of tech with scanners and routers, but I’m pretty lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/type/wordart.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;type/wordart.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><summary>For visual language, I had to pick six typefaces to represent me. Here are my picks, along with a short explanation of why I chose them.</summary></entry><entry><title>Switches</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switches" /><published>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/switches/">&lt;p&gt;I think most people in PComp this week was confused as to what we were supposed to document. There are a few labs assigned, but some of those are just looking at your electronic components. Do we respond to the readings? Tom Igoe’s class, apparently, has to do this. I chose to document the switch lab, since that one was fun.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Here’s a video of that first one. It’s very short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cm7eB3OsBgI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are shots of two other parts of the switch lab.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I have a video of the last part, because it was the most complicated part of the lab. I am clearly excellent at elucidating my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0X5cKt8o8dg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did a creative switch, or an attempt at it– I wired my book to turn the LED on when it was opened or closed. I had grand designs for using graphite to do a switch drawing, but I forgot my graphite sticks at home and had to steal lead from Koji. I’m sorry Koji. The drawing wasn’t enough drawn to conduct electricity. On Wednesday, I tried with the graphite sticks, but the payoff of graphite on the page still didn’t conduct electricity. The lead stick in itself conducted pretty well.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/switches/switch5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;switches/switch5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-a_-eWLjP-4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The readings were very lengthy this week, and honestly kind of confusing. I had to google “affect don norman” to figure out exactly what Don Norman meant when he referred to “affect”, because he never defined it in his piece about it. In my understanding, he contrasts cognition with affect: cognition is conscious thought and interpretation of the world, whereas affect is unconscious judgement of the world. I’m not sure if this is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I felt a bit of shame with his precise definition of affordance, since I used that word in my last pcomp blog post in the sense used by graphic designers that he derides. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><category term="physical computing" /><summary>I think most people in PComp this week was confused as to what we were supposed to document. There are a few labs assigned, but some of those are just looking at your electronic components. Do we respond to the readings? Tom Igoe’s class, apparently, has to do this. I chose to document the switch lab, since that one was fun.

Here’s a video of that first one. It’s very short.

And here are shots of two other parts of the switch lab.


I have a video of the last part, because it was the most complicated part of the lab. I am clearly excellent at elucidating my thoughts.

I also did a creative switch, or an attempt at it– I wired my book to turn the LED on when it was opened or closed. I had grand designs for using graphite to do a switch drawing, but I forgot my graphite sticks at home and had to steal lead from Koji. I’m sorry Koji. The drawing wasn’t enough drawn to conduct electricity. On Wednesday, I tried with the graphite sticks, but the payoff of graphite on the page still didn’t conduct electricity. The lead stick in itself conducted pretty well.



The readings were very lengthy this week, and honestly kind of confusing. I had to google “affect don norman” to figure out exactly what Don Norman meant when he referred to “affect”, because he never defined it in his piece about it. In my understanding, he contrasts cognition with affect: cognition is conscious thought and interpretation of the world, whereas affect is unconscious judgement of the world. I’m not sure if this is correct.</summary></entry><entry><title>A Star Trek Pilgrimage</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/startrek/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Star Trek Pilgrimage" /><published>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/startrek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/startrek/">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, I went on a fan pilgrimage with Patrick Presto– we took a trip to the Paley Center to visit their new exhibition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paleycenter.org/transported-paley-center-salutes-50-years-of-star-trek&quot;&gt;“Transported: Paley Center Salutes 50 Years of Star Trek”&lt;/a&gt;. Although I have many friends who are Trekkies, I’ve never been one for the series myself. I’ve seen two of the new movies (and don’t like them very much) and a handful of episodes from the Next Generation, but to call me a fan would be a stretch. I’m reasonably capable of pretending to be a fan– Presto accused me of being one after I recognized a Tribble– but genuine fandom is beyond me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new TV series coming out, though, I’m somewhat interested in being a fan– Bryan Fuller will be the showrunner, and I’m a big fan of his work. I thought it would be a good time to immerse myself in some Trek fandom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Paley Center’s celebration encompassed more or less every type of fan activity, but we would take part of only a few. The bulk of the exhibit revolved around content making: the Paley had 50 pieces of fan art on display on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/startrek/exhibit.jpg&quot; height=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;5312&quot; alt=&quot;startrek/exhibit.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids who visit the Paley could take part in Star Trek related arts and crafts: we walked by some kids creating Trek hand puppets out of paper bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/startrek/paperbags1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;startrek/paperbags1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Paley also had some evangelization events: not necessarily of Trek specifically– being a fan of Trek is almost assumed of its visitors– but we narrowly missed a roundtable discussion of which Trek captain is the best. That’s classic fan evangelization for each Trek captain. Although no rituals were created at the exhibit– as far as I knew– rituals were sustained during it, including the classic greetings of the Vulcan salute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Paley, as any museum would, also had a Trek-related gift shop. Presto and I failed to buy anything. No performative consumption was done; no posters were signed by the artists present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than anything else, though, the Paley exhibition was a pilgrimage, and a pilgrimage we went on. We have the pictures and video to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5NP51vBiyHk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is apparently a boomarang. I don’t understand apps nowadays.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observing all of the fan art in general did not trigger very many fan feelings in itself– I didn’t think that Trek fandom was a utopia, nor did I feel belonging. I sensed a bit of social hierarchy within the fan group: fans who could produce such art are at the top of the social chain and I, mere mortal, appear below them. Observing the credit panels for the fan art triggered a different feeling though: the classic Trek feelings of utopia came about, because the fan artists came from all sorts of backgrounds and from everywhere in the world. Anybody could be a Trekkie, and they could all belong in this gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/startrek/coolspock.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;startrek/coolspock.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t feel belonging though, so I tried to engage in a bit of socialization by talking to people in the gallery about some of the art (as well as Patrick, but since we were both outside observers it didn’t feel like a fan interaction.) What did people think of the art? Could they please explain this cryptic art to me? Nobody was able to explain the vulcan head giving birth to a baby vulcan to me (I unfortunately neglected to take pictures of this), so I didn’t feel fanlike feelings about this socialization. Just discomfort about a fan culture that could produce such art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the kids making their paper bag puppets felt like a utopia again. There was a lot of mixed feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick and I then attended a session to teach the audience how to speak Klingon– engaging in a mass attempt at impersonation. A speaker from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kli.org/&quot;&gt;Klingon Language Institute&lt;/a&gt;, Elizabeth Lawrence Faber, handed out pamphlets on Klingon grammar and taught us some of the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/startrek/klingon.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;startrek/klingon.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried earnestly to pronounce some of the words, but couldn’t produce the guttural noises despite my efforts. I honestly felt like I didn’t belong: people, including a particularly clever little boy, would ask insightful questions about Klingon and Trek that wouldn’t have occurred to me to ask. They’d pronounce things better than I could, and overall seemed more engaged– Patrick and I were both falling asleep during parts of the session. Plus, the introductory video was far from utopic nor welcoming: it was footage of Klingons spying on the Federation, and doing ill (as far as I could tell.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, at the end of the session, I felt the social stigma deeply: our instructor ended by trying to lead us in singing a Klingon lullaby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8UzuZxh1caM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was awkward. Nobody else was confident enough in their Klingon to try it, and she wasn’t singing on tune. Ending with this session left my visit on a sour note: I thought Trek was sorta cool during the fanart, but the Klingon lesson just reminded me of the time and effort that I could not see myself devoting to the fandom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/startrek/cereal.jpg&quot; height=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The cereal was cool, though.&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;startrek/cereal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cereal was cool, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="fandom" /><summary>On Saturday, I went on a fan pilgrimage with Patrick Presto– we took a trip to the Paley Center to visit their new exhibition, “Transported: Paley Center Salutes 50 Years of Star Trek”. Although I have many friends who are Trekkies, I’ve never been one for the series myself. I’ve seen two of the new movies (and don’t like them very much) and a handful of episodes from the Next Generation, but to call me a fan would be a stretch. I’m reasonably capable of pretending to be a fan– Presto accused me of being one after I recognized a Tribble– but genuine fandom is beyond me.</summary></entry><entry><title>Hiroshima, Mon Amour Poster Analysis</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/hiroshima/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiroshima, Mon Amour Poster Analysis" /><published>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T17:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/hiroshima</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/17/hiroshima/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/hiroshima.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The original poster by Boris Grisson&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/hiroshima.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiroshima, Mon Amour&lt;/em&gt; was a 1959 French film directed by Alain Resnais. It’s one of my favourite films, and highly influential in world cinema: it influenced the later French New Wave with its nonlinear storyline and its innovative use of flashbacks. Moreover, it’s just a lovely film about the shortcomings of memories and dealing with personal– and not personal– tragedy. The original poster was designed by Boris Grisson, a prolific Russian-French designer who designed over 2000 French film posters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;colour&quot;&gt;Colour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/colour1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/colour1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grisson’s posters were designed to be printed as lithographs, a printing technique in which the artist etches several stone blocks (using oils) and then flat colour is applied to the block, which is then used to produce a print on paper. Each colour would have its own stone block (or else would be applied by hand); consequentially, many lithographs have limited colour palettes. This poster is no exception to this. Although I have highlighted five separate colours here, it is more likely that only two or three inks were applied to this lithograph: a red, a black, and perhaps a soft peach (the brown is likely produced by combining the red and black.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall colour scheme is soft and evokes melancholy; a perfect fit for a film about memory. The red invokes passion and the idea of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/colour2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/colour2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This poster is also effectively produced using cheaper printing techniques; here, the print is cheaply created using only two types of ink: red and black. This variation is effective in its own way: the strong red on the white paper looks like the Japanese flag, and also looks like a splash of blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;typefaces&quot;&gt;Typefaces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/typefaces.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/typefaces.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This poster was created before even phototypesetting was popular, so the letterforms aren’t very consistent– it’s hard to identify what precise typefaces are used here. The type was likely traced, cut out, or stamped by hand. What is clear is that there are two typefaces used: a slab serif for the title, and a geometric sans-serif for all the other copy. The first is used sparingly, with only one bold-weight variation. The latter appears as both medium and bold weight and in condensed and regular forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;Grid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/grid.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/grid.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, a grid was likely not used in the design of this poster. The main image is painted, and there isn’t a lot of typography; the grid was primarily used at the time for things with more copy or from stricter schools of graphic design. That isn’t to say there isn’t alignment and order in the image; the title was likely aligned with the back of the man’s head and the top of his pants; the addition of the top left box (that proclaims the film a two-time winner at Cannes) is aligned with his hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/ruleofthirds.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/ruleofthirds.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rule of thirds applies, more or less, though. The woman’s face and the title are placed at thirds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-hierarchy-and-whitespace&quot;&gt;Visual Hierarchy and Whitespace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiroshima/arrows.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;hiroshima/arrows.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red splash in the background directs the eye. Without it, it would be harder to determine the positive space’s visual hierarchy; the whitespace is otherwise a bit formless. The splash directs you from the top left corner to the couple at the center and then finally, the movie’s title and the credits copy. A separate hierarchy occurs with the woman’s gaze and the award-touting box. You start at her gaze, and it drives you towards the left and the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the poster creates a compelling story of Japan, melancholy, and a hesitant couple. I think it’s fairly effective design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="visual language" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Interactivity</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/interactivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interactivity" /><published>2016-09-13T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/interactivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/interactivity/">&lt;p&gt;Comic books, for the most part, are not interactive mediums. Usually, reading them is just a series of one-sided actions and reactions: you read a comic book, and you respond emotionally to its static contents. The comic remains unmoved by your actions; it never responds to anything in your circumstance. There are occasional exceptions to this, however: if you send the publisher fan mail, and it is published, that may arguably be an interaction. You read the comic, respond with mail, and the writer or editor publishes your letter and a response. Of course, this doesn’t actually effect the body of the comic, only the back pages and extras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more concrete example of interactivity occurs when a comic writer designs their story around it: famously in 1988, Jason Todd, the Robin at the time to Batman, was put in a life-or-death situation, and DC decided to leave his fate up to a fan vote. You would call one number to save his life; call the other to let the Joker kill him. DC had expected fans to save Jason. They’d planned more stories around him, and didn’t imagine that fans could be so cold-blooded. Instead, the fans narrowly decided to let him die, and the publisher decided to go through with the fans’ decision. They couldn’t use their planned stories, and this death had negative repercussions to the Batman character and comic for years thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You read the comic book, you voted, and the comic’s story changed based on the results of that vote. That’s an interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More precisely, interaction is a back and forth between two or more things, or, in the words of Chris Crawford, “a cyclic process in which two actors alternately listen, think, and speak.” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Interactivity can then be subdivided into digital and physical interactions. But where do we draw the line between these two categories? What is physical interaction? Where should we put edge cases, like augmented realities and check-in spaces?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, there isn’t a need to make these kinds of interactions a strict categorization. Things can exist on a continuum: digital, physical, or somewhere in between. Interactions are more digital when they primarily involve objects that are intangible; they are more physical when they have physical or tactile components. Using a theremin is more of a digital phenomena than playing an electric guitar, but they are both electronic instruments. Both are considerably more physical than playing music on a digital soundboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is somewhat akin to how Crawford asserts that interaction itself can be measured in degrees and on a continuum.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Everything is shades of grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good interaction can be found when the interaction uses intuitive controls and gives you proper feedback for your actions. This may mean the affordances are natural to what a user already knows: for instance, a Wacom pen tablet’s controls are in line with how people use non-digital writing utensils. You press down for more pressure; write at an angle to change the shape of your line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a design can be successful even if it is completely out of sync with what one knows: returning to the theremin, the control scheme is completely out of line with what a typical person knows about playing music. However, the music sounds completely otherworldly, so the otherworldly control scheme is in line with expectations. Additionally, feedback is real time and can be instantly be heard, it is still successful at helping people play music.  It may be poor interaction, on some level, but a good design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, good design makes good use of affordances, but they are not interactive and give no feedback. A good example of this are real-time bus and subway countdown estimates. You don’t interact with them in any way; your actions do not affect the subway countdown. However, they’re great design by using your pre-existing expectations about subway timetables and signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the theremin, many designers today excel at the feedback portion, but fail at using existing affordances. In a long rant&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Bret Victor rails against the vision of the future that is screen-based– this fails to make use of thousands of years of developing physical affordances. An ideal interaction makes use of both existing affordances and also delivers feedback for your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Crawford, Chris. &lt;em&gt;The Art of Interactive Design: A Euphonious and Illuminating Guide to Building Successful Software&lt;/em&gt;, June 2002. San Francisco: No Starch, 2002. pp 3. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Crawford, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Interactive Design&lt;/em&gt;, pp 6. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Victor, Bret. &lt;em&gt;A Brief Rant on the Future of Interaction Design&lt;/em&gt;, November 2011. &lt;a href=&quot;http://worrydream.com/ABriefRantOnTheFutureOfInteractionDesign/&quot;&gt;http://worrydream.com/ABriefRantOnTheFutureOfInteractionDesign/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="itp" /><category term="pcomp" /><summary>Comic books, for the most part, are not interactive mediums. Usually, reading them is just a series of one-sided actions and reactions: you read a comic book, and you respond emotionally to its static contents. The comic remains unmoved by your actions; it never responds to anything in your circumstance. There are occasional exceptions to this, however: if you send the publisher fan mail, and it is published, that may arguably be an interaction. You read the comic, respond with mail, and the writer or editor publishes your letter and a response. Of course, this doesn’t actually effect the body of the comic, only the back pages and extras.</summary></entry><entry><title>A Fandom Timeline</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/fandom-timeline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Fandom Timeline" /><published>2016-09-13T00:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/fandom-timeline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/13/fandom-timeline/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fandom_timeline.png&quot; title=&quot;big nerding&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;fandom_timeline.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week for my fandom class, I created this timeline of past fan loves of my past. It took more time than I expected– what merited inclusion? What categories were too broad? Was there anything I was too embarrassed to include? (A definite “yes” on that last count, which is interesting. Next week is supposed to be about class dynamics of fandom, which should address this shame. Is my shame stemming from the class signifiers of these fandoms? Are subcultures necessarily indicative of class?) I did my best to track how my interests grew and faded, but I did less good of a job with how they scaled relative to each either– it was hard to keep track of them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also read two pieces this week: &lt;em&gt;Loving Music: Listeners, Entertainments, and the Origins of Music Fandom in Nineteenth-Century America&lt;/em&gt;, which detailed the fandom for musical performances in the 19th century, and &lt;em&gt;Shooter Boys and At-Risk Girls&lt;/em&gt;, a reflection by Molly Crabapple about being an “at-risk girl” in the 1990s. What struck me about these readings was the idea of how gender intersects with fandom– &lt;em&gt;Loving Music&lt;/em&gt; prominently featured the story of Lucy Lowell, a 19th century opera fan, and &lt;em&gt;Shooter Boys&lt;/em&gt; recounts the personal history of Crabapple. Although both pieces do address other genders, and there are certainly male fans out there, there are current discrepancies that make me wonder about the gender representation of fans throughout time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, it’s little studied and demographic studies do not generally exist, but many fandom communities feel like they are primarily women. Some of the most prominent examples of fanfiction have been written for and by women: Fifty Shades of Grey started as fanfiction, Wide Sargasso Sea is essentially Jane Eyre fanfic, and the term Mary Sue was coined for a notorious type of Star Trek original character that was a clear stand-in for the (female) author. Does being a part of fandom hold particular appeal to women? Or is it just certain fandom activities, and not just fandom in general? Perhaps certain fandom communities? Is anonymity a factor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to address these questions without doing more reading. My current hypotheses: the appeal of fandom isn’t gendered, but certain communities and activities are. Online fanwork communities are dominated by women– they are a safe place to find an audience and get feedback anonymously. It’s hard to address these questions without doing more reading; perhaps I’ll return to the topic at a further date.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>New Start: Redux</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/10/itp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Start: Redux" /><published>2016-09-10T19:01:35-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-10T19:01:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/10/itp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2016/09/10/itp/">&lt;p&gt;I need to restart this blog again for ITP…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><summary>I need to restart this blog again for ITP…</summary></entry><entry><title>Duck-Sized Horses</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2015/02/06/duck-sized-horses/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Duck-Sized Horses" /><published>2015-02-06T18:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2015-02-06T18:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2015/02/06/duck-sized-horses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2015/02/06/duck-sized-horses/">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I filled in a job questionnaire that included the infamous Reddit question, “Would you rather fight 100 duck sized horses or 1 horse sized duck?” I promptly chose the horses, but I didn’t get an interview. Perhaps they were duck people? My reasoning is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d fight the 100 duck-sized horses. In first year, I attended the University of Waterloo, where geese were well-known to follow and attack students– I learned a healthy amount of respect and fear for waterfowl. While the horses have the advantage of number and greater intelligence than the duck [they can gang up and will take longer than one hit to kill], they are also easily spooked and it should be fairly easy to break them up into smaller groups (and capture with nets or pillow cases if available). All of their muscle is in the upper legs, so shattering their miniaturized and spindly lower limbs should not take too much effort. The two primary weapons of horses, kicks and bites, are mitigated by the miniaturization– and furthermore, they are herbivores, so they do not have any intrinsic motivation to bite me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, ducks are omnivores and the direct descendants of dinosaurs, so the giant duck would likely try to eat me. They have ridges on their beaks that resemble teeth, and horse-proportioned, they would easily be able to break bones, shatter skulls, and destroy any weapon I could use on it. Although it would not likely be able to fly at that size, their wings will still be powerful and likely to kill me with one hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the tiny hooves of 100 duck-sized horses would make for a great back massage and tiny horses would make for excellent christmas and birthday presents for friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><summary>Recently, I filled in a job questionnaire that included the infamous Reddit question, “Would you rather fight 100 duck sized horses or 1 horse sized duck?” I promptly chose the horses, but I didn’t get an interview. Perhaps they were duck people? My reasoning is below:</summary></entry><entry><title>I Was a Teenage Web Developer</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/15/i-was-a-teenage-web-developer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Was a Teenage Web Developer" /><published>2014-08-15T16:02:40-04:00</published><updated>2014-08-15T16:02:40-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/15/i-was-a-teenage-web-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/15/i-was-a-teenage-web-developer/">&lt;p&gt;(*This post was originally posted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@repleats/i-was-a-teenage-web-designer-9b3f65d30d58&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, the other web designers I knew were other teenage girls. When I was 14, I attended a seminar to encourage young women to consider computer science. When I went to university, about a third of my first year CS classes were female.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any of these women could have become computer scientists. Some of them did. Many of them didn’t. So why did I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tumblr-before-tumblr&quot;&gt;Tumblr before Tumblr&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in the fifth grade when I made my first web page. It’s a typical nerd origin story: I wanted a truly unique pet page for my Neopet, and to do that, I needed to go beyond the provided templates and edit the HTML directly. I borrowed HTML books from the library, and created a webpage with a blinking black background, haphazardly placed tables, and glowing blue headers to match my electric kau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mookie.gif&quot; class=&quot;left&quot; title=&quot;RIP, Mookie3001.&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;mookie.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was beautiful. It was an eyesore. I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went on to create many more web pages. In the fifth grade alone, I also created a Neopets fan site, a personal website, and a website for my “writing”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I even volunteered to do my older brother’s Information Technology project, a Simpsons page complete with a “Who Needs the Kwik-E-Mart?” MIDI playing in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/webpages.jpg&quot; class=&quot;left&quot; title=&quot;I was 13 for the first of these images. These aren’t even half of the websites I made. I was a weirdly productive little teenager.&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;1350&quot; alt=&quot;webpages.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By high school, I was creating so many websites I can scarcely remember them all now. I begged my mother to use her credit card so I can buy my own domain name. I honed my skills in HTML, CSS, and PHP. Most importantly, I discovered communities of like-minded teenage web designers— a few in person, but mostly online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can find hardly any trace of these communities left on the modern internet. Trips to the Internet Archive are my primary reassurance that they weren’t a figment of my imagination. The modern equivalent of these communities would be Tumblr: they both connect like-minded, introverted teenagers with blogs, tutorial websites, and maybe a website for screen captures of favourite TV Shows. As part of those communities, we learned HTML, CSS, graphic design skills, and maybe some PHP.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We linked each other in blog rolls and talked to each other on phpBB/XMB forums. I was a member of the pixel-art-filled Dodo’s Message Board.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Being a part of DMB helped me learn some new skills, get aid when I needed it, and made me feel a little less alone in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I was making these websites, I decided to take the Information Technology class in high school and even asked to be bumped to the next grade’s offering of it. I was isolated as the only girl in a room full of older boys. I coded rudimentary C++, made my web pages, and retreated into my blogs and message boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-imperial-oil-seminar-in-computer-science-for-young-women&quot;&gt;The Imperial Oil Seminar in Computer Science for Young Women&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ninth grade, my InfoTech teacher suggested that I apply to attend the University of Waterloo’s Seminar in CS for Young Women. I filled in my application, and a few months later, I took a week off school to fly to exotic Waterloo, Ontario. It would be the first and only time I’d be in a computer lab with only other women.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a few things from this seminar. How to take apart a computer. How to program a rudimentary GUI in Tcl/Tk. What career paths you can choose with a CS degree. At this point, websites were my weird hobby, but in the future I saw in that seminar, it could be a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, I was one of the few girls referred by their InfoTech teachers— generally, they were referred by their math teachers or their guidance counsellors. It would be the first time the other girls had ever programmed, and some of these young women would go on to earn Computer Science degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t realize the impact it had on me at the time, but in retrospect, made a huge impression. Three years later, I started a degree in Computer Science at the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-waterloo&quot;&gt;My Waterloo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University was a series of firsts for me: the first time I ever lived away from home. The first time I truly loved programming, and not just web design. The first time I ever thought about quitting computer science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first year at Waterloo was lonely. Unlike most freshmen, I both lived off-campus and away from home. The university mishandled my application and, by the time they sorted it out, there wasn’t room in the dormitories for me. Nobody I knew went to Waterloo— if they headed east, it was either to Toronto or Montreal. Furthermore, in my second semester, Dodo’s Message Board shut down. I had never been so isolated in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems you face while being in a visibly marginalized group aren’t necessarily different from those of the majority,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but being marginalized can often make those same problems worse. Feeling lonely is bad for any college student. Being a minority compounds that loneliness. Getting poor grades is terrible. But when you’re the only girl and you’re getting terrible grades? You feel like that’s a sign to cut your losses and leave. Or maybe you feel extra pressure to stay: you’re the sole representative for your gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, my Operating Systems professor kicked out every student who failed the first assignment. The idea was to save students from paying the course fees: if you couldn’t understand pointers, you would probably fail the course. It would be best to wait until you did understand pointers. A friend of mine failed this assignment. The removal was intended to be a mercy, but it felt like a rejection: “You’re not smart enough for this. Get out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of leaving Computer Science, I left Waterloo and headed back to the West Coast. I went to the University of Victoria where my best friend was going to school. I wasn’t quite so alone anymore. I’ve stayed in the West Coast since, and earned my degree in Computer Science with honours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lessons&quot;&gt;Lessons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m eliding a lot of details in this origin story. I’ve retconned&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; away employment, alienation and abuses— I’m choosing which stories define me. Here’s what helped along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Availability. I’m grateful for having a computer and information technology classes. Furthermore, I’m grateful that my household had enough money that I didn’t need to work as a teenager and that I didn’t have to take care of any siblings. Around 20% of households do not have a computer at home, and some schools do not have information technology classes. There are many households where would-be computer scientists wouldn’t have time for the programming lessons advocated by Code.org. You can’t begin an outreach program with the baseline assumption that people can just make time to take part in them. We need to provide hardware and economic assistance to those who need it.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation. I’m looking at the quotes page of Code.org, and most of the reasons to start programming suggested by these leaders and celebrities are either about economic or personal development. These may not be motivating for everybody, so we can expand this list by encouraging coding as a creative outlet, mental stimulation, or just a fun activity. It’s especially useful to have intrinsic motivations when you’re marginalized. It helps keep you going when you’re burnt out and you think that you’re not good enough. When it comes down to it, I like making websites and have fun doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outreach Programs. I was already making websites by the time I attended the CS Seminar, but it helped me envision a future with Computer Science. Outreach programs are often the first time someone tries programming. They can dispel programming myths and misconceptions: I’ve known a lot of people who were discouraged from computing because they didn’t enjoy math.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Programming is a different skill though, and finding calculus dull doesn’t mean a CS degree is not for you. Outreach programs can clear that up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Support Network. Being supported by my family and having a network of other teenagers with websites were both critical to me entering this field. They were also important for discouraging me from leaving. Even introverted nerds hate feeling lonely. It helps to have someone willing to help you when you need it, and to listen carefully even when you don’t want explicit help. Sometimes, it’s nice just to talk about your problems without being questioned about them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely grateful for all the advantages I’ve had in life. I began as a teenage designer, and end here as a full-stack web developer. Truth be told, I hadn’t looked at this history in years. I suffer Impostor Syndrome and forget my past. It should be clear to me: I belong here, and women who weren’t teenage web designers belong here too. You don’t need to have a typical nerd origin story to be a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bad poetry? Oh no-etry! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Even if it was just enough to wrangle your installation of B2. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I was too intimidated to join VortexMB or fu.CK. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Being in a lab by myself or with a singular female friend doesn’t count. On the other hand, I can’t count the times when the rest of the lab is only men. I notice every time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sometimes they are though. There are abuses only marginalized people face. But that’s not what my life was like at this point. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Retroactive continuity, like in the comics, when you alter previously established history. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There are services like Free Geek for hardware, but having to pay or volunteer is still a barrier. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For the record, half my AP Calculus class were women in high school. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="me" /><summary>(*This post was originally posted to Medium.)</summary></entry><entry><title>The Ultimate Guide to General Delimited Input</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/05/the-ultimate-guide-to-general-delimited-input/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ultimate Guide to General Delimited Input" /><published>2014-08-05T16:05:25-04:00</published><updated>2014-08-05T16:05:25-04:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/05/the-ultimate-guide-to-general-delimited-input</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2014/08/05/the-ultimate-guide-to-general-delimited-input/">&lt;p&gt;Although my heart belongs to ruby, lately, I haven’t been using it at all– I’ve been working on coding tumblr the game in entirely client side JavaScript. To keep my ruby skills fresh though, I’ve been doing a reading about Ruby on the side. One topic, which I hardly gave any thought to before, has captured my attention: Ruby’s general delimited input, otherwise known as “percent literals” or “percent notation”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provenance of these macros is unknown to me. Originally, I ran across to these as “shorthand” which seemed like an odd moniker to me– they’re not at all shorter than the regular syntax. Suggestions online include that these are another of Ruby’s inscrutable Perlisms, like those weird Perl-style global variables, but the only references to them are in the context of Ruby! I can only conclude that they’ve nothing to do with Perl, and that’s a myth perpetuated by Rubyists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General delimited input notation is defined directly in MRI’s parse.y, and it’s present as far back as version 1.0 from 1996, so it’s likely just sprung from the head of Matz and not a feature cribbed from another language as some people suggest. Whatever its origins, GDI has its uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All forms of GDI come in the same basic syntax: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%(some modifier) (some delimiter) (your content) (that delimiter)&lt;/code&gt; There are six modifiers for GDI, and some of those have both interpolated and non-interpolated versions. For delimiters, you can use any non-alphanumeric symbol (in the past, you could use alphanumeric ones too, but that’s a terrible practice.) Most commonly, you’ll see people use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q{curly brackets}&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q(parentheses)&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q&amp;lt;these pointy things&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q[square brackets]&lt;/code&gt;, but you can use tildes and even quotation marks, for extra confusion. I’d advise against it, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;%W&quot;wait can you even do this?&quot;
=&amp;gt; [&quot;wait&quot;, &quot;can&quot;, &quot;you&quot;, &quot;even&quot;, &quot;do&quot;, &quot;this?&quot;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby style guides usually advocate the use of parentheses, except in the case of regular expressions, where they advocate curly brackets (since parentheses are very common in RE.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, one can use your same delimiters unescaped within the GDI, so long as you balance them. So this is fine: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q{I like braces like these:{} }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%Q{I only prefer a single brace:{ }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, you should escape that poor brace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q--q&quot;&gt;%q / %Q&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;%q is a macro for a single quote non-intepreted string, and %Q is a macro for a double quote interpreted string. Consequentially, in the former you don’t need to really escape any characters– it’s good for strings with both quotation marks. In the latter, you can use string interpolation, so it’s good for strings with both interpolation and double quotes.
If you don’t use a modifier, for example, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;%(hello)&lt;/code&gt;, it’s a shorthand for %Q.
```
%Q( Daria said, “Can you do this math?: #{1+2}” )
=&amp;gt; “ Daria said, &quot;Can you do this math?: 3&quot; “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;%q( Quinn said, “I cannot do this math: #{1+2}” )
=&amp;gt; “ Quinn said, &quot;I cannot do this math: #{1+2}&quot; “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;%( Jane said, “I can do this math: #{1+2}” )
=&amp;gt; “ Jane said, &quot;I can do this math: 3&quot; “
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
### %x
%x uses the \` method and runs its contents as a command in a subshell. Use \` unless your command contains that symbol.
&lt;/code&gt;
%x(ruby –copyright)
=&amp;gt; “ruby - Copyright (C) 1993-2014 Yukihiro Matsumoto\n”
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
### %r
%r creates an interpolated regex, but the usual syntax of `/regex/` does as well. Use it if your regex has more than one /.
&lt;/code&gt;
%r(^Adventure\s?Time$)
=&amp;gt; /^Adventure\s?Time$/
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
### %w / %W
Ruby 1.1 added %w and %W, which are likely the most common form of GDI you'll find in the wild. It's easiest to think of them as a &quot;word array&quot; or a &quot;whitespace-delimited array&quot;, if you're pedantic. It creates an array of strings as separated by the whitespace.
&lt;/code&gt;
%W( 1 2 3 4 5 #{1+5} )
=&amp;gt; [“1”, “2”, “3”, “4”, “5”, “6”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;%w( 1 2 3 4 5 #{1+5} )
=&amp;gt; [“1”, “2”, “3”, “4”, “5”, “#{1+5}”]
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
### %s
Introduced in Ruby 1.8, lord knows why this exists-- nobody really uses it. %s creates a single symbol, with whitespace in tact. One might be tempted to use it for symbols with whitespace in it, but the preferred method is by using quotes after `:`, like so: `:&quot;this works&quot;`.
&lt;/code&gt;
%s(this is useless)
=&amp;gt; :”this is useless”
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
### %i / %I
The latest modifier for GDI, introduced only in Ruby 2.0, this is the cousin to %w and %W, but instead of an array of strings, these create arrays of symbols. As usual, %i is non-interpolated and %I is interpolated.
Be warned, that the interpolated form creates an extra string on the heap for each symbol. How often do you really want an interpolated symbol, anyways?
&lt;/code&gt;
fruit = “apple”
%I(banana orange carrot #{fruit})
=&amp;gt; [:banana, :orange, :carrot, :apple]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;%i(banana orange carrot #{fruit})
=&amp;gt; [:banana, :orange, :carrot, :”#{fruit}”]
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, GDI has its pros and cons: on the one hand, you can use GDI to avoid escaping literals– if you use a lot of quotation marks and other symbols, it can be significantly less confusion to read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><summary>Although my heart belongs to ruby, lately, I haven’t been using it at all– I’ve been working on coding tumblr the game in entirely client side JavaScript. To keep my ruby skills fresh though, I’ve been doing a reading about Ruby on the side. One topic, which I hardly gave any thought to before, has captured my attention: Ruby’s general delimited input, otherwise known as “percent literals” or “percent notation”.</summary></entry></feed>
