<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-21T00:34:53-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/</id><title>Ceiling.cat</title><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><entry><title>Glitch, A Fail Story</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glitch, A Fail Story" /><published>2017-02-20T15:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T15:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/glitch/">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1BMAGmJ5jZB0V1vUPhXJMGUXjTc6IQoDoyPblylFSyAI/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=15000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><category term="glitch" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Blockchained Melody</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchained Melody" /><published>2017-02-20T06:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T06:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/20/blockchain/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought much for Bitcoin, and consequentially blockchain technologies. Anecdotally, I knew it as the currency of libertarians and drug dealers; I only knew people who used it because they needed something illegal or used our university’s power and servers to mine it. Consequentially, it was kind of interesting to read positive takes on their potential uses for charity work, though it was quite clear to me that the sources were biased towards the technology (three of the articles came from websites devoted to promoting the blockchain or a product of blockchain; the fourth was Forbes, but was not on a blockchain technology.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, one reading wasn’t too bad for the most part, but ended with the suggestion that the reader should “buy cryptocurrency.” Ridiculous. You don’t advise potential stock buyers to just buy up some stock to learn about trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I do concede that blockchain has its uses when accountability is paramount or when the local currency is unstable or otherwise unreliable, for instance, in states where inflation is out of control. I don’t really see how it can prevent corruption or crime that doesn’t involve double dealing– and even then, that supposes all the broker’s partners will be using the blockchain technology. If even one partner doesn’t, they can double deal with one blockchain partner and one that doesn’t use the technology. They’d also have to all be using the same technology. A lot of the appeal of blockchain is decentralization, but to insist on decentralization and standardization simultaneously doesn’t seem entirely feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another concern I have is how this is essentially predicated on other countries having the resources to freely mine the blockchain, which is fairly resource intensive. Isn’t it problematic to toot your own horn for paying for a South African school’s electricity when your payment required a similar sized farm in China to oversee it? Or perhaps one in Europe or America (though China is the most likely.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, I still see blockchain as largely an attempt by libertarians to sidestep the government. And buy drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article I felt most kindly towards was for M-Pasa, which grew out of Kenya and thusly was well suited to Kenyan needs. Maybe I’d like the blockchain more if it didn’t seem like another case of the Western world prescribing solutions to non-western countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions I have for this week’s panel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the strengths of blockchain is in decentralization, but how can we ensure standardization and adoption without an authority to guide it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a related note, how can we ensure decentralization when so many of the miners are in farms in the same location?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin is largely what people think of when they think of blockchain currencies, but it has numerous problems (reserves are held by a few people, the aforementioned server farms in China, limits and refunds.) If not Bitcoin, what cryptocurrency could you mean? Do you envision a future with one cryptocurrency or with many?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What advantages does blockchain offer local or national charities? In countries with stable currency?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite cryptocurrency is still Dogecoin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>I’ve never thought much for Bitcoin, and consequentially blockchain technologies. Anecdotally, I knew it as the currency of libertarians and drug dealers; I only knew people who used it because they needed something illegal or used our university’s power and servers to mine it. Consequentially, it was kind of interesting to read positive takes on their potential uses for charity work, though it was quite clear to me that the sources were biased towards the technology (three of the articles came from websites devoted to promoting the blockchain or a product of blockchain; the fourth was Forbes, but was not on a blockchain technology.)</summary></entry><entry><title>Joinery</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joinery" /><published>2017-02-19T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/19/joinery/">&lt;p&gt;For my midterm project for Subtraction, I wanted to construct the case for a desktop vending machine for the battery store that I run with Lindsey Daniels. I’ve seen pictures of this done before, but the creator doesn’t release his plans since he sells the parts on his website. Why not make my own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/venduino.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/venduino.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the joints I needed to study are tenons– I’ll be making use of a lot of right angles for the vending machine. It was a little tricky making the template in vector works, and I got frustrated more than a few times. I never really understood when and why the program would want to snap things, so I often had to manually adjust x and y coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/vectorworks.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/vectorworks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, cutting was a bit of a cinch. I was working off the scraps of my MDF last week, so I was a bit concerned about the spacing, but it worked out fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/cutting.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re very little, but they’re important for testing this joint out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/final.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/final.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version I tried was not quite flush. I had to adjust the spacing of my pocket on the right side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was far more flush, but still had too much of a pocket. Let’s try it again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this attempt worked out fairly well, and I had run out of my scrap of MDF so I had to stop. It’s pretty nice, though, but I’ll have to try out the joints again when I get my materials for my vending machine. I’ll be ordering ply instead of MDF– what if somebody spills things onto my vending machine– so the material change might make things a little different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_joinery/try3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_joinery/try3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><category term="cnc" /><category term="joinery" /><summary>For my midterm project for Subtraction, I wanted to construct the case for a desktop vending machine for the battery store that I run with Lindsey Daniels. I’ve seen pictures of this done before, but the creator doesn’t release his plans since he sells the parts on his website. Why not make my own?</summary></entry><entry><title>Connecting the Future</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/14/future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Connecting the Future" /><published>2017-02-14T06:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-14T06:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/14/future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/14/future/">&lt;p&gt;For a technologist, I’m awfully skeptical about technology, particularly when it’s from Silicon Valley. Every breathless press release I read about a startup just makes me wonder, “what’s the catch?” Consequently, I went into this week’s readings with doubt in my head, especially when the social good of a technology seems like an afterthought. This seemed to be the case for both the Uber and drone technology pieces: Uber started off, they admit, to “roll around San Francisco like ballers”, and drones are marketed for people already served by couriers. We’re envisioning the future of transportation when many places don’t have the present of transportation– and then retrofitting it into those places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fairness, these technologies do have benefits in these places, though I’m skeptical that these locations wouldn’t be better served with traditional modes of transportation. Delivering vaccines is one thing, but what is the potential cost and social benefit of developing a road system in Lesotho compared to building a drone system? What’s the potential benefit of developing durable public transport versus Uber?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the thing that surprised me most about the readings was how uncritical they could be. The Uber piece mentions the objections to Uber, but only on a surface level. It’s also unthoughtful about its impact on women– is it seriously praising a company known for sexist ads (“who said women don’t know how to drive?”) and for failing to respond to sexual assault issues? The piece mentions criticism of taxi drivers, but dances around the central issue: is it harmful to be supporting a global business versus globalization, and should we question the corporatization of transportation? Also, has the writer even taken an UberPOOL? Don’t they realize that everyone hates it? The best case scenario for an UberPOOL is to get one without other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our other readings included a piece on a crowd sourced aerial assessment platform, and how that compared to professional evaluations, and I found little to object to that. I did feel like it minimized how their volunteers were still professionals in related professions, such that I was not completely trusting of the results. I don’t know if a true novice would be as good at using the platform than people already experienced with GIS. The last one was on training and designing protocols for diagnoses in underserved communities, which really just made me wonder– are community health workers compensated for their work? Or are they strictly volunteer positions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my questions for the panel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UberPOOL rides are more difficult for drivers– they have to contend with multiple pickups and dropoffs, and nonsensical recommended routes. How does Uber properly compensate drivers for UberPOOL?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does Verifly insure the payloads and what drones carry?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is the value of more durable transportation networks measured?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you get feedback and let local populations advocate their needs?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(sub) What are the most interesting changes have you had to make to localize a product versus the global implementation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions are mostly Uber oriented.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>For a technologist, I’m awfully skeptical about technology, particularly when it’s from Silicon Valley. Every breathless press release I read about a startup just makes me wonder, “what’s the catch?” Consequently, I went into this week’s readings with doubt in my head, especially when the social good of a technology seems like an afterthought. This seemed to be the case for both the Uber and drone technology pieces: Uber started off, they admit, to “roll around San Francisco like ballers”, and drones are marketed for people already served by couriers. We’re envisioning the future of transportation when many places don’t have the present of transportation– and then retrofitting it into those places.</summary></entry><entry><title>Ceci n’est pas une pizza</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/13/cnc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ceci n'est pas une pizza" /><published>2017-02-13T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-13T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/13/cnc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/13/cnc/">&lt;p&gt;I had a lot less trouble with this week’s Subtraction exercise than last week’s. The primary trouble I had was with scheduling and other people– I waited three hours to see if someone would vacate the MasterCAM station on Friday, and found it constantly occupied. Consequently, my project isn’t quite where I wanted it to be, but I’m pretty content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I had to do was get materials and come up with a concept. I found some unlabeled MDF, and was brainstorming on Wednesday when a website told me that it was national pizza day on February 9th– so I decided to cut out a pizza. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In truth, I wanted to cut out vending machine housing, but I didn’t have enough material. Pizza it is!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a template in Vectorworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/pizza1.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/pizza1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then modified it so the cut lines were clearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/pizza2.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/pizza2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I wanted to bring to the MasterCAM on Friday, but the station was busy. Consequently, I couldn’t get it set up until during my CNC reservation on Sunday, at which point I discovered that the slice lines were too thin for the bit that I had. I had to quickly discard the slice lines and keep only the original sauce concept, which was fine! I just wish I discovered it on Friday, but the MasterCAM was busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/mastercam.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/mastercam.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up the CNC, which was simple enough. Honestly, I had more trouble using enough pressure with a hand drill to keep my material on then anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/cnc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/cnc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the CNC in action. I spent most of the time vacuuming, just to pass the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/action.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/action.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cutting finished without hiccups, though it ended up a little close to the edge of the material for my liking. I should double check my origin in relation to the cuts before I take it to the CAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/finished.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/finished.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still a pretty nice wooden pizza, though. Ceci est une belle maquette, même si ce n’est pas une pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: I later put the thing in a pizza box. It’s pretty cute, and worth a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/pizza1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/pizza1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_cnc/pizza2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_cnc/pizza2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="milling" /><category term="cnc" /><summary>I had a lot less trouble with this week’s Subtraction exercise than last week’s. The primary trouble I had was with scheduling and other people– I waited three hours to see if someone would vacate the MasterCAM station on Friday, and found it constantly occupied. Consequently, my project isn’t quite where I wanted it to be, but I’m pretty content.</summary></entry><entry><title>Branches</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/branches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Branches" /><published>2017-02-12T07:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-12T07:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/branches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/branches/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about fate for my story of Cassandra. We’re meant to change critical actions in the story to see how they effect the narrative, but the idea of Cassandra is so tied up with the idea of ‘fate’ that it can be hard to find an action to change. To me, these are the key components of the Cassandra myth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) A curse to always tell the truth, but not be believed in some capacity.
2) Repeated attempts to tell the truth despite the curse. Every attempt still results in not being believed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is what makes Cassandra a hero to me: knowing her curse, she still attempts to warn people. But still, fate and the Gods will have her never be believed. If we change this aspect, and let someone believe her, it hardly seems like the story of Cassandra anymore– unless, perhaps, it still ultimately results in nobody believing that person either. Perhaps no authority figure believes them? Fate must be inescapable for the story to still be “Cassandra”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I conceived of my retelling of Cassandra as an interactive narrative, a story that will take place in a fictional secure phone application that Cassandra has just installed for her job at the oil company. The player steps into the role of Cassandra, and should feel the despair of her. I considered making the story a VR experience, but thought that a phone application that takes place over an extended period of time would be the sort of ‘immersion’ that I would prefer for the story. The story’s impact is in the repeated failures to be believed, and in wearing you down. If you’re using VR, very few people would use the application for more than ten minutes, so the repetition and wearing down is minimized. I wanted the tension to take place over days, and for the player to feel anxious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential changes to the narrative:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making someone believe her&lt;/em&gt;: as mentioned before, this changes the narrative substantially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giving Cassandra a brother who also tells the truth&lt;/em&gt;: this is actually an aspect of the original story as told by Homer. Cassandra has a twin brother, Helenus, who she teaches the art of prophecy. Contrary to her, his prophecies are believed (he does not stop the Greeks from winning the war as he is captured before the Trojan horse is created.) Giving her a brother, or other comrade, who is believed, might emphasize her plight, but since my narrative involves a singular company secret, letting him be believed would still fulfill Cassandra’s goals of whistleblowing. It’s an interesting twist on the original myth, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Changing the context to something besides whistleblowing&lt;/em&gt;: I considered for a second changing the context to a woman trying to report her sexual assault, but decided that was too bleak a subject for even me. One of my goals is to have a game that all genders will play, and I think men will shy away from a game that is so alien to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;readings&quot;&gt;Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s reading was far more tolerable than last week’s for me, despite also giving fairy tales a Freudian treatment. The difference, to me, was substantial: instead of applying a Freudian reading to actual children who are in therapy, the reading is applied to cartoons and works of art. To imply a fictional cat is doing a phallic action is far more understandable than claiming a small girl has penis envy. Even unjustified claims about Walt Disney’s character seems fine to me, as he’s well documented as a megalomaniac and control freak by his employees, and his actions– after all, he did manipulate local Floridian governments to create Disneyworld. Plus, it is no exaggeration to claim he’s had far reaching effects on the idea of fairy tales in the public– you can simply look at how many treatments of fairy tales in our class are updates on the Disney version, and not any other version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can look at what the public considers a fairy tale for further proof of Disney’s influence: ask a little girl what their favourite fairy tale is, and they might respond with “Pocahontas” or “Mulan”. Neither were fairy tales before Disney rewrote their stories.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="fairy tales" /><category term="fables" /><category term="myths" /><category term="fairy tales for the 21st century" /><summary>I’ve been thinking a lot about fate for my story of Cassandra. We’re meant to change critical actions in the story to see how they effect the narrative, but the idea of Cassandra is so tied up with the idea of ‘fate’ that it can be hard to find an action to change. To me, these are the key components of the Cassandra myth:</summary></entry><entry><title>All Roads Lead Back to ITP</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/allroads/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All Roads Lead Back to ITP" /><published>2017-02-12T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-12T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/allroads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/12/allroads/">&lt;p&gt;For this week of Everything is Spatial, we used some geolocation data we generated over the last two weeks with the Moves application, and visualized the paths we took as well as the locations we visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_allroads/basic.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_allroads/basic.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the base map of my last two weeks– all roads lead back to ITP… I’m here a lot. I changed the paths to be a thinner line for travelling with public transit, and a thicker line for just walks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then meant to enhance this data with one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Details of the places we visited (it’s currently just coordinates)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A key or legend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frequency of visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go for the fourth option, and find details about the places I visited. Some of the locations I visited are already annotated, since I did so via the Moves app earlier, but I failed to do most of them. The rest I decided to use Google Maps’ geocoder to annotate, because I had done so before and was vaguely familiar with the process. I generated an API key, and wrote the following code to annotate the places with tooltips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;onEachFeature(feature, layer) {
            if (feature.properties &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
                feature.properties.place &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
                feature.properties.place.name) {
                layer.bindTooltip(feature.properties.place.name, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
            } else {
                var latlng = feature.properties.place.location;

                geocoder.geocode({'location': {lat: parseFloat(latlng.lat), lng: parseFloat(latlng.lon)}}, function(results, status) {
                if (status === 'OK') {
                  if (results[0]) {
                    layer.bindTooltip(results[0].formatted_address, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
                  }
                }
                });
            }
        }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this worked fairly well, as the following screenshot shows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spatial_allroads/annotations.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;spatial_allroads/annotations.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problm with this code, however, is that Google Maps rate limits free accounts, and it fires the requests too rapidly. The majority of places go unlabeled. To solve this, we can slow down the labelling, but this is also not ideal: for a web application, you want to load as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem with this code is that the API key is needed on the client side, leaving you exposed to potential abuse. Someone could use this code to ping Google with their own georequests, and waste your money or rates. To protect you from this, Google lets you restrict your key to usage by certain websites and IP addresses, which should help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practical solution for this would be to prepopulate the information, and do the Geomapping before on the server side. (Or else pay Google to no longer be rate limited.) This would solve both of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very lazy though, so I decided to just restrict my key, and deal with the rate limit by just removing the addresses that failed to populate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;        onEachFeature(feature, layer) {
            if (feature.properties &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
                feature.properties.place &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
                feature.properties.place.name) {
                layer.bindTooltip(feature.properties.place.name, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
            } else {
                var latlng = feature.properties.place.location;

                geocoder.geocode({'location': {lat: parseFloat(latlng.lat), lng: parseFloat(latlng.lon)}}, function(results, status) {
                if (status === 'OK') {
                  if (results[0]) {
                    layer.bindTooltip(results[0].formatted_address, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
                  } else {
                    placesLayer.removeLayer(layer);
                  }
                } else {
                    placesLayer.removeLayer(layer);
                }
                });
            }
        }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done! Here’s the map below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/mapbox.js/v3.0.1/mapbox.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/mapbox.js/v3.0.1/mapbox.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://api.tiles.mapbox.com/mapbox.js/plugins/leaflet-omnivore/v0.3.1/leaflet-omnivore.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/js?key=AIzaSyCnH8dPy1Q156b4G5667i-LxOrhnIGC1hA&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;map&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
// BaseMap
var layer = L.tileLayer('http://{s}.basemaps.cartocdn.com/dark_all/{z}/{x}/{y}.png');
var map = L.map('map').setView([40.7246342, -73.9427715], 13);
map.addLayer(layer);


var walkingLayer = L.geoJson(null, {
filter: function(feature) {
    // my custom filter function
    return feature.properties.activities.map(function(x){ return x.activity }) == &quot;walking&quot;;
},
style: function(feature) {
    // my custom filter function
    return {
        color: &quot;#9e9&quot;,
        weight: 5
    };

}
});
var transportLayer = L.geoJson(null, {
filter: function(feature) {
    // my custom filter function
    return feature.properties.activities.map(function(x){ return x.activity }).includes(&quot;transport&quot;);
},
style: function(feature) {
    // my custom filter function
    return {
        color: &quot;#4a4&quot;,
        weight: 1,
        opacity: 0.5
    };

}
});
var dataLayer = omnivore.geojson(&quot;/assets/spatial_allroads/activities.json&quot;, null, walkingLayer).addTo(map);
var dataLayer = omnivore.geojson(&quot;/assets/spatial_allroads/activities.json&quot;, null, transportLayer).addTo(map);
var geocoder = new google.maps.Geocoder;

var placesLayer =  L.geoJson(null, {
    // filter: function(feature) {
    //     return feature.properties.place.name;
    // },
    pointToLayer: function (feature, latlng) {
        return new L.CircleMarker(latlng, {
            radius:7,
            color: &quot;white&quot;,
            fillOpacity: 0.5
        })},
    onEachFeature(feature, layer) {
        if (feature.properties &amp;&amp;
            feature.properties.place &amp;&amp;
            feature.properties.place.name) {
            layer.bindTooltip(feature.properties.place.name, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
        } else {
            var latlng = feature.properties.place.location;

            geocoder.geocode({'location': {lat: parseFloat(latlng.lat), lng: parseFloat(latlng.lon)}}, function(results, status) {
            if (status === 'OK') {
              if (results[0]) {
                layer.bindTooltip(results[0].formatted_address, {permanent: true}).addTo(map);
              } else {
                placesLayer.removeLayer(layer);
              }
            } else {
                placesLayer.removeLayer(layer);
            }
            });
        }
    }
});

var pdataLayer = omnivore.geojson(&quot;/assets/spatial_allroads/places.json&quot;, null, placesLayer).addTo(map);

&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="everything is spatial" /><category term="spatial" /><summary>For this week of Everything is Spatial, we used some geolocation data we generated over the last two weeks with the Moves application, and visualized the paths we took as well as the locations we visited.</summary></entry><entry><title>Do No Evil</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do No Evil" /><published>2017-02-07T06:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T06:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/workshop/">&lt;p&gt;Last week for Doing Good is Good Business, we did a design workshop to practice solving problems– we paired up to solve each other’s problems with communicating with distant loved ones. I paired with Dorothy, who had trouble reaching a friend of hers in Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of trouble thinking of creative ideas in that short amount of time– these aren’t very radical ideas at all. Practice makes perfect though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/progress4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/progress4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I settled on a design concept of collaboratively drawing from far away, since I got the sense from Dorothy that she and her friend were both artists. It was also inspired by a few different ‘couple apps’ I’ve seen, which let you see where your partner has touched on screen. While doing that, why not make art?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorothy also came up with an amazing prototype to solve my problem of figuring out when is best to call my mom– which reminds me, I should go do that right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gb_workshop/final3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;gb_workshop/final3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>Last week for Doing Good is Good Business, we did a design workshop to practice solving problems– we paired up to solve each other’s problems with communicating with distant loved ones. I paired with Dorothy, who had trouble reaching a friend of hers in Dubai.</summary></entry><entry><title>Do No Evil</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do No Evil" /><published>2017-02-07T05:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T05:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/07/evil/">&lt;p&gt;In UNICEF’s guidelines for innovation, #8 is a particular favourite of mine: “do no harm.” It harkens back to Google’s old motto to “don’t be evil”, but Google has since changed their slogan since, and it feels like the rest of the tech world has as well. UNICEF’s version even goes a step farther than google: whereas evil is ambiguous and up for interpretation, harm can be measured. To do no harm is a difficult goal and requires a lot of forethought and consideration of ethics, which are ideas explored by this week’s speakers and within the required reading for &lt;em&gt;Doing Good is Good Business&lt;/em&gt;. How do we use data to do good and not do harm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fairness, Donald Trump supporters would not characterize Cambridge Analytica as doing any harm, but if “The Data That Turned the World Upside Down” is completely factual, their work is easily described as harmful. Although this, and many other articles I’ve read on the subject, act as though the use of Big 5 and personality psychology was Cambridge Analytica’s chief innovation, from my reading, it’s not too different from what Barack Obama’s team innovated in 2008 and 2012. The true difference is the use of targeted advertising and segmentation for voter suppression: discouraging potential Hillary Clinton supporters from voting. This is certainly harmful, and certainly not what Michal Kosinski intended with his data collection and analysis– let alone what Mark Zuckerburg and other technologists intended with the web applications they created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, personalized newsfeed and recommender systems were created with the best of intentions. You wouldn’t want to waste your time with things you weren’t interested in. But to be fed a diet of only things you’re interested in can be harmful to your soul, and harmful to your understanding of the world. I’m not always very sympathetic to conservatives– I don’t think there are always two sides to every story, and the so-called “other side” should not be part of the conversation sometimes (for instance, I do not believe creationism has a place in science classes.) But keeping Palestinian and Israeli networks completely separated seems to be doing tangible harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a prime example of the blindness of the tech industry, there is no discussion of ethics within “Social Media Fingerprints of Unemployment”. Is it truly ethical to use social media data to determine economic statistics? One might argue that it isn’t too different from data collected in traditional ways– such as censuses or unemployment surveys. But there is no obvious connection in social media to unemployment, and people who use social media do not explicitly consent to their posts being used in this way. If we do use big data for these purposes, would it affect the accuracy of the data once this information collecting is fully disclosed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some questions I might have for our panel discussion next class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can websites and applications do more to inform their users of the information being collected on them and how it’s being used?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How common is the practice of buying and selling data amongst companies? Or amongst companies and non-profits?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is done to compensate for underrepresentation amongst minority in Big Data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="doing good is good business" /><category term="unicef" /><category term="good business" /><summary>In UNICEF’s guidelines for innovation, #8 is a particular favourite of mine: “do no harm.” It harkens back to Google’s old motto to “don’t be evil”, but Google has since changed their slogan since, and it feels like the rest of the tech world has as well. UNICEF’s version even goes a step farther than google: whereas evil is ambiguous and up for interpretation, harm can be measured. To do no harm is a difficult goal and requires a lot of forethought and consideration of ethics, which are ideas explored by this week’s speakers and within the required reading for Doing Good is Good Business. How do we use data to do good and not do harm?</summary></entry><entry><title>Othermill</title><link href="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Othermill" /><published>2017-02-06T08:01:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-06T08:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ceiling.cat/2017/02/06/othermill/">&lt;p&gt;I had a great deal of trouble with this week’s assignment, to the point that the thing isn’t finished. If I can manage the energy, I might finish it later, but for now I think I’ve tried hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/mountains.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/mountains.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I wanted to mill. It’s an abstract representation of the north shore mountains– the mountains that tower over Vancouver. A little piece of home! I had trouble with picking something to mill, as I only had a 1/8” bit, and a lot of my original ideas needed finer milling. This was good enough, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took great care to load the bit and stick my block onto the machine the first time around. Later attempts, which I had to do, I took less care, and the block came off the base a few times. I think this is because I didn’t give it time to cure, but later, when I left the block on the board a little longer, I had no troubles with it coming off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rDGBYxkI3kE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I had trouble with this machine when I started to run the job. Whenever I tried, it seemed to stop and restart itself. I hypothesized it was a power issue, so I switched the power supply with that of another machine, but when I did this, the machine would constantly beep and did not spin the bit. I ended up giving up and trying a different machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to an Othermill Pro, it worked very well, but was a long job (nearly an hour!) and loud as hell. I had by this point already attempted three attempts on the other machine, and then with the Pro, it took me two tries before the glue set properly. Since I had spent so much time already listening to the machine mill extremely loudly, and since I was the only one milling, I rearranged the sound dampeners to suit my needs. I made a fort, in other words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 40 minutes into this job and after a few vacuums, even the Othermill Pro decided it could have no more and restarted in the middle of a cut. I suspect it overheated from the lengthy job. At this point, I had been at this for hours, and it was nearly midnight, so I decided to leave the job as it was and clean up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/03.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the final result, but I might take it back and finally cut the thing out. The engravings are rather fine– I just need to cut the damn thing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sub_othermill/04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;sub_othermill/04.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason the right triangle is cut off was because I kept using the same piece of wood and didn’t align it perfectly with each attempt– I could’ve restarted, but I had grown attached to the dumb thing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rita Cheng</name><email>rita@ritacheng.com</email></author><category term="subtraction" /><category term="othermill" /><category term="milling" /><summary>I had a great deal of trouble with this week’s assignment, to the point that the thing isn’t finished. If I can manage the energy, I might finish it later, but for now I think I’ve tried hard enough.</summary></entry></feed>
