<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ux, | Rita Cheng's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/categories/ux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-15T13:16:52-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rita Cheng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokedex Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/24/pokedex-design/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T11:20:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/24/pokedex-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started a new playthrough of Pokemon Leafgreen&mdash; the last Pokemon game I had played through was Ruby, so I thought I&rsquo;d ease back into playing these games with this one. It&rsquo;s both a continuation of the series and a game I&rsquo;m intimately familiar with&mdash; it is a remake of the first generation of Pokemon games.</p>

<p>One thing that struck me very quickly was how poorly designed the Pokedex was in terms of user experience. Unless you&rsquo;re part of Twitch playing Pokemon, there is hardly any reason to consult the Pokedex beyond looking at your catch and seen counts. The Pokedex has improved since the first generation&mdash; there is now at a glance type information, clear thumbnails of each Pokemon, and different categories, but it is still largely unhelpful for many potential use cases. I often find myself creating spreadsheets or looking for web applications to meet my needs.</p>

<p>Roughly, here is a persona for a potential Pokedex User:</p>

<blockquote><p>Red is a 10 year old boy from Pallet Town, who is on a quest to become a Pokemon Master. He would like to learn more about the Pokemon he has seen or caught, and could use some help on his journey to catch &lsquo;em all. He is quite adept at using technology, regularly using his computer to store and withdraw his Pokemon and items.</p></blockquote>

<p>The Pokedex is reasonably helpful for Red to discover facts about his Pokemon, but, particularly in Firered and Leafgreen, it falls short as a reference for catching Pokemon. Some features that would help include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Searching by name. This is a feature that was removed in FR/LG, for reasons unknown. Consequentially, the only way to find a Pokemon is to look through many pages, particularly if you do not know its local habitat.</li>
<li>Filtering by Caught / Uncaught status. If I&rsquo;d like to know more about the Pokemon I own, there would be a lot less friction if I didn&rsquo;t have to scroll through entries that are incomplete, and vice versa.</li>
<li>Viewing Pokemon by Location Found. Apparently a feature added in B2/W2 and then removed for no apparent reason, this would be a boon for completionists, allowing a trainer to view at a glance whether they&rsquo;ve caught all the Pokemon in an area.</li>
<li>Custom lists. In attempting to complete the Kanto Pokedex, I find myself making lists of Pokemon I intend to catch in the wild, Pokemon I need to remember to trade, and Pokemon I need to remember to train. It would be handy if this was a feature facilitated in the game rather than Google Documents I&rsquo;ve created.</li>
</ul>


<p>If I were a Pokedex designer, I would want to conduct user studies, (If Professor Oak wanted us to test the devices, why didn&rsquo;t he ask us for our thoughts on them?) write up task analyses, and create storyboards for an improved interface. On the other hand, if I were in the Pokemon universe, I&rsquo;d probably forget about all of that, and just try to catch them all myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
