<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Thoughts | Rita Cheng's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-15T13:16:52-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rita Cheng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Password Auditing]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/04/20/password-auditing/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T00:35:06-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/04/20/password-auditing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the recent disclosure of the Heartbleed exploit, account security is undergoing increased media scrutiny and many of my less technical friends have asked me questions about how to proceed. Although it is likely unnecessary to change every single account password, now is as good a time as any to do a security audit of yourself and your application accounts. Here is a small audit that is fairly easy to do (and indeed, I did so earlier today):</p>

<h3>Collect a List of your Online Accounts</h3>

<p>The first step is intuitive enough: to secure yourself, you need to know where your openings are. If you use a password manager such as <a href="https://lastpass.com/">LastPass</a>, <a href="http://www.roboform.com">Roboform</a>, or <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">1Password</a>, this should be extremely straightforward and you can move on to the next step. They can also be built into your browser (Chrome has a fairly commonly used one.)</p>

<p>If you do not, I recommend using one to all but the most paranoid of users, as they simplify keeping track of your accounts and passwords, and can be synced between your devices. Otherwise, make a list manually by going through your commonly used websites and look at popular websites (popular websites are at once more likely to be secure and more likely to be targeted for an attack.) Also, search your inbox for account registration or password reset emails. (Search &ldquo;account&rdquo;, &ldquo; username&rdquo;, &ldquo;password&rdquo;.) Once you have a list, you can move on.</p>

<h3>Try to Delete Unused Accounts</h3>

<p>I sign up for many websites on a whim and never use them again. Are there any sites like this for you as well? Or do you never really use that Instagram anyways? No opening is better than a secure one, so you should probably just close these accounts down.</p>

<p>Look through your list and find any accounts you could really do without, and update your accounts with dummy information and new passwords. Even if your account is successfully deleted, it&rsquo;s hard to ensure that a website will truly honour your privacy or your request. After this, it&rsquo;s time to delete the account, which can be extremely difficult to do.</p>

<p>First, you can check <a href="http://justdelete.me/">JustDelete.Me</a> if the website is listed, and follow their instructions for removing your account. Otherwise, start by looking at your account settings or their help sections&mdash; they may have information on deleting your account, or if you&rsquo;re lucky, a button to do so. Then, if you&rsquo;re out of luck, send an email to customer support asking them to delete your account (include any pertinent information, like your username.) If they tell you it is impossible, make sure you have removed your personal information and changed the password as previously instructed,  and hope that this will suffice.</p>

<h3>Change These Passwords</h3>

<p>For the remaining accounts, go through and change the passwords for them as necessary. Here is my order of priority of whether you should change your password or not:</p>

<ol>
<li>Exploit Affected Websites (such as by Heartbleed) Immediate change</li>
<li>Duplicate Passwords</li>
<li>Bad Passwords</li>
<li>Really Old Passwords (2+ Years)</li>
<li>Old Passwords (1+ Year)</li>
<li>Kinda Old Passwords (4+ Months)</li>
<li>Recent Passwords (&lt; 4 Months, lower priority)</li>
</ol>


<p>Anything at levels 4 or higher should really be changed now. Bad Passwords include most passwords that are dictionary words, and do not include very many numbers or symbols. (You can look up &ldquo;password entropy&rdquo; for thoughts on this and advice on creating new passwords.)</p>

<p>For the typical end user, I just recommend using a password manager to generate and keep track of new passwords. Otherwise, there have been very many articles on password generation, including <a href="http://xkcd.com/936/">this famous XKCD comic</a>. For my money, I believe that any wildly popular advice on passwords is likely to be insecure, so you should really make up your own rules involving numbers and symbols. For instance, maybe you made up a secret language in Grade 6 that you remember to this day&mdash; make use of that. Use camel case pig Latin. Intersperse symbols and numbers throughout all of these.</p>

<h3>Conclusions</h3>

<p>After you are done changing your passwords, make sure that you don&rsquo;t write them down or leave access to them where a person can find them, and if you need to share access to an account with someone, change the password first. Remember, the easiest way to gain access to somebody&rsquo;s account is through social engineering.</p>

<p>Finally, it is likely a good idea to also ensure that all your apps and programs are up-to-date, and to do an audit of what apps have access to your Facebook and Twitter accounts. A virus scan probably also won&rsquo;t hurt either. However, simply changing your passwords as listed above is a good first step for people who are confused and pressed on time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokedex Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/24/pokedex-design/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T11:20:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/24/pokedex-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started a new playthrough of Pokemon Leafgreen&mdash; the last Pokemon game I had played through was Ruby, so I thought I&rsquo;d ease back into playing these games with this one. It&rsquo;s both a continuation of the series and a game I&rsquo;m intimately familiar with&mdash; it is a remake of the first generation of Pokemon games.</p>

<p>One thing that struck me very quickly was how poorly designed the Pokedex was in terms of user experience. Unless you&rsquo;re part of Twitch playing Pokemon, there is hardly any reason to consult the Pokedex beyond looking at your catch and seen counts. The Pokedex has improved since the first generation&mdash; there is now at a glance type information, clear thumbnails of each Pokemon, and different categories, but it is still largely unhelpful for many potential use cases. I often find myself creating spreadsheets or looking for web applications to meet my needs.</p>

<p>Roughly, here is a persona for a potential Pokedex User:</p>

<blockquote><p>Red is a 10 year old boy from Pallet Town, who is on a quest to become a Pokemon Master. He would like to learn more about the Pokemon he has seen or caught, and could use some help on his journey to catch &lsquo;em all. He is quite adept at using technology, regularly using his computer to store and withdraw his Pokemon and items.</p></blockquote>

<p>The Pokedex is reasonably helpful for Red to discover facts about his Pokemon, but, particularly in Firered and Leafgreen, it falls short as a reference for catching Pokemon. Some features that would help include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Searching by name. This is a feature that was removed in FR/LG, for reasons unknown. Consequentially, the only way to find a Pokemon is to look through many pages, particularly if you do not know its local habitat.</li>
<li>Filtering by Caught / Uncaught status. If I&rsquo;d like to know more about the Pokemon I own, there would be a lot less friction if I didn&rsquo;t have to scroll through entries that are incomplete, and vice versa.</li>
<li>Viewing Pokemon by Location Found. Apparently a feature added in B2/W2 and then removed for no apparent reason, this would be a boon for completionists, allowing a trainer to view at a glance whether they&rsquo;ve caught all the Pokemon in an area.</li>
<li>Custom lists. In attempting to complete the Kanto Pokedex, I find myself making lists of Pokemon I intend to catch in the wild, Pokemon I need to remember to trade, and Pokemon I need to remember to train. It would be handy if this was a feature facilitated in the game rather than Google Documents I&rsquo;ve created.</li>
</ul>


<p>If I were a Pokedex designer, I would want to conduct user studies, (If Professor Oak wanted us to test the devices, why didn&rsquo;t he ask us for our thoughts on them?) write up task analyses, and create storyboards for an improved interface. On the other hand, if I were in the Pokemon universe, I&rsquo;d probably forget about all of that, and just try to catch them all myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foursquare and Kinds of Fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/01/foursquare-and-kinds-of-fun/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-01T18:03:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/02/01/foursquare-and-kinds-of-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a <a href="http://angrydm.com/2014/01/gaming-for-fun-part-1-eight-kinds-of-fun/">blog post</a> recently about LeBlanc' eight types of fun (as applied to being a good dungeon master for D&amp;D) and, since I don&rsquo;t DM or play D&amp;D, it got me thinking about web applications and gamification. Although Kevin Warbauch&rsquo;s Coursera class on gamification was very informative, I found that this blog post was more illuminating than the discussion on fun included in the course. It got me thinking about how Foursquare&rsquo;s gamification were so much more effective than other applications: it covers more types of fun than the usual gamified effort, and it&rsquo;s consequentially more fun.</p>

<p>This is partially a consequence of Foursquare&rsquo;s core concept as well as its game elements. For instance, it largely achieves the Sensory aspect of fun because of checking into the locations, rather than any artificial game elements. What could be more sensory than going to a restaurant and trying some new food? Similarly, it achieves Discovery as part of its original mission: Foursquare helps you find new places to go. Submission isn&rsquo;t as deliberately achieved, but its a side effect of Foursquare being so easy and uninvolved: all you have to do is check in, and then enjoy yourself at the locale.</p>

<p>Fellowship is likely the most important type of fun for Foursquare: the social network is designed to facilitate meeting up with your friends. Although its certainly possible to use Foursquare solitaire, much of the fun is seeing where your friends check in and getting implicit recommendations that way.</p>

<p>More explicit game elements of Foursquare are directed towards gamers who like Challenge. Collecting badges, climbing leaderboards, and creating streaks are all components borrowed from games and can be extremely habit forming. Foursquare, to an extent, also includes the Expression type of fun: the places where you check in, and particularly, where you become King, make a particular statement about yourself. If you&rsquo;re king of Sun Sui Wah and you&rsquo;ve collected all the Chinese food badges, it denotes to the world: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m an expert on Chinese food.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a much stronger assertion than just claiming it.</p>

<p>The two remaining types of fun are a bit weaker on Foursquare. Becoming King may satisfy those who like Fantasy, but it&rsquo;s a weak argument. The sense of progression in steaks and points may satisfy Narrative seekers a little, but not to any great extent. Still, six out of eight is extremely good for any game, let alone a gamified platform. Developers would do well by following Foursquare&rsquo;s example on this in making their applications fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
