<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | Rita Cheng's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-05T13:10:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rita Cheng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bullet Points From Maximize Your Potential]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/01/21/bullet-points-from-maximize-your-potential/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T13:55:13-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ritacheng.com/blog/2014/01/21/bullet-points-from-maximize-your-potential</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have an embarrassing secret: I love self-help books, whether they&rsquo;re the usual cheesy &ldquo;believe in yourself&rdquo; drivel, or coated with a veneer of business or professional material. I don&rsquo;t think this obsession is all that different from &ldquo;life hacks&rdquo; or the motivational posts that litter Hacker News from time to time, except for two points: they might contain fresh insights that the life hackers haven&rsquo;t covered yet and they usually pad out these insights with walls of text. They need to fill in an entire book somehow.</p>

<p>I recently read 99U&rsquo;s &ldquo;Maximize Your Potential: Grow Your Expertise, Take Bold Risks &amp; Build an Incredible Career&rdquo;, and took down a few notes. To save you the trouble of reading the book, here are some of the big takeaways:</p>

<ul>
<li>Post long term goals by your workstation to keep them in mind.</li>
<li>Let go of email/social media to reduce your mental list of &ldquo;things to do&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Compulsive decisions != Conscious decisions</li>
<li>UNPLUG.</li>
<li>Breathe deeply while you work.</li>
<li>Drink lots of water.</li>
<li>Instinct > Technology</li>
<li>Set aside specific time each week/day to work on spare projects to nurture your imagination.</li>
<li>Always carry a spare notebook for questions / ideas.</li>
<li>Let your mind wander when stuck.</li>
<li>Do creative work at beginning of day, and save reactive work for afterwards.</li>
<li>Have a routine.</li>
<li>Establish associative triggers for work. (e.g. different hats for different activities)</li>
<li>Consistent intervals for work (e.g. Pomodoro. 90 min bursts then take a break.)</li>
<li>Don’t wait to be in &ldquo;the mood&rdquo; for work. Just do it!</li>
<li>Spend time by yourself in a day.</li>
<li>Block off periods of times with no distractions (These are meetings with yourself.) Start off w/ 1 h meetings, and add 15 mins every two weeks.</li>
<li>Remove even the option of being distracted.</li>
<li>Finish tasks so you stop thinking about them!</li>
<li>Save iterations and POST MILESTONES.</li>
<li>Alternate creative and mindful work.</li>
</ul>


<p>You might already do some of these things, and some of these suggestions may be overwhelming. Just take a step at a time! I&rsquo;m currently doing well with my &lsquo;drinking water&rsquo; New Years' resolution!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
